Linda, there's that guy
from the stereo store.
- Don't you think
he looks like Richard Gere?
- See his cute little butt?
- You guys, let's talk about
that fox that just walked in.
- We already were.
I'm gonna go over there
and change the shakers.
- Cool out. That's Stacy's section.
- He's too old.
She's not even
in high school yet.
Smoking's upstairs to your left.
Smoking's upstairs.
Rat, is Dolly Parton giving you
a percentage of the profit?
What can I do for you, gentlemen?
You the guy with
the Van Halen tickets?
That could be.
How much for something
in the first ten rows?
- Twenty bucks apiece.
- Those tickets were only $12.50.
So don't buy 'em.
All the other scalpers are sold out.
Scalper?
Did you call me a scalper?
Listen, gentlemen, I perform a service
here, and the service costs money.
Do you want the tickets or don't you?
Okay, we'll take 'em.
All right.
What'd I say, $25?
Twenty!
All right.
Thank you.
Just made 16 bucks, Rat.
What's the matter? You look depressed.
I hate working the theater. All the
action's on the other side of the mall.
- How's it going?
- You want to take his table?
Go for it.
He's cute.
Just take his order,
look him in the eye.
If he says anything remotely funny,
laugh like you never heard anything
so funny.
And smile!
Go for it.
So, you working hard or hardly working?
You look like you
could still be in high school.
I know.
Everybody says that.
- How old are you?
- Nineteen.
- Twenty-six.
Do you think we could
still be friends?
So what can I get you?
How 'bout a meatball sandwich,
a medium Coke,
and your phone number?
- Hi.
- Hello.
Get outta here, Bradley.
- Dave.
- How you doin', Brad?
Cookin'!
Daddy's home, boys.
I shall serve no fries
before their time.
This one's on you, dude.
Who's got the beaucoup dolares today?
Uno dinero.
- What have you got, Mr. Buck Man?
- I got a cigarette.
I got uno "nickelette."
Hey! You guys had shirts on
when you came in here.
Somethin' happened to 'em, man.
Come on, Spicoli,
just put the shirts back on.
You see that sign?
"No shirts. No shoes. No dice."
Right.
Learn it.
Know it. Live it.
- Whoa.
- He's the full hot orator.
Linda, did I show you this?
He gave me his card.
"Ron Johnson, Audio Consultant."
Maybe we should get a frame for this,
and put it up on the wall.
Linda, you're the one who told me
I was gonna get a boyfriend at the mall.
- Do you think he'll call this week?
- Why don't you call him?
- I can't.
- You can. Guys love that sort of thing.
- Really?
- Yes!
Stacy, what are you waiting for?
You're 15 years old.
I did it when I was 13.
It's no huge thing. It's just sex.
- He was hot, wasn't he?
- If I didn't have a fiance
in Chicago, I'd go for it.
Hey, how you doin'?
Welcome to Ridgemont.
Will it look okay?
Well, she was an American girl
Raised on promises
- Do you know where U.S. History is?
- Down the hall and turn left.
Somewhere else
She was an American girl
Hi, Bradley.
Grown up.
Lookin' good.
Another year joined at the lips.
- Hi, Brad!
- Denise. I'd make you see God.
Brad!
- Big Cruising Vessel!
- Bradley!
Thank you.
Six more payments, gentlemen,
and this beautiful...
blue, four-door, luxury sedan
is all mine!
I'll give you
four tickets in the fifth row...
for the low price of $140.
See that car? Some alumni
gave Jefferson that car...
for playing football
when he was a sophomore.
- Helped him pick it out.
- Slick car.
We go way back, you know.
Hey, Charles, how you doin', buddy?
Car looks great. I mean really terrific.
You're really keeping it up
wonderfully.
Don't fuck with it!
Shit!
That's my man.
Brad?
- Arnold! What's happening?
- Can I talk to you a minute?
Sure, man.
I really hate Bronco Burger.
Ever since they started with the chicken
nuggets, everything went downhill.
You have to fry all their greasy food,
and you have to polish things.
And the manager's an asshole.
I was just wondering...
Arnold, do you want to work
at All-American Burger?
Yeah, well, um...
I can probably get you in.
Just let me talk to Dennis Taylor.
- All right!
- Okay.
Wait.
Did you hear the bell ring?
- What bell?
- We're here.
Aloha.
My name is Mr. Hand.
I have but one question for you.
Can you attend my class?
It is for your own good. And if you
can't make it, I can make you.
We have a 20-question quiz every Friday.
Your grade is the average
of all your quizzes,
plus the midterm and final
which counts for one-third.
Got it?
Also...
There will be no eating. E-A-T-l-N-G.
No eating in this class!
You get used to doing
your own business on your own time.
That's one demand I make.
Just like you wouldn't want me
to come to your house...
- and discuss U.S. History
on your time, understand?
- Yes, sir.
This guy's been stoned
since the third grade.
- Yes?
- Yeah, I'm registered in this class.
- What class?
- This is U.S. History.
- I see the globe right there.
- Really?
Hey.
May I come in?
Oh, please!
I get so lonely when I hear
that third attendance bell ring...
and all my kids are not here.
Sorry, I'm late. It's just like
this new schedule's totally confusing.
I know that dude!
Mr. Spicoli.
That's the name they gave me.
- You're ripping my card!
- Yes.
Hey, bud, what's your problem?
No problem at all.
I think you know
where the front office is.
You dick!
I have taken the time
to print up a complete schedule...
of class quizzes
and the chapters they cover.
Please pass them
to the desk behind you.
Back, back, back.
Did you hear about this surfer guy
who pulled a knife on Mr. Hand
this morning?
Oh, no!
He just called him a dick.
A dick? Oh, God.
People exaggerate so much here.
Linda, that girl
looks just like Pat Benatar.
I know. Wait.
There are three girls at Ridgemont...
who have cultivated
the Pat Benatar look.
Chanel Semlar,
Mary Ann Zlotnick
in the red tights.
Do you think guys find that
more attractive?
Stacy, please, give me a break!
You are so much prettier!
Yeah, I know, but do you think
they'd be better in bed?
What do you mean?
You either do it or you don't.
No. There are like... variables
that I might not be good at.
- Like what variables?
- Like, you know, giving blow jobs.
What's the big deal?
- I never did it.
- You've never given a blow job?
Never? Stace, there's nothing to it.
It's so easy.
Check it out.
Relax your throat muscles.
Don't bite.
And slide it in.
Try it again.
Good. Push it slowly in and out.
You got it.
Okay.
- Can I ask you something
and you promise not to laugh?
- Sure.
Okay. When a guy has an orgasm,
how much comes out?
A quart or so.
No, I'm just kidding.
Just practice.
I'm not going to a morgue.
I'll get my mom to write a note.
Nobody's getting me into a room
with a bunch of dead guys.
You have to go.
I hear it's part of the final.
I hear it's really disgusting.
Do you know what they do?
- Have you heard?
- What?
The bodies are dissected
and Mr. Vargas...
pulls out parts of the dead body
and holds them up.
You mean, he reaches in
and pulls this stuff out?
- Like stomach and tumors or something?
- Yeah, stomach, tumors, entrails.
Good day, everyone.
My name is Mr. Vargas.
Look.
I'm a little slow today.
I just switched to Sanka,
so have a heart.
All right, now.
The World of Life. That is the name
of the textbook we will be using.
I'm in love.
See the mustache comin' in, Rat?
You can almost cross it out.
- I'm in love.
- You are a wuss. Part wimp, part pussy.
What do you mean wuss?
This girl is my... exact type.
- Where'd you see her?
- In my biology class.
- Did you get her number?
- No.
- Did you get her name?
- No! No! It's too soon.
It's never too soon, Rat.
A girl decides how far she's gonna
let you go in the first five minutes.
What am I supposed to do? Go up to
this strange girl in my biology class...
and say, "Hello. I'd like you to
take your clothes off and jump on me"?
I would.
I can see it all now. This is
gonna be just like last summer.
You fell in love
with that girl at the Fotomat.
You bought $40 worth of fuckin' film,
and you never even talked to her.
You don't even own a camera!
You tell me, Mike.
What should I do?
This is what you do.
Start from the minute
you walk into biology.
I mean, don't just walk in.
Move across the room.
And you don't talk to her.
You use your face.
You use your body.
Use everything.
That's what I do.
I mean, I just send out
this vibe...
and I have personally found
that women do respond.
I mean, something happens.
Naturally something happens.
You put the vibe out to 30 million
chicks, something is gonna happen.
That's the idea, Rat.
That's the attitude.
- The attitude?
- Yeah.
The attitude dictates
that you don't care whether
she comes, stays, lays or prays.
Whatever happens,
your toes are still tappin'.
Now, when you got that...
then you have the attitude.
- Good night, Stacy.
- Good night, Mom.
- You look beautiful.
- Thanks. So do you.
Where do you feel like going?
I don't know.
- How 'bout The Point?
- Okay.
All right!
The Point it is.
That's a really nice jacket.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
- It's warm.
- Yeah, it is. It's really warm.
I wonder how long it will last.
So...
am I gonna get to first base?
- Are you really 19?
- Yeah, yeah, I am. I'm really 19.
So tell me, do you like Ron?
I like Ron, but it hurt so bad.
Don't worry. Keep doing it.
It gets a lot better. I swear.
It better.
- Mom says to clean the pool.
- Why can't you do it?
Your friends use the pool.
Your friends messed it up.
- Your friends use the pool too.
- I take out the garbage!
Brad!
- Brad, have Mom and Dad seen these?
- They're not home yet.
- Brad?
- What?
What would you say if
I asked you to put these...
in the trunk of the Cruising Vessel
and get rid of them?
- I'd say, "Who the hell is Ron Johnson?"
- Please.
Thank you very much.
- Lisa's great!
- Yeah.
I don't understand why you want
to break up with a girl like that.
Me and Lisa have been going together
for two years. I love her and all.
I mean, she's great in bed.
It's just that...
I'm a single, successful guy.
And this is my last year in school.
This could be the best year of my life!
I just feel like I need
my freedom now, you know?
Okay, here's your preparation stuff.
You got your sliced tomatoes,
shredded lettuce, secret sauce.
- What's the secret sauce?
- Thousand Island dressing.
What's the secret sauce
at Bronco Burger?
- Ketchup and mayonnaise.
- Gotcha.
Order for you, Bradley.
- Were those flowers really for me?
- Of course!
- How much did they cost?
- Don't worry about it.
Want to go to The Point tonight?
What's there to do at The Point?
What do you mean? We've been
going out together for two years.
I don't want to have to use sex
as a tool, Brad.
Tool? Tool for what?
We've been going together for two years!
- I don't want to talk about it here.
- I wanna talk about it!
- Brad?
- Lisa!
Brad!
You gotta flip 'em, or they'll burn.
Great.
"C."
"D."
"F."
"F." "F."
Three weeks we've been talking
about the Platt Amendment.
What are you people, on dope?
A piece of legislation was introduced
into Congress by Senator John Platt.
It was passed in 1906.
This amendment to our Constitution...
has a profound impact
upon all of our...
Where is Jeff Spicoli? I saw him earlier
today near the first floor bathrooms.
Is he still on campus?
Anyone? Yes, Desmond?
I saw him by the food machines.
- How long ago?
- Right before class.
Okay.
Bring him in.
What is this fascination with truancy?
What is it that gets inside your heads?
There are some teachers in this school
who look the other way at truants.
It's a little game
that you both play.
They pretend they don't see you.
You pretend you don't ditch.
Now, who pays the price later?
You!
Wait a minute.
There's no birthday party for me here!
Hola, Mr. Hand.
What's the reason for your truancy?
Just couldn't make it on time.
You mean,
you couldn't or you wouldn't?
It was like a full crowd scene
at the food lines.
Food will be eaten on your time.
Why are you continuously late
for this class, Mr. Spicoli?
Why do you shamelessly waste
my time like this?
- I don't know.
-
I like that.
"I don't know."
That's nice!
"Mr. Hand,
will I pass this class?"
"Gee, Mr. Spicoli,
I don't know!"
That's nice. I really like that.
You know what I'm gonna do?
I'm going to leave your words on this
board for all my classes to enjoy.
Giving you full credit,
of course, Mr. Spicoli!
All right.
How fucking long
do I have to wait?
Christmas sucks.
I hate it.
You gotta get used to working holidays.
People are always screaming.
I have to quit this job.
I'm gonna get so fat...
- no one's gonna want to take me out.
- Ron hasn't called, huh?
- Not since November.
- What does it matter?
He's a stereo salesman.
What'd you wanna do, marry him?
Have kids with him?
Have this guy come home
50 years old and bald?
And have that little Pacific Stereo
sign on? Come on, Stace.
Hey, it's his loss.
Got any Blue Oyster Cult?
No, I don't have any
Blue Oyster Cult.
I ate 34 pairs last time.
Where were you?
I was that close to working
at 7-Eleven, you know.
What?
- All right! Play me?
- Totally.
You got quarters?
When are those Earth, Wind and Fire
tickets comin' in?
Earth, Wind and Fire?
Geez, I haven't heard anything.
The minute I do,
I'll let you know.
I'm plannin' on taking
my little brother over here.
Is that your little brother?
He's a good-lookin' kid.
Great.
Charles Jefferson...
for Earth, Wind and Fire
and little brother.
I'll let you know when
they come around, okay?
Wow! Does he really live here?
I thought he just flew in for games.
Shit! He knows where to come
when he wants some tickets.
Go on. Get outta here.
You're messing up my business.
Come on, Rat.
Let's go get you a woman.
Wow.
You ready for
your moment of truth?
Damone, I noticed I was starting
to get a pimple this morning...
Rat, the shyness routine
is really starting to aggravate me.
I mean, who is she, anyway?
She's a waitress in a pizza parlor.
Look at her. Look at you.
A member of the Honor Roll.
Assistant to the assistant manager
of the movie theater.
Rat, if this girl
can't smell your qualifications,
then who needs her, right?
- Right.
- All right. How do you feel?
- I feel good.
- Do ya? All right.
Now stop fucking around
and go get her.
Hey, Rat, you gotta ace that jacket.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. All right, that's cool.
You look good. All right?
Go get her.
$1.10, and you get five cents back.
Thanks.
- Hi! Don't I know you
from biology class?
- Yeah!
- What can I do for you?
- I had a couple of questions.
I was curious.
What do you do with the
jackets people leave here?
- We keep 'em.
- You keep 'em?
In case they come back.
You can look through it if you want.
No, that's cool. It would take
too long to look through all that.
I'll pick up a new one.
What was your other question?
Oh, my other question is...
can I have your phone number
so I can ask you out sometime?
- Do you have a pen?
This one's out of ink.
- Yeah.
Stacy. Nice to meet you, Stacy.
My name is Mark Ratner.
I've gotta go.
Lisa, I have something to tell you.
Look, I'm a senior now.
I'm a single, successful guy.
And I've got to be fair to myself.
Lisa... I think I need my freedom.
Oh, don't do that.
- Please, please don't do that.
- Brad!
- Can you cover me on register two?
- Okay.
- May I help you?
- Ah, yes.
This is not the best breakfast
I ever ate and...
- I'd like my money back.
- Okay. I believe
you have to fill out a form.
No. I'd like my money back now.
I'm sorry. It doesn't work that way.
I have to fill out a form.
Well, you ate most of it
already so...
See that sign?
It says "100% guaranteed."
You know what the meaning
of guarantee is?
Did they teach you that here?
Sir, if you'd just wait a minute.
Look. Just put your little hand
in the cash register...
and give me my $2.75 back,
please, Brad.
Sir, if you'd just give me a minute.
I'll find the forms.
I'll take care of everything.
I don't have a minute.
You've made me late enough.
I am so tired of dealing
with incompetence.
It says 100% guaranteed,
you moron!
Mister, if you don't shut up,
I'm gonna kick 100% of your ass.
Ah, is there a problem here?
Can I help you, sir?
You bet you have a problem.
Your employee used profanity
and threatened me with violence.
I'm surprised. I eat here all the time
and usually have good service.
All I wanted was my money back on this
breakfast. It was a little under-cooked.
And he threatens me with violence.
I'm gonna call your super...
I can take care of it.
Mr. Hamilton, did you threaten this
customer or use profanity in any way?
Uh... he insulted me first.
He called me a moron, Dennis.
Answer me! Did you threaten
this customer or use profanity?
- Yes.
- You're fired.
I'm very sorry, sir.
I'll refund your money right now.
I hope you won't hold this against us.
You know how these young kids are
these days.
Here we are.
Perhaps another breakfast?
I hope you had
a hell of a piss, Arnold!
The world's finest
surfers showed up today to do battle...
with what's turned out to be the biggest
waves to hit this coast since 1946.
Hello. I'm Stu Nahan,
and I'd like you to meet this young man.
His name, Jeff Spicoli.
Jeff, congratulations.
Things looked rough out there today.
I'll tell you, Stu,
I did battle with some humongous waves.
Just like I told the guy on ABC,
"Danger is my business."
A lot of people
expected Mark "Cutback" Davis,
or Bob "Jungle Vet" Gerard...
- would take the honors this year.
- Those guys are fags!
Let me ask you. When you get out there,
do you ever fear for your life?
Stu, surfing's not a sport.
It's a way of life. It's no hobby.
It's a way of looking at that wave
and saying, "Hey, bud, let's party!"
Where'd you get this jacket?
From the network. Let me ask you,
what's next for Jeff Spicoli?
Headed over to the Australian
and then the Hawaiian Internationals.
Then me and Mick are gonna wing on over
to London and jam with the Stones.
You guys are invited too.
Jeff! Jeff!
Jeff, Dad says you have to get up.
- Leave me alone.
- Dad says you're gonna be late again,
you butthole!
- Leave me alone!
- Dad says you're gonna be late again,
you booger!
Dad, Jeff threw his snorkel at me!
We just want to say that
we're not Spirit Bunnies anymore.
We always hated that name.
It bugged the heck out of Dina and me.
- It's just such a put-down!
- Really!
We know you've got a lot of spirit,
everybody, right?
And we're gonna destroy Lincoln
next week! All right!
You know, it takes a lot
of courage to get up here...
and do something that
you know people will make fun of.
- Yeah.
- Man...
I'm never gonna talk
to those guys again.
I'm the one who got Arnold and Dave
their jobs there in the first place.
If you'd apologize to Dennis,
I'm sure he'd take you back.
Fuck Dennis Taylor!
I'm not gonna apologize to that wimp.
I'm just glad
we're still together...
because a lot's happened,
and I really need you this year.
Look, Brad, I've been trying
to think of a way to tell you this.
We're almost out of school.
It's our last year.
And I think we owe it
to ourselves to be free,
to go out with other people.
I still want to be friends.
What do I say to her
once we get in the car?
No problem, Rat. What you need
is my special five-point plan.
Come on, Damone, I need real help.
What'd you mean?
Men have died...
trying to obtain this
valuable information.
- But I'll give it to you for free.
- What's your five-point plan?
All right.
Now, pay attention.
First of all, you never let on
how much you like a girl.
Oh, Debbie... hi.
Two.
You always call the shots.
Kiss me, you won't regret it.
Three. Act like wherever you are,
that's the place to be.
Isn't this great?
Four.
When ordering food, find out what she
wants, then order for the both of you.
It's a classy move.
The lady will have
the linguine in a white clam sauce,
and a coke with no ice.
And five.
Now, this is most important, Rat.
When it comes down to makin' out,
whenever possible,
put on side one
of Led Zeppelin IV.
- This is a nice car.
- Yeah. It's my sister's.
Yeah?
Do you have Mrs. George
for English?
- Yeah. She's pretty good.
- Yeah, she is pretty good.
- Have you decided?
- Um, yeah.
I'll have the knockwurst.
Excellent.
You work at Cinema Four, right?
That must be great.
You get to see all those free movies.
You get free popcorn.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Would you mind if I excuse
myself for a moment?
Oh, no, go ahead.
Are you ready to order here?
She will have the knockwurst.
And you?
- I'll have the same.
- Anything to drink?
- Coke.
- Two Cokes.
Okay.
Thank you.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
- Hello?
- Mike, it's Mark.
- What happened to your date?
- It's happening right now.
Everything's fine except...
I left my wallet at home.
Why don't you go home and get it?
No, I can't! I'm here.
The food's coming and everything.
Look, would you do me a favor?
Just borrow your mom's car, drive to my
house, get my wallet and bring it here.
Hello? Mike?
Mike?
Geez, I'm really kinda busy, Rat.
Just do me this one favor.
I swear I won't ask you for anything
again in this lifetime or any other.
- But just please do this for me.
- You owe me for this one.
Okay, thanks.
Thanks a lot. Thanks.
-  Beaver, are you all right?
- What happened?
Are you sure there's nothing else
I can bring you?
Do you want another Coke?
Um... okay.
Two more Cokes.
- Hey, Mark, is that you?
- Yeah, hi.
- You come here?
- Yeah. I come for the strudel.
It's great.
Hey, listen, I found your wallet
the other day. You want it back?
Oh, wow! Yeah.
I was looking for this.
Oh, Mike,
you don't know Stacy Hamilton.
- Stacy, this is Mike Damone.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
See you later.
Right. Gotta be goin'.
You wanna go?
Um... yeah.
- I had a really nice time tonight.
- Me too.
I'm real sorry someone broke in
and stole your tape deck.
I never thought it would've happened
at such a fancy place.
I know.
You want to come in for a sec?
- Okay, sure.
- Good.
- Where's your brother?
- He's out tonight with some friends.
- Can I get you something to drink?
- No, that's... that's okay.
Oh. Well,
would you mind if I change?
No.
Okay. Could you get this for me?
It always sticks.
Thanks.
Where are your parents?
My parents are out of town
for the weekend.
Brad and I are watching the house.
- This is a really nice picture of you.
- Thanks.
You can come in my room
if you want.
So, what do you want to do?
I don't know.
Um, you want to look
at a photo album?
I keep a lot of pictures
from when I grew up and stuff.
- It's kinda stupid, huh?
- Sure! Yeah.
Yeah? Great.
Photographs.
This is the one that Brad took.
It's like double-image type thing,
you know. It's like a mirror.
This is me being stupid.
And this is my dog Gypsy,
and my cat Tullio.
- They're dead now.
- Remember him? Mr. Degan?
You had Degan?
- He always wore the same suit!
- The same suit!
- He must've had 500 of those suits.
- He was terrible!
No, I think it was one.
- You know, I just thought of something.
- What?
My sister is crazy
when it comes to her car.
- It's gotta be back by 11:00.
- Want to call her?
No. Look, l... She gets crazy.
Her car is her baby.
- I better be going.
- Really?
I'll call you.
Well, I'll see you in class. Okay?
Bye.
- Mark Ratner doesn't like me.
- Mark Ratner doesn't like you?
You're crazy!
No, he shows absolutely
no interest in me.
Mark Ratner is definitely somebody
you'd have to make the first move with.
Linda, I did. I made the first move,
I made the second move.
I made a complete jerk out of myself,
is what I did.
What do you care about
Mark Ratner for?
He's a 16-year-old usher
in the movie theater.
You have dated older guys. You work
at the best food stand in the mall.
And you are a close
personal friend of mine.
Yeah. But I was really
beginning to like him.
Yeah? If that's true,
you better find somebody else fast.
- Seen the new Playboy?
- Good?
- Bo Derek's tits!
- All right!
I like sex.
People on ludes
should not drive.
Hey, this is my brother's car!
- You said he was outta town.
- And he is.
All right.
Then don't hassle it.
Are you crazy, Spicoli?
That light was red!
- It was yellow a minute ago.
- You're gonna scratch my brother's car.
No, I'm not.
Look, I'm driving.
You navigate.
Where is this party?
Make a right, right here.
Here! Here! Here!
My brother's gonna kill us!
He's gonna kill us!
He's gonna kill you. He's gonna kill me.
Hey, man, just be glad
I had fast reflexes.
- My brother's gonna shit!
- Make up your mind, dude.
Is he gonna shit,
or is he gonna kill us?
First he's gonna shit,
then he's gonna kill us.
Relax, all right?
My old man is a television repairman.
He's got this ultimate set of tools.
I can fix it!
You can't fix this car, Spicoli!
- I can fix it.
- Ha.
Hey!
- I'm giving you $50...
- No, no, no!
That means if you win
I give you $25.
If I win, you give me $5.
- You can't lose.
- All right.
I'll put you down for $5.
Now, don't forget about
the 14-point spread.
Fourteen-point sp...
I don't believe those guys
at Lincoln did this to Jefferson's car!
They totalled it.
I can't believe it.
Jefferson's gonna really make
Lincoln pay for this.
That guy's gonna totally
destroy them.
Annihilate.
You know what I mean?
Shit, he is pissed off.
They may well mean
what they say about you
You might wander back
to future friends
Come too close
and take you by the hand
'Cause now you see there's more
to life then what we lovers do
- Oh, shit!
- Hut. Hut.
Brought down again
by 33, Charles Jefferson.
Hit by Jefferson.
Crushed by Jefferson.
Man! Jefferson. Jefferson.
Jefferson. Jefferson.
Jefferson.
Stretcher!
Again by Jefferson.
Five, four, three, two, one!
- There's nothing to eat here.
- What do you mean?
- Take a look. There's nothing I can eat.
- Get a trout dog.
Forget it. Do you have any fish here
that isn't breaded?
- It's all prepared the same way.
- Get a whaler.
Or a clamwich.
Ever hear the word blemish?
Want me to eat something fried?
- Let's get outta here.
- Let's go.
Thank you.
Come again, and have a nice day.
I sent a letter to Doug today.
Can't wait 'til he gets out here.
- What's Doug doing in Chicago?
- He works for the airline.
You'll meet him.
Oh, Linda, you have to do this.
- What?
- "Rate Your Mate."
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- Let me test Doug.
- Okay.
"Most satisfactory
lovemaking occurs:
"A, when your mate climaxes first.
B, you climax first.
C, you and your mate climax together?"
Climax together.
This is gonna be great, Rat.
It's like the highlight of their day.
Maybe we oughta call first. I don't know
about dropping in like this.
Are you kiddin'?
We're gonna surprise 'em.
Just fix your collar, all right?
Relax. Just be cool.
Attitude, remember?
- Where'd you get that, the hamper?
- Hey, this is clean.
It's like riding a bike.
You fall off, you get right back on.
You mess up a date, do it again!
- Do you always climax with Doug?
- Yes.
I think so.
He's no high school boy.
Hey!
Come over to help you
with your math homework.
Figured you could use it
on such a hot day.
Don't worry.
They're gonna let us in.
Okay.
- Promise you're going to leave
as soon as my mother gets home.
- Okay.
- Linda, this is Mike and Mark.
- How you doin'?
The water looks great.
Check it out.
Looks fine.
Wai...
Very funny!
-  Lin, come in!
-  I'll teach you to dive.
I used to be a champion, you know.
Does Mom know you have company?
It's just Mark and Mike from school.
- Hi.
-  How ya doin'?
- Hi, Linda.
- Hi, Brad.
Ow!
Uh, could you keep it down?
I have work to do inside.
Okay.
Who's his tailor?
God, he hardly even talks anymore.
Yeah, I know.
He hates wearing a uniform.
Rat, show them
how you can stand up underwater.
? Da-um-da-um-da-um?
What are you doing?
- Watch out, Rat!
- Leave me alone!
All right, Damone,
you're gonna get it.
Hi, Brad.
You know how cute
I always thought you were.
Stacy, do you have Q-tips?
I've got water in my ears.
I don't know.
Check in the house.
Wait. Just a minute.
Doesn't anybody
fucking knock anymore?
In 1898, Spain owned Cuba outright.
Think about it.
Cuba owned by a disorganized
parliament 4,000 miles away.
Cubans were in a constant...
Cubans were in
a constant state of revolt.
In 1904...
the United States decided
to throw weight around...
- Who is it?
- Mr. Pizza Guy.
- Again?
- Mr. Pizza Guy, sir.
- Who ordered
the double cheese and sausage?
- Right here, dude.
For you, dude.
Am I hallucinating? What in the hell
do you think you're doing?
Learning about Cuba,
and having some food.
Mr. Spicoli,
you're on dangerous ground.
You're causing a major disturbance
on my time.
I've been thinking about this,
Mr. Hand.
If I'm here and you're here,
doesn't that make it "our" time?
There's nothing wrong
with a feast on "our" time.
You're absolutely right.
It is our time.
Yours, mine and everyone else's
in this room.
But it is my class.
Hamilton, Brandt, Cornfeld, up front!
Mr. Spicoli has been kind enough
to bring us a snack.
Be my guest.
Help yourselves.
Get a good one.
- Mike? Mike? Hi.
- Hi.
- How you doing?
- Good. How are you?
I hate walking. I have to walk
every day. It's such a drag.
Why don't you get a ride
with somebody?
Sometimes I ride with my brother,
but he works mornings.
- Then he drives himself to school.
- What a guy!
Listen, Mark Ratner
really likes you.
- Do you like him?
- Mark is really nice.
But I think I like you.
Well, uh... this is me.
- Do you have any iced tea?
- Yeah, sure.
Come on in.
The annuals are coming out
pretty soon.
- You gonna get one?
- I don't know.
Oh, come on. Aren't you curious
to see how your picture turned out?
- I know what I look like.
- I know.
But it's nice to have pictures
of your friends and stuff.
I don't know. Maybe.
It's no big deal.
I probably will.
Must be nice having a pool.
- You want to go swimming?
- Yeah, sure.
- I'm going to go change, okay?
- Yeah.
Okay, great.
This is great iced tea.
- Come on.
- Huh?
Brad keeps his stuff
in the change room.
- This is nice.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- These'll fit you.
- You're really a good kisser.
- Yeah?
So are you.
You want to take off
your clothes, Mike?
You first.
Both of us at the same time.
Okay.
Are you okay?
Ahh.
I think I came.
Didn't you feel it?
Yeah. I guess I did.
I gotta go, Stacy.
I've really gotta go.
- See ya.
- Bye.
Linda, how long does Doug take?
- Doug takes forever.
- Come on.
He takes, uh... 20 to 30 minutes.
I thought you said
he took 30 to 40 minutes.
That's right. I'm sorry.
I meant 30 to 40 minutes.
How long did Damone take?
Damone took, uh...
15 to 20 minutes.
That's not bad for a high school boy.
- Mike! Hi!
- Hi.
- God, I haven't seen you for a while.
- Yeah.
- In a hurry. Got stuff I gotta do.
- I'm in a hurry too.
- I just thought I'd say hi to you.
- Hi.
Hamilton, I'll take over
the fryer for a while.
Those boys at I.B.M. Ordered a stack
of those Catch-of-the-Day boxes.
- I told them you would personally
deliver them within the hour.
- Aye, aye, sir.
Hamilton, come over here.
- What are you doing?
- I'm changing.
You took off your Captain Hook uniform.
I thought I'd put street clothes on
for the drive to I.B.M.
The uniform's uncomfortable.
You're going there as a representative
of Captain Hook Fish and Chips.
Part of our image, part of our appeal
is that uniform. You know that.
You want me to put
the stuff back on?
Yes, I do. Show a little pride.
Aye, aye, sir.
Dina, can you honestly tell me
that you forgot?
Forgot the magnetism of Robin Zander
or the charisma of Rick Nielsen?
- That's kid stuff.
- Kid stuff?
Can I talk to you for a sec?
Stacy, I'm doing business.
Call me tonight, all right?
No. I've gotta talk to you now.
Okay?
Don't go away.
Look at 'em.
I hope this is important
because I could be blowin' a big deal.
Mike, I just...
I just want you to know
that I'm pregnant.
How do you know it's mine?
We only did it once.
I haven't been with anybody else.
I know it's yours.
Jesus!
It was your idea.
You wanted to do it.
You wanted it more than I did.
No.
Take that back.
All right.
I take it back.
Look, we gotta do somethin' about it.
I mean, uh,
we gotta get an abortion.
My brother Art got his girlfriend
one once. It's simple.
- It's no big deal.
- Yeah. I got that planned.
It's going to cost $150
at the Free Clinic.
Doesn't sound free to me.
I suppose you want me
to pay for it.
Half, okay?
And a ride to the clinic.
Seventy-five dollars and a ride.
Okay.
Okay. Thanks.
Thank you.
God.
Rick, I need that $50 you owe me.
- Don't have it.
- I know times are tight,
but I really need it.
- Don't have it now.
- When you needed the tickets,
I got 'em for you.
So close to stage
you probably scared the band.
I'm not the Bank of America.
I know you're not the Bank of America,
but I need my $50.
- How about Thursday?
- Thursday's too late.
I need it tonight.
Can't give you what I don't have.
Just forget about it.
I'll get it from you Thursday, okay?
All right.
See ya.
Is Mike there?
This is Stacy.
Hold on, please.
Stacy, he says he's helping
his father in the garage.
He'll call you later.
Brad!
Wait a second.
- Yeah, this is it.
We're just going bowling.
- Okay.
- Thanks a lot.
- See you later.
Okay.
- How we doing in here?
Debbie, you ready to leave?
- Yes. Thank you.
Stacy, I can't let you go
unless you have a ride home.
- Oh. I told my boyfriend
to meet me downstairs.
- Okay.
Thanks.
Brad.
Since when do you
go bowling anyway?
Okay, Brad.
Please don't tell Mom and Dad.
Come on!
Who did it?
You're not gonna tell me, are you?
Okay.
It'll just be your secret.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Come on.
- You hungry?
- Yeah.
I told you to tell Mike to pay for it.
Why didn't you tell him?
Linda, he didn't show up.
That little prick!
I called his house.
His mother told me he was
in the garage helping his father.
Mike Damone's
a no-brain little prick, Stacy.
I'm not gonna let him
get away with this.
Linda, please don't do anything.
I don't even like the guy.
Stacy, he's not a guy.
He's a little prick!
Hi, Mikey!
Hi, Damone.
Damone, what went on
between you and Stacy?
Let me tell you something.
Sometimes girls go haywire.
It happened a month ago.
I've been trying to think
of a way to tell you ever since.
We were out... messin' around,
and something happened.
It's over.
It's no big deal.
I never even called her again.
If you ask me,
she's a very aggressive girl.
- Do you understand?
- No, I don't understand.
- She never really was your girlfriend.
- Fuck you, Damone.
There are a lot of girls out there,
and you have to mess around with Stacy?
What do you gotta prove, anyway?
I'm sorry.
I always stick up for you.
Whenever people say, "That Damone, he's
a loudmouth," and they say that a lot,
I always say,
"Hey, you just don't know Damone."
When they call you an idiot,
I say, "Damone's not an idiot.
You just don't know him."
Well, you know something, man?
Maybe they do know you pretty good.
Maybe I'm just finding out now.
Get lost.
You want to do something about it, Rat?
You want to do something about it?
Come on.
- Come on, you wuss!
- Okay. Let's go, man.
- I'll break your fuckin' head off.
- Do something, man.
- A big talker, man!
- Knock this crap off!
Take it somewhere else.
Not in my gym, buddy.
Shit.
Woke up in a great mood.
I don't know what the hell happened.
Come on. Hurry up.
Hurry up.
Today we're going to explore
how this hospital preserves human life.
We'll be visiting every floor
where these fine doctors and nurses...
take care of us in life...
and in death.
Over 30 children
are delivered here each day.
Dr. Kramer to the nurses' station.
- Good morning, Doctor.
- Hi.
Class, this is Dr. Miller.
He'll be joining us
for the last part of our tour today.
If you guys will follow me, please.
I'd like to ask you one last time.
Conduct yourselves
with the utmost maturity.
- You in my class?
- I am today.
-  Yes, Greg?
- Who are these guys?
Most of them are derelicts.
They sold their bodies
to medicine for money.
- About $30, I think?
- Twenty-five.
Righteous bucks!
This gentleman here is named Arthur.
Arthur was good enough
to die last week of heart failure.
We are fortunate today
to view his body...
in its pristine state.
Here an incision has been made.
The ribs have been sawed off,
allowing us to remove
the breastplate...
and really observe the human organs
as they exist in their natural state.
Here we have the human lungs.
And here is the human heart
which, you can see,
is actually located
in the center of your chest.
Ohh! Gnarly!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm fine.
- I just made a jerk out of myself.
- No, you didn't.
Can't go back in there.
Sure. We'll wait until they come out,
and then we'll blend in.
Here they come.
You're so nice.
You should be comin' on pretty soon,
dude. How much did you smoke?
This'll be
a little demonstration of that.
Listen up.
- What was that?
- That was my skull.
-
- I'm so wasted!
Oh, man!
What is this stuff?
Doesn't that stuff
cause brain damage?
- Only if you take it
every day for a month.
- Bitchin'!
- Dude, I'll pick you up in
the van and go to the dance.
- Later.
Jeff, you have company.
Get out of here, Curtis.
I don't hear you unless you knock.
That's better. Entre.
Mr. Hand!
Well, were you going somewhere
tonight, Jeff?
Yeah.
The graduation dance.
It's the last school fiesta
of the year.
Hmm. I'm afraid we've got
some business to discuss here.
Did I do something wrong, Mr. Hand?
According to my calculations,
Mr. Spicoli,
you wasted a total of, uh,
eight hours of my time this year.
And rest assured,
that is a kind estimate.
Now I have the unique pleasure
of squaring our account.
Tonight you and I are going to talk in
great detail about the Davis Agreement,
all the associated treaties, and
the American Revolution in particular.
If you can turn to page 47
of Land of Truth and Liberty.
Oh, I left that book in my locker,
Mr. Hand.
In that case, I'm glad I remembered to
bring an extra copy... just for you.
Look, Mark.
I want to apologize for
everything that's happened.
I'm really sorry.
A guy just doesn't do that to a buddy.
I understand.
You can't help it.
You're just lewd,
crude and obnoxious.
- I can deal with that.
- Excuse me.
Are we still friends?
- Huh?
- Okay.
All right.
What Jefferson
was saying was, "Hey!
"We left this England place
'cause it was bogus.
"So if we don't get some cool rules
ourselves... pronto,
we'll just be bogus too."
Very close, Jeff.
I think I've made my point with you
tonight.
Do you have a guy like me
in class every year?
You know,
a guy who you make an example of?
- You'll find out next year.
- No way!
As soon as I cruise history, I'm not
coming near your side of the building.
- "Cruise history"?
- Soon as I pass your class.
Ooh. If you pass.
You're gonna flunk me?
Don't worry, Spicoli.
You'll probably squeak by.
Yeah! Aloha, Mr. Hand.
Aloha, Spicoli.
Honey,
these are my two star students.
Boys, I'd like you to meet
my wife, Mrs. Vargas.
Hi.
Summer!
Yea!
Totally!
I wrote him a letter.
Tell me what you think.
"Dear Doug.
"I received your message that
you weren't coming to my graduation.
"Doug, this is not the kind of thing
that occurs between adults.
"Maybe you've found someone new,
someone more mature.
"But if you ask me, Doug,
you're the one being childish.
"Anyhow, if you think I'm gonna
sit around and wait for you, forget it.
- Sincerely, Linda." What do you think?
- Uh...
I have another version
where I call him an asshole.
No, that one's better.
It's more...
- Mature?
- Yeah.
- I don't have to sink to his level.
- I can go out with anyone I want,
practically.
- That's right.
Yeah.
Thanks for cheering me up.
Come on.
Hey, dude!
I know that song.
Hey, I'm not.
I'm not.
Hey, come on down
from there.
Linda, I finally figured it out.
I don't want sex.
Anyone can have sex.
- What do you want?
- I want a relationship.
- I want romance.
- You want romance?
In Ridgemont? We can't even get
cable TV here, and you want romance.
Another summer at Perry's.
I can't. I swear.
It's not that bad.
Keep your eyes open.
There's lots of men around here.
- How you doin'?
- Fine.
I'm glad you came over...
'cause I have this picture of me
that I wanted to give to you...
so that you'll remember
to call me over the summer.
I don't know. I'm going to be traveling
a lot this summer and I'm not sure...
I'll give you a call sometime.
- That'd be great.
-  Stacy!
- You worked at All-American Burger!
- Seven months ago.
Uh-huh.
I knew it.
Why don't you get a job,
Spicoli?
- What for?
- You need money.
All I need are some tasty waves,
a cool buzz, and I'm fine.
Thanks.
Can I use your bathroom?
Yeah, go ahead.
- It's the first door on the left.
- Like up this ramp?
First door on the left.
Money, and I want it now.
Now!
- Okay. Okay. Um...
- Now!
What are you doin'?
The safe!
Behind the doughnuts.
I've been watchin' this place.
I know what I'm doin'.
- Open it up. Open it up!
- Okay.
C'mon! C'mon!
I just started here. They just
taught me the procedure and l...
Let me figure it out.
- Come on, shit head. Let's go.
- Get off my case, motherfucker!
Hey, no towels, man.
- I got you, you son of a bitch.
- Oh, motherfucker!
There goes your ride home.
Awesome! Totally awesome!
All right, Hamilton.