4
00:03:21,660 --> 00:03:23,910
I'm gonna play it again.

5
00:03:23,990 --> 00:03:26,020
You play that thing one more time, 

6
00:03:26,020 --> 00:03:29,080
and I'm gonna melt it down into hair spray.

7
00:03:29,160 --> 00:03:31,420
Well, let me play the other side then. 

8
00:03:31,420 --> 00:03:33,830
No, Rayette. It's not a question of sides.

9
00:03:33,920 --> 00:03:36,960
It's a question of musical integrity.

10
00:03:37,050 --> 00:03:39,760
Well, then let me sing one for ya.When there's a

11
00:03:39,840 --> 00:03:41,550
Hold it. Hold it.

12
00:03:42,550 --> 00:03:44,760
-Oh-ho, Bobby! -What? What?

13
00:03:44,850 --> 00:03:47,260
-You quit that now. -What? What?

14
00:03:47,350 --> 00:03:49,220
-You said you're gonna help me pick a song. -I did?

15
00:03:49,310 --> 00:03:52,390
I'm gonna cut off your damn water, Bobby, I swear.

16
00:03:58,360 --> 00:04:00,440
Selfish.

17
00:04:00,530 --> 00:04:03,110
You can play on the piano, and your whole damn family...

18
00:04:03,200 --> 00:04:06,120
can play on some type of musical instrument.

19
00:04:06,200 --> 00:04:09,830
And all I'm askin' is for you to help me improve my musical talent.

20
00:04:09,910 --> 00:04:12,120
And you'd think you would.

21
00:04:13,500 --> 00:04:16,500
Dipesto, why don't you take that sign off your tit...

22
00:04:16,590 --> 00:04:20,210
and why don't you and me go out and have us a real good time?

23
00:04:21,380 --> 00:04:23,420
Where are we goin'?

24
00:04:24,970 --> 00:04:29,180
I don't know. But I'll holler up to Elton and Stoney.

25
00:04:31,810 --> 00:04:34,600
Bobby, now, listen a minute.

26
00:04:36,150 --> 00:04:38,940
You know, I'll go out with you...

27
00:04:39,020 --> 00:04:42,150
or... I'll stay in with you...

28
00:04:42,240 --> 00:04:45,860
or I'll do anything that you like for me to do...

29
00:04:45,950 --> 00:04:48,820
if you will tell me that you love me.

30
00:04:51,080 --> 00:04:53,410
You can sing the song.

31
00:05:02,090 --> 00:05:04,590
You are never satisfied.

32
00:05:07,010 --> 00:05:08,590
That's right.

33
00:05:11,890 --> 00:05:15,560
Oh, honey, I'm sorry.

34
00:05:24,440 --> 00:05:27,110
All right. Here it is.

35
00:05:34,000 --> 00:05:36,370
They were all set up right for ya.

36
00:05:36,460 --> 00:05:38,670
Get right in there, Dipesto.

37
00:05:38,750 --> 00:05:41,880
-That's all you gotta do. Just relax, honey. -Come on, Rayette!

38
00:05:41,960 --> 00:05:43,590
-Keep that left foot -The right 

39
00:05:43,590 --> 00:05:44,960
-left foot forward. -Bear down. Bear down.

40
00:05:52,260 --> 00:05:54,770
Not too much of a match, is it, Elton?

41
00:05:54,850 --> 00:05:56,850
You better leap out with your right foot.

42
00:06:00,650 --> 00:06:04,570
-In the gutter. Isn't that wonderful? -The ball's too heavy for me, honey.

43
00:06:04,650 --> 00:06:07,240
The pins, you know. I can't see them. I can't make 'em out.

44
00:06:07,320 --> 00:06:08,900
Just squint. I squint.

45
00:06:08,990 --> 00:06:10,620
Well, there they are right down there. 

46
00:06:10,620 --> 00:06:12,530
They're at the end of all these little boards.

47
00:06:12,620 --> 00:06:15,080
You notice 'em leadin' down. Just spot and follow through.

48
00:06:15,160 --> 00:06:17,410
-But there are so many of 'em. -What's that for?

49
00:06:17,500 --> 00:06:19,000
-That's for luck. -Oh, you're crazy.

50
00:06:19,080 --> 00:06:22,080
-Go on out there and show Ray how to do it. -You slobbered on me.

51
00:06:22,170 --> 00:06:23,750
It ain't the first time.

52
00:06:23,840 --> 00:06:26,460
Watch this.

53
00:06:26,550 --> 00:06:29,880
There she is. She's doing a little variation on the Apache shift.

54
00:06:29,970 --> 00:06:34,220
I taught her that.

55
00:06:34,310 --> 00:06:37,980
-Are you mad at me? -No, I'm not mad at you, honey. It'll be all right.

56
00:06:38,060 --> 00:06:40,850
-We're not excited. -Look at me and tell me you're not mad at me.

57
00:06:40,940 --> 00:06:42,650
I'm not mad at you.

58
00:06:47,030 --> 00:06:49,610
-Listen. I'm gonna show you how it gets done. -Go on. Beat it.

59
00:06:49,700 --> 00:06:52,490
-Don't talk about it. do it. -Isn’t he pretty?

60
00:06:56,040 --> 00:06:59,040
Good one!

61
00:06:59,120 --> 00:07:01,620
Very good.

62
00:07:04,710 --> 00:07:07,670
Show me a little somethin' now. Give me spirit. Give me something.

63
00:07:13,680 --> 00:07:16,810
That stupid thing just goes all cocky-wobbly, honey.

64
00:07:16,890 --> 00:07:20,350
-If you'd just do what the hell I tell ya. -I did! Didn't I, El?

65
00:07:20,440 --> 00:07:22,650
You got another ball coming.

66
00:07:26,610 --> 00:07:28,530
-Come on, Rayette. -Just relax, Ray. That's all.

67
00:07:32,860 --> 00:07:35,990
 Attaboy, Ray!

68
00:07:36,080 --> 00:07:38,660
That was real good, wasn't it?

69
00:07:38,750 --> 00:07:40,410
I finally did it.

70
00:07:40,500 --> 00:07:43,960
Great. You throw the big Z's for 19 frames...

71
00:07:44,040 --> 00:07:48,000
and then you throw a strike on the last ball of a losin' game.

72
00:07:48,090 --> 00:07:51,800
Wonderful. Just wonderful. Wasn't that wonderful, ladies?

73
00:07:51,880 --> 00:07:54,760
-Are you talking to us? -Wonderful.

74
00:07:56,600 --> 00:07:58,890
I guess I'll go wait in the car.

75
00:07:58,970 --> 00:08:01,520
Why don't you go wait in the car, Rayette?

76
00:08:01,600 --> 00:08:04,100
I will. I'll wait there right now.

77
00:08:04,190 --> 00:08:06,190
One minute, honey, and I'll go with ya.

78
00:08:13,320 --> 00:08:16,870
Me and Stoney got to get on home, relieve the sitter.

79
00:08:16,950 --> 00:08:20,580
Why don't you and Ray just come on by the place?

80
00:08:20,660 --> 00:08:22,870
All right. Uh, why don't you go on?

81
00:08:22,960 --> 00:08:26,630
Here. I'll, uh-I'll take care of the beers.

82
00:08:26,710 --> 00:08:30,170
-And would you walk Rayette along with ya? -Sure.

83
00:08:30,260 --> 00:08:32,460
Thanks, El.

84
00:08:51,400 --> 00:08:54,240
-Oh. Uh, what do we owe you? -Four dollars, sir.

85
00:08:54,320 --> 00:08:55,950
Okay.

86
00:08:56,030 --> 00:08:58,780
Excuse me.

87
00:08:58,870 --> 00:09:01,620
-Here's a five. Thanks very much. -Thank you.

88
00:09:06,670 --> 00:09:11,380
We've been wanting to ask you. You're on the TV, aren't ya?

89
00:09:11,460 --> 00:09:13,960
Am I? On the TV?

90
00:09:14,050 --> 00:09:19,550
She says you're the guy that sells all the cars on... TV.

91
00:09:20,850 --> 00:09:24,350
Well, I might have sold a few cars.

92
00:09:24,430 --> 00:09:28,270
I told ya! My name's Shirley, but they call me Betty.

93
00:09:28,360 --> 00:09:30,440
And her name's Twinky.

94
00:09:30,520 --> 00:09:33,780
-Twinky? -Yeah, 'cause she's so twinky!

95
00:09:33,860 --> 00:09:36,490
Boy, oh, boy.

96
00:09:36,570 --> 00:09:41,280
Well, Betty and Twinky, it, uh, sure is nice talking to you girls.

97
00:09:41,370 --> 00:09:43,450
I wish that I had some more time.

98
00:09:43,540 --> 00:09:45,830
-That's a wig you wear, isn't it? -Me?

99
00:09:45,910 --> 00:09:48,620
Yeah. I told her it was you, but that you're wearing a wig...

100
00:09:48,710 --> 00:09:53,420
'cause on TV you're mostly all, uh, bald up there.

101
00:09:55,470 --> 00:09:58,050
Yeah, your little friend's real-real sharp.

102
00:09:58,130 --> 00:09:59,890
Well, I don't, uh 

103
00:09:59,970 --> 00:10:01,930
I don't wear the wig on TV...

104
00:10:02,010 --> 00:10:03,180
because if you're gonna be out 

105
00:10:03,180 --> 00:10:05,520
there in front of two and a half million people...

106
00:10:05,600 --> 00:10:07,690
you've got to be sincere.

107
00:10:07,770 --> 00:10:10,980
I mean, I like to wear it when I'm in bowling alleys and slipping around.

108
00:10:11,060 --> 00:10:14,020
Stuff like that. I think it gives me a little class. What do you think?

109
00:10:14,110 --> 00:10:18,150
-Oh, definitely. -Yeah, but I can see a little bitty of the net up there.

110
00:10:18,240 --> 00:10:20,280
That's what give it away.

111
00:10:20,370 --> 00:10:23,030
A little net.

112
00:10:23,120 --> 00:10:26,950
Yeah, well, I-I wish I had more time to talk to you girls...

113
00:10:27,040 --> 00:10:29,710
but, uh, I have to 

114
00:10:42,930 --> 00:10:45,760
Come on, Ray. We're gonna go over to Elton's.

115
00:10:45,850 --> 00:10:48,350
I'm not.

116
00:10:48,440 --> 00:10:50,600
You're just gonna sit here?

117
00:10:50,690 --> 00:10:52,810
Yes.

118
00:10:52,900 --> 00:10:56,570
Okay. I hope no one hits on you.

119
00:10:56,650 --> 00:10:58,610
I hope they do.

120
00:11:00,610 --> 00:11:04,240
Okay. See you later.

121
00:11:29,980 --> 00:11:33,980
No one would want to hit on you. You look too pathetic.

122
00:11:36,230 --> 00:11:39,690
Come on, Dipesto. We can still have a good time.

123
00:11:41,400 --> 00:11:44,110
You're the pathetic one, not me.

124
00:11:45,830 --> 00:11:47,990
I'm goin' over to Elton's.

125
00:11:52,750 --> 00:11:55,630
I am not a piece of crap.

126
00:11:59,510 --> 00:12:02,800
I'm sorry.

127
00:12:02,880 --> 00:12:05,180
You treat me like I was.

128
00:12:07,890 --> 00:12:12,180
Go slip around... right before my face.

129
00:12:13,230 --> 00:12:16,310
And in front of Elton and Stoney that way.

130
00:12:17,770 --> 00:12:20,610
What do you imagine they think of somebody you treat like that?

131
00:12:20,690 --> 00:12:23,360
Now, now, Ray.

132
00:12:29,370 --> 00:12:32,660
Now, sweetheart, Elton and Stoney know that I love ya.

133
00:12:32,750 --> 00:12:36,500
They're just gonna think that I'm not too nice a guy, which I'm not...

134
00:12:36,580 --> 00:12:39,480
and that you're a real hell of a good person 

135
00:12:39,480 --> 00:12:41,300
for puttin' up with me, that's all.

136
00:12:41,380 --> 00:12:45,340
You'll just find me dead one time.

137
00:12:47,390 --> 00:12:49,300
Just kill me.

138
00:12:52,730 --> 00:12:54,890
Come on, be a good girl.

139
00:12:56,560 --> 00:12:59,400
You ever really get up and leave me...

140
00:12:59,480 --> 00:13:01,820
you'll read about it in the newsprint.

141
00:13:01,900 --> 00:13:04,900
I'm not gonna get up and leave you.

142
00:13:11,620 --> 00:13:13,200
Now, come on.

143
00:13:13,290 --> 00:13:16,370
Let's go over to Elton's and have a good time.

144
00:13:19,090 --> 00:13:21,500
You love me, Bobby?

145
00:13:23,840 --> 00:13:25,760
What do you think?

146
00:14:04,840 --> 00:14:06,010
Fuck.

147
00:14:07,090 --> 00:14:09,720
You got banana on your face.

148
00:14:09,800 --> 00:14:11,300
I do?

149
00:14:14,430 --> 00:14:18,020
I still ain't figured out how you got me workin' back out here.

150
00:14:19,730 --> 00:14:21,610
I got you to come and work out here?

151
00:14:21,690 --> 00:14:22,870
I ain't figured out how 

152
00:14:22,870 --> 00:14:25,480
you let me get you to come out here and work on these rigs.

153
00:14:25,570 --> 00:14:29,360
I've never worked on these damn things before. You've worked on 'em before.

154
00:14:29,450 --> 00:14:32,870
I can't figure out how you let me get us out here.

155
00:14:32,950 --> 00:14:36,500
Somebody had to look out for you.

156
00:14:37,790 --> 00:14:39,710
You're a mess.

157
00:14:39,790 --> 00:14:42,710
You're crazy.

158
00:15:00,270 --> 00:15:03,020
-All right. I'm gonna bet two dollars right off. -I'm in.

159
00:15:03,110 --> 00:15:05,730
-I think you're bullshittin' me now. -Well, I have to see it.

160
00:15:05,820 --> 00:15:07,730
-What you got, Bill? -A pair of nines.

161
00:15:07,820 --> 00:15:10,530
-Can you beat two pair? -There's three aces right there, natural -

162
00:15:10,610 --> 00:15:14,580
-Oh, you pull me. -I pull -I got me a hand!

163
00:15:14,660 --> 00:15:17,830
I think it's time for me to go home. See you in the mornin', boys.

164
00:15:17,910 --> 00:15:19,590
See you in the morning, Glenn. 

165
00:15:19,590 --> 00:15:22,580
I don't know if I'm goin' out there tomorrow at all, man.

166
00:15:22,670 --> 00:15:26,420
I've-I got a-I got a lot of money tied up in everything I got.

167
00:15:28,420 --> 00:15:31,470
I don't want no chains going around and all this.

168
00:15:31,550 --> 00:15:33,970
It's all right, but I prefer card playing. Where is it?

169
00:15:34,050 --> 00:15:36,430
What the hell is goin' on in the middle of this game?

170
00:15:36,510 --> 00:15:39,060
People talkin' and all this. We got money here or what?

171
00:15:46,610 --> 00:15:50,530
Okay. When I was four, just four years old...

172
00:15:50,610 --> 00:15:54,660
I went to my mother and I said, "What's this hole in my chin?"

173
00:15:54,740 --> 00:15:58,200
I saw this dimple in my chin in the mirror and didn't know what it was.

174
00:15:58,290 --> 00:16:00,370
And my mother said-Guess what my mother says.

175
00:16:00,460 --> 00:16:03,670
She says, "When you're born, you go on an assembly line past God.

176
00:16:03,750 --> 00:16:05,860
"And if he likes you, he says, 

177
00:16:05,860 --> 00:16:07,590
'You cute little thing,' and you get dimples there."

178
00:16:07,670 --> 00:16:11,130
"And if he doesn't like you, he goes, 'Go away."'

179
00:16:11,220 --> 00:16:15,680
So, about six months later, my mother found me saying my prayers...

180
00:16:15,760 --> 00:16:18,180
and I was going, "Now I lay me down to sleep."

181
00:16:18,260 --> 00:16:21,520
My mother says, "What are you covering up your chin for?"

182
00:16:21,600 --> 00:16:24,960
And I said, "Because if I cover up the hole, 

183
00:16:24,960 --> 00:16:27,060
maybe he'll listen to me."

184
00:17:04,640 --> 00:17:07,940
"Unfit." I look unfit to you, Elton? 

185
00:17:07,940 --> 00:17:08,940
I'm fit! I'm fit.

186
00:17:23,620 --> 00:17:26,460
Don't you know no songs about women or nothin'?

187
00:17:26,540 --> 00:17:31,130
Yeah, but I'm just too loaded to think of 'em now.

188
00:17:31,210 --> 00:17:34,720
-Hey, watch out for all this traffic. -Oh, God!

189
00:17:34,800 --> 00:17:36,430
I ain't in no hurry.

190
00:17:36,510 --> 00:17:41,260
Believe starting off your day like this, goin' to work?

191
00:17:41,350 --> 00:17:43,720
Unbelievable. Let me have a drink, will ya?

192
00:17:45,350 --> 00:17:47,020
Thanks, Elton.

193
00:17:49,860 --> 00:17:51,980
Ooh, boy, that's tough in the morning.

194
00:17:52,980 --> 00:17:56,070
What the hell are these people doing here?

195
00:18:00,280 --> 00:18:05,620
Isn’t this some goddamn thing, Elton? Jesus Christ!

196
00:18:10,630 --> 00:18:14,800
What does he want? Boy, I can't stand this goddamn freeway.

197
00:18:18,930 --> 00:18:20,840
Oh, yeah, I heard ya!

198
00:18:20,930 --> 00:18:23,530
Why don't you flash your lights so's we can see 

199
00:18:23,530 --> 00:18:25,560
what else you got for Christmas?

200
00:18:28,350 --> 00:18:30,600
Yeah, yeah, yeah!

201
00:18:30,690 --> 00:18:32,980
Where you goin'?

202
00:18:36,280 --> 00:18:41,200
Ants! Why don't we all line up like a goddamn bunch of ants...

203
00:18:41,280 --> 00:18:44,990
in the most beautiful part of the day and gas ourselves!

204
00:18:56,380 --> 00:18:58,420
Hey, get off my car.

205
00:19:14,610 --> 00:19:16,530
Hey, Bobby!

206
00:19:29,160 --> 00:19:31,210
Oh, shit! What's he doing?

207
00:19:57,610 --> 00:19:59,990
Play it!

208
00:20:06,490 --> 00:20:10,660
You better quit foolin' around! Come on!

209
00:20:10,750 --> 00:20:15,420
Bobby, he's turning!

210
00:20:15,500 --> 00:20:17,420
Will you hold your horses?

212
00:22:01,610 --> 00:22:05,030
I was with Elton last night, Rayette.

213
00:22:05,110 --> 00:22:06,950
It's the truth.

214
00:22:19,960 --> 00:22:21,500
Rayette.

215
00:22:32,810 --> 00:22:34,890
You son of a bitch!

216
00:23:03,540 --> 00:23:05,750
Now reach for it. Come on, reach for it.

217
00:23:05,840 --> 00:23:08,470
Come on.

218
00:23:08,550 --> 00:23:11,090
It's good for you. Come on. Let's go see Bob.

219
00:23:11,180 --> 00:23:13,220
I can't see!

220
00:23:22,310 --> 00:23:26,440
-Isn’t he sweet? -I can't see the set.

221
00:23:26,530 --> 00:23:31,320
-You take him for a while. Go ahead now. -How you doin'?

222
00:23:32,870 --> 00:23:35,950
You oughta get yourself one of them little things, Bobby.

223
00:23:40,830 --> 00:23:43,290
Ah! That's it.

224
00:23:43,380 --> 00:23:47,210
Just crush that one too, then I won't get any.

225
00:23:47,300 --> 00:23:50,010
Bless my soul. It's a new harmonica.

226
00:23:50,090 --> 00:23:52,550
-That's for your birthday. -My birthday?

227
00:23:52,640 --> 00:23:56,970
How do you know when my birthday is? I don't even know myself.

228
00:23:57,060 --> 00:23:59,020
Bye, Stoney.

229
00:24:00,730 --> 00:24:03,100
The kitchen's on fire, Stoney.

230
00:24:05,560 --> 00:24:07,860
Your mother just died, Stoney.

231
00:24:07,940 --> 00:24:09,690
-Bye-bye. -Bye.

232
00:24:10,780 --> 00:24:12,650
-See you, Elton. -All right, Bob.

233
00:24:12,740 --> 00:24:14,910
See you later. Thanks a lot.

234
00:24:15,990 --> 00:24:17,910
Incidentally, what's his name?

235
00:24:17,990 --> 00:24:21,500
You just love that little baby, don't you?

236
00:24:23,210 --> 00:24:25,540
Well, what if she was, Bob?

237
00:24:25,630 --> 00:24:28,710
I can't see nothing so bad in that.

238
00:24:28,800 --> 00:24:32,800
Well, what if I were to let you in on a little secret that she is?

239
00:24:34,220 --> 00:24:36,340
That's right. She told me.

240
00:24:37,760 --> 00:24:40,770
She's all torn up about it too, which I hate to see.

241
00:24:41,810 --> 00:24:44,940
Oh, hell. Isn’t it something you just have to face up to?

242
00:24:45,020 --> 00:24:46,810
I'll tell ya, somewhere along 

243
00:24:46,810 --> 00:24:49,150
the line you even get to likin' the whole idea.

244
00:24:49,230 --> 00:24:53,570
When Stoney first give me the news, I could've shit.

245
00:24:57,490 --> 00:25:00,240
Well, isn't that nice?

246
00:25:00,330 --> 00:25:02,560
It's ridiculous! I'm sitting here listening 

247
00:25:02,560 --> 00:25:04,210
to some cracker asshole...

248
00:25:04,290 --> 00:25:07,580
lives in a trailer park compare his life to mine.

249
00:25:11,510 --> 00:25:15,880
Keep on telling me about the good life, Elton, because it makes me puke.

250
00:25:15,970 --> 00:25:19,050
Well, if you're sayin' you think you're something better than what I am...

251
00:25:19,140 --> 00:25:20,640
now, that's somethin' else.

252
00:25:20,720 --> 00:25:22,890
But I can't say much of someone who could run off...

253
00:25:22,980 --> 00:25:26,390
and leave a woman in a situation like this and feel easy about it.

254
00:25:26,480 --> 00:25:27,980
And that's all I have to say.

255
00:25:28,060 --> 00:25:30,150
Well, I'm glad that's all you got to say, Elton...

256
00:25:30,230 --> 00:25:32,230
because I'm about as goddamned tired of your mouth...

257
00:25:32,320 --> 00:25:35,650
as I am working on this goddamned job!

258
00:25:40,580 --> 00:25:42,160
Shit-ass!

259
00:25:56,760 --> 00:25:58,680
Hey, Longcipher!

260
00:26:01,180 --> 00:26:03,560
Hey, Longcipher!

261
00:26:04,560 --> 00:26:06,680
Longcipher, I'm quittin'.

262
00:26:06,770 --> 00:26:09,650
Do you hear me, Longcipher? I said I'm quittin'.

263
00:26:09,730 --> 00:26:11,940
I don't give a damn what you do.

264
00:26:12,020 --> 00:26:14,780
I'm glad to get rid of both you dumb guys.

265
00:26:31,210 --> 00:26:33,710
Hey! What's goin' on?

266
00:26:38,220 --> 00:26:39,220
Hey!

267
00:26:43,640 --> 00:26:46,180
Hey, what's goin' on?

268
00:26:49,690 --> 00:26:52,270
Don't do that, Bob. It don't make sense!

269
00:26:52,360 --> 00:26:55,530
They've got the right, Bob! It's the law.

270
00:26:55,610 --> 00:26:58,280
The law.

271
00:27:15,750 --> 00:27:18,210
Hey, don't you think you could just leave him?

272
00:27:18,300 --> 00:27:19,880
I mean, sure as hell, If he'd have known who you were, 

273
00:27:19,880 --> 00:27:21,300
he wouldn't have done that.

274
00:27:21,390 --> 00:27:24,300
-Would you, Bob? -What the hell's goin' on, Elton?

275
00:27:24,390 --> 00:27:26,220
All right. Let him go.

276
00:27:28,060 --> 00:27:30,100
What's goin' on, Elton?

277
00:27:30,190 --> 00:27:33,880
I got accused of robbing a filling station down in the Indian nation. 

278
00:27:33,880 --> 00:27:34,770
Didn't I tell ya?

279
00:27:34,860 --> 00:27:37,860
I just got wild and jumped my bail.

280
00:27:37,940 --> 00:27:42,240
They come runnin' at me a whole year later. Isn’t that somethin'?

281
00:27:43,950 --> 00:27:46,780
Hey, tell Stoney for me, hear?

282
00:29:02,440 --> 00:29:05,110
Hi. Miss Dupea?

283
00:29:05,200 --> 00:29:07,700
Upstairs. Up those stairs.

284
00:29:56,870 --> 00:29:58,960
There she goes again.

285
00:30:00,130 --> 00:30:03,090
My one-year-old can carry a tune better than that.

286
00:30:09,680 --> 00:30:11,100
Miss Dupea?

287
00:30:14,640 --> 00:30:16,680
Miss Dupea.

288
00:30:17,770 --> 00:30:20,020
-Yes? -I'd like to remind you again...

289
00:30:20,110 --> 00:30:23,320
that this is not an opera or a musical comedy.

290
00:30:26,450 --> 00:30:28,860
I'm sorry. Was I singing again?

291
00:30:28,950 --> 00:30:31,370
If you wanna call it that.

292
00:30:31,450 --> 00:30:34,450
Well, you have simply to tell me. That's all.

293
00:30:34,540 --> 00:30:37,460
That's exactly what I am doing again.

294
00:30:37,540 --> 00:30:40,920
Must you let me get two-thirds of the way through the movement?

295
00:30:41,000 --> 00:30:43,590
This is tiring me.

296
00:30:43,670 --> 00:30:47,260
I have another suggestion. Why don't we take a break, Miss Dupea?

297
00:30:47,340 --> 00:30:48,550
For pity sake.

298
00:30:48,630 --> 00:30:51,970
-Is she gonna cry again? -I don't want to take a break.

299
00:30:52,050 --> 00:30:56,560
Some coffee. Uh, what would you like in your coffee, Miss Dupea?

300
00:30:56,640 --> 00:30:59,100
-Tea. -One tea.

301
00:30:59,190 --> 00:31:02,310
-Tell her Bobby's here. -Bobby's here.

302
00:31:06,240 --> 00:31:08,240
Oh, my goodness!

303
00:31:11,240 --> 00:31:13,990
Robert Eroica.

304
00:31:24,000 --> 00:31:26,920
I can't look at you.

305
00:31:27,010 --> 00:31:28,550
Well, don't then.

306
00:31:33,010 --> 00:31:35,560
You always do this to me.

307
00:31:35,640 --> 00:31:38,720
Well, I don't mean to. Here's your tea, Tita.

308
00:31:38,810 --> 00:31:40,430
Thank you.

309
00:31:40,520 --> 00:31:42,100
Don't put it there.

310
00:31:42,190 --> 00:31:44,230
Why? What's wrong?

311
00:31:44,310 --> 00:31:48,280
This is a very special CB 275.

312
00:31:49,610 --> 00:31:51,490
No kidding.

313
00:31:51,570 --> 00:31:55,700
It has absolutely no objectionable idiosyncrasies.

314
00:32:03,210 --> 00:32:06,590
Robert, I have to talk seriously to you.

315
00:32:06,670 --> 00:32:10,420
Everybody still living up on the island?  

316
00:32:10,510 --> 00:32:13,300
At the moment, there's really just...

317
00:32:13,390 --> 00:32:17,640
Daddy, Carl and myself... and Van Oost.

318
00:32:17,720 --> 00:32:19,310
-Who's Van Oost? -Catherine.

319
00:32:19,390 --> 00:32:22,730
She's a pianist. She's working with Carl.

320
00:32:22,810 --> 00:32:25,270
Carl's a fiddler. What's he doing coaching piano?

321
00:32:25,360 --> 00:32:27,770
Well, 11 months ago...

322
00:32:27,860 --> 00:32:31,440
he was on his bicycle on his way to the post office in the village...

323
00:32:32,530 --> 00:32:36,320
and he ran straight into a jeep and sprained his neck.

324
00:32:36,410 --> 00:32:39,950
Strained his neck?

325
00:32:40,040 --> 00:32:43,040
That's not funny. He permanently sprained his neck.

326
00:32:43,120 --> 00:32:47,170
And since then, it's been extremely painful for him to tuck the violin.

327
00:32:48,460 --> 00:32:51,420
Crashes into a jeep and totals his neck.

328
00:32:55,180 --> 00:32:56,680
Robert.

329
00:32:59,510 --> 00:33:02,100
 I have to tell you.

330
00:33:03,270 --> 00:33:05,230
Daddy's very ill.

331
00:33:13,950 --> 00:33:16,780
-What? -He's had two strokes.

332
00:33:23,330 --> 00:33:24,960
He's not 

333
00:33:27,330 --> 00:33:31,840
-They feel he-maybe he might not recover. -Don't tell me about this.

334
00:33:37,590 --> 00:33:40,220
But don't you think it's right...

335
00:33:40,310 --> 00:33:42,770
that you should see him at least once?

336
00:33:42,850 --> 00:33:45,890
-Miss Dupea. -Just a minute, please.

337
00:33:45,980 --> 00:33:48,480
Robert, don't you think it's right you should see him?

338
00:33:48,560 --> 00:33:50,440
Yeah. I guess so.

339
00:33:50,520 --> 00:33:53,900
I'm going back up tonight. Will you come with me?

340
00:33:53,990 --> 00:33:55,950
No.

341
00:33:56,030 --> 00:33:58,740
I-I'd rather drive up.

342
00:33:58,820 --> 00:34:01,370
Maybe I'll go into Canada after.

343
00:34:03,580 --> 00:34:06,750
I'm not gonna stay long, Tita. You know, one week at the most.

344
00:34:06,830 --> 00:34:08,420
I know.

345
00:34:12,210 --> 00:34:13,710
Well.

346
00:34:16,970 --> 00:34:18,510
Come on. I'll walk you out.

347
00:34:20,390 --> 00:34:22,010
I'll be back in two minutes.

348
00:34:22,100 --> 00:34:24,430
We've had our break, Miss Dupea.

349
00:34:24,520 --> 00:34:28,020
-They hate me, I feel. -Maybe you'd better stay.

350
00:34:30,310 --> 00:34:33,940
I want to talk to you about so many things.

351
00:34:34,030 --> 00:34:36,610
I'll be seeing you in a couple of days.

352
00:34:37,900 --> 00:34:40,160
I'm so glad.

353
00:34:40,240 --> 00:34:41,950
Me too.

354
00:34:43,200 --> 00:34:44,700
Bye.

355
00:36:28,270 --> 00:36:31,890
Hello?

356
00:36:36,440 --> 00:36:41,400
You got the day off? 

357
00:36:50,160 --> 00:36:55,710
Are you sick? 

358
00:36:59,590 --> 00:37:06,260
Guess you heard about Elton. 

359
00:37:06,340 --> 00:37:07,350
Okay, I got your point.

360
00:37:07,350 --> 00:37:10,760
I hope you didn't strain yourself getting in here before I hit the back door.

361
00:37:17,900 --> 00:37:20,650
I have to go home.

362
00:37:20,730 --> 00:37:22,690
My father's sick.

363
00:37:29,160 --> 00:37:31,620
 I'll be gone for two or three weeks.

364
00:37:31,700 --> 00:37:35,410
 You'll be gone, period.

365
00:37:51,390 --> 00:37:57,390
 I'll try and call you from up there.

366
00:38:05,740 --> 00:38:09,280
 Come on, Dipesto.

367
00:38:09,370 --> 00:38:12,160
I never told you it'd work out to anything.

368
00:38:14,000 --> 00:38:15,700
Did I?

369
00:38:20,420 --> 00:38:23,170
I'll send you some money. That's all I can do.

370
00:38:27,090 --> 00:38:29,970
I'll try and call you from up there.

371
00:38:34,180 --> 00:38:39,190
 Bye, Ray.

372
00:39:24,940 --> 00:39:26,860
You wanna go with me?

373
00:40:39,140 --> 00:40:42,180
-Like it? -I love it.

374
00:40:50,190 --> 00:40:54,400
-What the hell are they doing? -Is that-Is that an accident?

375
00:40:57,410 --> 00:41:02,000
-Who was-Who was driving? -"Who was driving?" You were driving.

376
00:41:02,080 --> 00:41:04,410
Hey, what the hell's going on?

377
00:41:04,500 --> 00:41:05,830
Rotate, mack!

378
00:41:08,090 --> 00:41:10,380
Look at my car. Look at my car.

379
00:41:10,460 --> 00:41:12,930
I just bought it brand-new from a used car lot, 

380
00:41:12,930 --> 00:41:14,260
and the steering goes to pot on me.

381
00:41:14,340 --> 00:41:16,590
-You're lucky nobody was hurt. -Can you give us a lift?

382
00:41:16,680 --> 00:41:18,180
Come on, Terry. We got a ride.

383
00:41:18,260 --> 00:41:19,970
You're gonna give those people a lift?

384
00:41:20,060 --> 00:41:22,430
-Well, I can't just leave 'em here. -I'd like to go back...

385
00:41:22,520 --> 00:41:25,640
and punch the son of a bitch in the used car lot out.

386
00:41:25,730 --> 00:41:28,480
Jesus! What a rude person.

387
00:41:31,820 --> 00:41:34,950
-What's your name? -Palm Apodaca.

388
00:41:36,780 --> 00:41:39,580
-What's your name? -Terry Grouse.

389
00:41:41,290 --> 00:41:43,080
What?

390
00:41:43,160 --> 00:41:45,370
How far are you going to?

391
00:41:45,460 --> 00:41:46,960
Washington.

392
00:41:48,040 --> 00:41:51,590
We'll get off in Washington. We'll hook a ride.

393
00:41:51,670 --> 00:41:53,550
Where are you going?

394
00:41:53,630 --> 00:41:55,420
Alaska.

395
00:41:55,510 --> 00:41:58,640
Alaska? What, are you on vacation?

396
00:41:58,720 --> 00:42:01,850
She wants to live there because it's cleaner.

397
00:42:01,930 --> 00:42:04,470
Cleaner? Cleaner than what?

398
00:42:06,100 --> 00:42:08,620
You don't have to tell everybody about it. 

399
00:42:08,620 --> 00:42:11,730
Pretty soon they'll all go, and it won't be so clean.

400
00:42:11,820 --> 00:42:14,230
What makes you think it's cleaner?

401
00:42:14,320 --> 00:42:18,410
I saw a picture of it. Alaska's very clean.

402
00:42:18,490 --> 00:42:21,450
It appeared to look very white to me.

403
00:42:21,530 --> 00:42:23,790
Don't you think?

404
00:42:23,870 --> 00:42:26,830
Yep. But that was before the big thaw.

405
00:42:28,000 --> 00:42:29,500
Before the what?

406
00:42:47,140 --> 00:42:50,690
I had to leave this place because I got depressed seeing all the crap.

407
00:42:50,770 --> 00:42:53,770
And the thing is, they're making more crap, you know.

408
00:42:53,860 --> 00:42:56,690
They got so many stores and stuff and junk full of crap.

409
00:42:56,780 --> 00:42:59,400
-I can't believe it. -Who?

410
00:42:59,490 --> 00:43:02,120
Who? Man, that's who.

411
00:43:03,620 --> 00:43:05,870
Pretty soon there won't be any room for man.

412
00:43:07,540 --> 00:43:11,080
They're selling more crap that people go and buy than you can imagine.

413
00:43:11,170 --> 00:43:12,750
Crap.

414
00:43:14,210 --> 00:43:16,170
I believe everybody should have a big hole 

415
00:43:16,170 --> 00:43:18,090
where they throw the stuff in and burn it.

416
00:43:18,170 --> 00:43:21,300
They'd never find a hole big enough. Never.

417
00:43:21,390 --> 00:43:23,100
Now, take me now. Look at me.

418
00:43:23,180 --> 00:43:27,020
When I was just one person, before I was with Bobby 

419
00:43:27,100 --> 00:43:30,390
I was collecting onto me more garbage every day...

420
00:43:30,480 --> 00:43:33,810
till I was getting to thinkin' that I should get a disposal.

421
00:43:33,900 --> 00:43:35,400
Disposal?

422
00:43:35,480 --> 00:43:38,940
What's that but more crap? I've never seen such crap.

423
00:43:39,030 --> 00:43:40,950
-Mass production is what does it. -What do you mean, mass?

424
00:43:41,030 --> 00:43:43,570
I have to come out and tell you the truth. You're not that clean either.

425
00:43:43,660 --> 00:43:46,080
Wait a minute. I'm not that neat maybe, but I am clean.

426
00:43:46,160 --> 00:43:47,790
Well, you're not that bad.

427
00:43:47,870 --> 00:43:50,000
But some people.

428
00:43:50,080 --> 00:43:53,330
People's homes just filth. I've been in people's homes

429
00:43:53,420 --> 00:43:56,880
In my personal observation, I think that more people are neat than are clean.

430
00:43:56,960 --> 00:44:02,260
My personal thing, I don't see that. I'm seeing more filth. A lot of filth.

431
00:44:02,340 --> 00:44:04,640
What they need to do every day-No, once in a while 

432
00:44:04,720 --> 00:44:08,180
is do a cockroach thing, you know, where they spray the homes.

433
00:44:08,270 --> 00:44:10,850
Can you imagine if their doors were painted a pretty color, 

434
00:44:10,860 --> 00:44:12,020
and they had a pot outside?

435
00:44:12,100 --> 00:44:14,350
-Yeah, could be adorable. -And they picked up.

436
00:44:14,440 --> 00:44:19,190
Then it wouldn't be filthy with Coke bottles and whiskey and, uh 

437
00:44:19,280 --> 00:44:21,240
Those signs everywhere-they should be erased!

438
00:44:21,320 --> 00:44:24,110
All those signs selling you crap and more crap and more crap.

439
00:44:24,200 --> 00:44:28,200
 I don't know. I don't know. I don't even want to talk about it.

440
00:44:28,290 --> 00:44:31,040
-Well -It's just filthy! People are filthy.

441
00:44:31,120 --> 00:44:33,870
I think that's the biggest thing that's wrong with people.

442
00:44:33,960 --> 00:44:36,130
I think they wouldn't be as violent if they were clean...

443
00:44:36,210 --> 00:44:38,210
because then they wouldn't have anybody to pick on.

444
00:44:38,300 --> 00:44:40,710
Dirt.

445
00:44:40,800 --> 00:44:42,880
Not dirt. See, dirt isn't bad.

446
00:44:42,970 --> 00:44:45,260
It's filth. Filth is bad.

447
00:44:45,350 --> 00:44:48,180
That's what starts maggots and riots.

448
00:44:48,260 --> 00:44:52,140
Hey, follow that truck. They know the best places to stop.

449
00:44:52,230 --> 00:44:54,640
That's an old maid's tale.

450
00:44:54,730 --> 00:44:56,520
Bullshit!

451
00:44:56,610 --> 00:44:59,780
Truck drivers are the only ones that know the best places to stop on the road.

452
00:44:59,860 --> 00:45:01,070
Salesmen and cops are the ones. 

453
00:45:01,070 --> 00:45:03,150
If you'd ever waitressed, honey, you'd know that.

454
00:45:03,240 --> 00:45:05,880
Don't call me honey, mack. 

455
00:45:05,880 --> 00:45:08,200
Don't call me mack, honey.

456
00:45:09,830 --> 00:45:12,750
I wouldn't be a waitress. They're nasty and full of crap.

457
00:45:12,830 --> 00:45:15,500
You just hold on to your tongue!

458
00:45:15,580 --> 00:45:17,250
Hold on to this.

459
00:45:17,340 --> 00:45:20,210
If you think that you can talk to me like that 

460
00:45:20,300 --> 00:45:22,630
Shut up! All of ya.

461
00:45:27,680 --> 00:45:32,470
I'd like a, uh, plain omelet, no potatoes, tomatoes instead...

462
00:45:32,560 --> 00:45:34,770
a cup of coffee and wheat toast.

463
00:45:34,850 --> 00:45:36,350
No substitutions.

464
00:45:36,440 --> 00:45:39,520
What do you mean? You don't have any tomatoes?

465
00:45:39,610 --> 00:45:41,270
Only what's on the menu.

466
00:45:41,360 --> 00:45:42,610
You can have a number two, 

467
00:45:42,610 --> 00:45:44,610
a plain omelet. It comes with cottage fries and rolls.

468
00:45:45,700 --> 00:45:48,200
I know what it comes with, but it's not what I want.

469
00:45:48,280 --> 00:45:50,870
-Well, I'll come back when you make up your mind. -Wait a minute.

470
00:45:50,950 --> 00:45:54,120
I have made up my mind. I'd like a plain omelet.

471
00:45:54,210 --> 00:45:56,120
No potatoes on the plate.

472
00:45:56,210 --> 00:45:59,290
A cup of coffee and a side order of wheat toast.

473
00:45:59,380 --> 00:46:01,550
I'm sorry, we don't have any side orders of toast.

474
00:46:01,630 --> 00:46:04,090
I'll give you an English muffin or a coffee roll.

475
00:46:04,170 --> 00:46:06,880
What do you mean you don't make side orders of toast?

476
00:46:06,970 --> 00:46:09,590
You make sandwiches, don't you?

477
00:46:09,680 --> 00:46:12,140
-Would you like to talk to the manager? -Hey, mack!

478
00:46:12,220 --> 00:46:14,180
Shut up.

479
00:46:14,270 --> 00:46:17,480
You've got bread and a toaster of some kind?

480
00:46:17,560 --> 00:46:19,100
I don't make the rules.

481
00:46:19,190 --> 00:46:22,190
Okay, I'll make it as easy for you as I can.

482
00:46:22,280 --> 00:46:24,150
I'd like an omelet, plain...

483
00:46:24,240 --> 00:46:27,320
and a chicken salad sandwich on wheat toast.

484
00:46:27,410 --> 00:46:31,320
No mayonnaise, no butter, no lettuce, and a cup of coffee.

485
00:46:31,410 --> 00:46:33,870
A number two-chicken sal san...

486
00:46:33,950 --> 00:46:36,620
hold the butter, the lettuce and the mayonnaise.

487
00:46:36,710 --> 00:46:39,580
And a cup of coffee. Anything else?

488
00:46:39,670 --> 00:46:43,590
Yeah. Now all you have to do is hold the chicken, bring me the toast...

489
00:46:43,670 --> 00:46:45,230
give me a check for 

490
00:46:45,230 --> 00:46:47,590
the chicken salad sandwich, and you haven't broken any rules.

491
00:46:47,680 --> 00:46:49,930
You want me to hold the chicken, huh?

492
00:46:50,010 --> 00:46:52,640
I want you to hold it between your knees.

493
00:46:54,350 --> 00:46:56,180
You see that sign, sir?

494
00:46:56,270 --> 00:46:57,740
Yes, you all have to leave. 

495
00:46:57,740 --> 00:47:01,440
I'm not taking any more of your smartness and sarcasm!

496
00:47:01,520 --> 00:47:05,280
 You see this sign?

497
00:47:05,360 --> 00:47:08,150
Fantastic that you could figure that all out and lie that down on her...

498
00:47:08,240 --> 00:47:10,610
so you could come up with a way to get your toast.

499
00:47:10,700 --> 00:47:13,530
-Fantastic! -Yeah? Well, I didn't get it, did I?

500
00:47:13,620 --> 00:47:15,870
No. But it was very clever.

501
00:47:15,950 --> 00:47:17,910
I would have just punched her out.

502
00:47:22,590 --> 00:47:25,050
People.

503
00:47:25,130 --> 00:47:27,420
Animals are not like that. Mm-mmm.

504
00:47:28,590 --> 00:47:31,890
They're always cleaning themselves. Did you ever see, um...

505
00:47:31,970 --> 00:47:34,350
pigeons?

506
00:47:35,430 --> 00:47:37,720
Well, he's always picking on himself and his friends.

507
00:47:37,810 --> 00:47:40,190
They're always picking bugs out of their hair all the time.

508
00:47:40,270 --> 00:47:42,150
Monkeys too.

509
00:47:42,230 --> 00:47:45,020
Except they do something out in the open that I don't go for.

510
00:47:49,780 --> 00:47:53,870
You know, I read where they invented this car that runs on, um 

511
00:47:54,870 --> 00:47:56,370
that runs on, um 

512
00:47:56,450 --> 00:47:59,790
When you boil water?

513
00:47:59,870 --> 00:48:02,040
-Steam. -Right, steam.

514
00:48:02,120 --> 00:48:04,710
A car that you could ride around in and not cause a stink.

515
00:48:04,790 --> 00:48:07,590
But do you know they will not even let us have it?

516
00:48:07,670 --> 00:48:09,550
Can you believe it?

517
00:48:09,630 --> 00:48:12,090
Why? Man!

518
00:48:12,180 --> 00:48:14,260
He likes to create a stink.

519
00:48:14,350 --> 00:48:16,810
I mean, I've seen filth that you wouldn't believe.

520
00:48:16,890 --> 00:48:19,060
What a stink.

521
00:48:20,100 --> 00:48:22,020
I don't even want to talk about it.

522
00:49:19,990 --> 00:49:23,000
You depressed about your daddy, hon?

523
00:49:23,080 --> 00:49:24,080
No.

524
00:49:25,670 --> 00:49:28,250
I imagine it's me then, isn't it?

525
00:49:29,250 --> 00:49:30,750
Is what you?

526
00:49:31,760 --> 00:49:33,510
Are you depressed I come along?

527
00:49:36,340 --> 00:49:38,680
Who says I'm depressed?

528
00:49:39,850 --> 00:49:42,350
Is that a happy face I see?

529
00:49:46,600 --> 00:49:50,110
'Cause if it is, I'll just catch a Greyhound back.

530
00:49:52,190 --> 00:49:55,700
Oh, you're not gonna kill yourself this time. I wish I'd known.

531
00:50:14,220 --> 00:50:17,130
I don't know if I'm gonna be able to get to sleep.

532
00:50:18,220 --> 00:50:20,220
Hint, hint.

533
00:50:25,890 --> 00:50:29,230
Guess I'll have to count the sheep.

534
00:50:29,310 --> 00:50:32,400
One, two...

535
00:50:32,480 --> 00:50:35,860
three, four...

536
00:50:35,950 --> 00:50:39,910
five, six...

537
00:50:39,990 --> 00:50:41,490
seven 

538
00:50:43,410 --> 00:50:47,410
Look at this ol' cold shoulder.

539
00:50:49,170 --> 00:50:52,090
What am I going to do about it?

540
00:50:58,630 --> 00:51:02,760
You know, if you wouldn't open your mouth, everything would be just fine.

541
00:51:06,930 --> 00:51:09,100
 Tick-a-lock!

542
00:51:19,610 --> 00:51:21,780
Why can't I come out with you to your family's house?

543
00:51:21,870 --> 00:51:23,530
Now you give me one good reason.

544
00:51:23,620 --> 00:51:25,740
I have to see what's going on first.

545
00:51:25,830 --> 00:51:27,870
My father's sick. You understand?

546
00:51:27,960 --> 00:51:30,790
They wouldn't be prepared for my bringing anyone.

547
00:51:30,880 --> 00:51:33,460
So how long do I have to sit and twiddle my thumbs in that place?

548
00:51:33,540 --> 00:51:36,090
Look, Ray, if you can't do what I'm asking you...

549
00:51:36,170 --> 00:51:39,760
why don't you just take the money and go on back south with it?

550
00:51:39,840 --> 00:51:41,970
Oh, now, hon, don't talk like that.

551
00:51:42,050 --> 00:51:45,890
Look, will you try and understand? This is not something that I want to do.

552
00:51:45,970 --> 00:51:48,890
Jesus Christ! You ought to know me well enough for that.

553
00:51:49,890 --> 00:51:51,390
All right, hon.

554
00:51:52,810 --> 00:51:55,900
It'll be all right. I mean, there's stuff for me to do.

555
00:51:55,980 --> 00:51:58,820
They got magazines in there and TV, right?

556
00:51:58,900 --> 00:52:02,820
Yeah. I'll try and call you in a couple of days.

557
00:52:04,530 --> 00:52:06,030
All right.

558
00:52:07,040 --> 00:52:09,040
Bye.

559
00:55:48,470 --> 00:55:51,220
He doesn't even know who the hell I am.

560
00:56:12,610 --> 00:56:13,950
How long has it been since... 

561
00:56:13,950 --> 00:56:14,990
Remember Mother used to say, "Bobby"...

562
00:56:15,080 --> 00:56:16,990
-Excuse me. -Excuse me.

563
00:56:17,080 --> 00:56:19,080
-Go ahead. -Excuse me.

564
00:56:19,160 --> 00:56:21,460
I was just going to ask Robert how long it 

565
00:56:21,460 --> 00:56:23,000
had been since he's been away from here.

566
00:56:23,080 --> 00:56:25,040
Three years.

567
00:56:25,130 --> 00:56:27,420
No, no, no. It's more like two years, isn't it? Hmm?

568
00:56:27,500 --> 00:56:29,420
Oh, it's been more than that, Carl.

569
00:56:29,510 --> 00:56:33,180
Tita, you have no sense of timing away from the piano, dear.

570
00:56:33,260 --> 00:56:35,090
I don't think that's true.

571
00:56:35,180 --> 00:56:36,600
It's true.

572
00:56:36,680 --> 00:56:38,430
What have you been doing since then?

573
00:56:38,520 --> 00:56:42,560
Odd jobs of work here and there. Nothing too interesting.

574
00:56:42,640 --> 00:56:44,850
You no longer play at all?

575
00:56:44,940 --> 00:56:46,860
You know, Robert, before my misfortune 

576
00:56:46,940 --> 00:56:49,610
I'm not sure you're aware of my accident, Robert. Mm-hmm?

577
00:56:49,690 --> 00:56:51,690
Yeah. Tita was telling me about it.

578
00:56:51,780 --> 00:56:55,030
Well, you know, it's very difficult for me to turn my neck.

579
00:56:55,120 --> 00:56:57,870
This way especially. If I-For instance, if I want to look at Catherine...

580
00:56:57,950 --> 00:57:00,580
I have to shift the whole base of my body around this way.

581
00:57:00,660 --> 00:57:02,910
I was real sorry to hear about it, Carl.

582
00:57:03,000 --> 00:57:06,540
-Hmm? -I said I was real sorry to hear about it.

583
00:57:06,630 --> 00:57:08,880
Anyway, as I was saying

584
00:57:08,960 --> 00:57:11,380
Catherine, what was I saying? Hmm?

585
00:57:12,630 --> 00:57:14,550
You were saying something...

586
00:57:14,640 --> 00:57:17,800
about something that happened around the time of the accident.

587
00:57:17,890 --> 00:57:19,810
Oh! Yes. Just before the accident...

588
00:57:19,890 --> 00:57:22,980
just after I'd come off tour with the Betanthaller Quartet...

589
00:57:23,060 --> 00:57:25,810
Father and Herbert and I had a summit conference concerning you, mm-hmm.

590
00:57:25,900 --> 00:57:27,560
Oh, my. A summit conference.

591
00:57:27,650 --> 00:57:30,150
Where was I, I wonder? Polishing silver behind the coal bin?

592
00:57:30,230 --> 00:57:33,320
Well, I don't know where you were, penis envy.

593
00:57:33,400 --> 00:57:34,990
I hope I didn't hear that.

594
00:57:35,070 --> 00:57:39,330
Nevertheless, they wanted to hire a detective to ferret you out...

595
00:57:39,410 --> 00:57:42,410
and I talked them out of it, because I felt that whatever you were doing...

596
00:57:42,500 --> 00:57:43,970
you had a perfect right to do, 

597
00:57:43,970 --> 00:57:46,920
no matter how nonsensical your adventures might be.

598
00:57:47,000 --> 00:57:50,340
-It was as simple as that, Robert. -Well, I really appreciate it, Carl.

599
00:57:50,420 --> 00:57:54,670
I don't think you ought to imply that Daddy was wrong in front of Daddy.

600
00:57:54,760 --> 00:57:56,930
Don't force him that way, Spicer.

601
00:57:58,350 --> 00:58:00,260
How long have you been here?

602
00:58:00,350 --> 00:58:02,720
Um, only two months.

603
00:58:04,180 --> 00:58:08,480
Well, satiety is my father and mother. Hmm?

604
00:58:09,940 --> 00:58:11,940
Carl? 

605
00:58:12,030 --> 00:58:15,530
If you're finished, I think I'd like to go do some work.

606
00:58:15,610 --> 00:58:17,200
Oh, certainly, dear.

607
00:58:17,280 --> 00:58:19,530
Excuse me. See you later.

608
00:58:20,950 --> 00:58:22,870
I hope you feel right at home, Robert.

609
00:58:22,950 --> 00:58:24,620
I feel fine.

610
00:58:57,240 --> 00:58:59,780
He has ways of communicating, Robert.

611
00:58:59,870 --> 00:59:03,580
I can tell when he's expressing approval or disapproval...

612
00:59:03,660 --> 00:59:05,370
just from his eyes.

613
00:59:05,450 --> 00:59:08,920
Yeah. Some range.

614
00:59:10,080 --> 00:59:14,340
I can't take much more of seeing him sitting there like a stone.

615
00:59:14,420 --> 00:59:17,590
-It's not that bad. -Yes, it is.

616
00:59:17,670 --> 00:59:19,930
Will you stay a while?

617
00:59:25,060 --> 00:59:27,020
I don't know.

618
00:59:59,380 --> 01:00:01,550
Now, breathe!

619
01:00:01,640 --> 01:00:04,300
All right! 

620
01:00:06,270 --> 01:00:08,220
Now, once more. Once more.

621
01:00:22,240 --> 01:00:24,240
-Hello. -Hi.

622
01:00:24,320 --> 01:00:26,450
Been lookin' all over for you.

623
01:00:26,540 --> 01:00:28,450
You have? I went riding.

624
01:00:28,540 --> 01:00:29,660
-Riding? -Mm-hmm.

625
01:00:29,750 --> 01:00:31,660
That's dangerous, you know.

626
01:00:31,750 --> 01:00:33,580
-Riding? -Mm-hmm.

627
01:00:33,670 --> 01:00:37,840
You play the piano all day and then jump on a horse, you could get cramps.

628
01:00:37,920 --> 01:00:41,170
Well, I like to ride.

629
01:00:41,260 --> 01:00:43,930
Rain or shine, I do it any chance I can get.

630
01:00:44,010 --> 01:00:46,100
-It's very invigorating. -Is it?

631
01:00:46,180 --> 01:00:47,680
Yes.

632
01:00:47,760 --> 01:00:51,600
Well, I don't like to get too invigorated myself.

633
01:00:51,690 --> 01:00:53,390
-You don't? -Mm-mmm.

634
01:00:53,480 --> 01:00:55,860
What else do you do?

635
01:00:55,940 --> 01:00:58,860
Well, there's fishing, boating.

636
01:00:58,940 --> 01:01:02,150
There's concerts on the mainland.

637
01:01:03,160 --> 01:01:06,200
I feel silly telling you this. This is really your home.

638
01:01:06,280 --> 01:01:08,620
You probably know better than I what there is to do.

639
01:01:08,700 --> 01:01:09,790
Nothing.

640
01:01:10,790 --> 01:01:13,000
Nothing?

641
01:01:13,080 --> 01:01:14,870
Nothing.

642
01:01:14,960 --> 01:01:17,960
Well, it must be very boring for you here.

643
01:01:18,050 --> 01:01:20,630
That's right.

644
01:01:20,710 --> 01:01:23,130
I find that hard to comprehend.

645
01:01:23,220 --> 01:01:26,640
I don't think I've ever been bored. Excuse me.

646
01:01:32,810 --> 01:01:34,730
What are you doing right now?

647
01:01:34,810 --> 01:01:39,150
Right now I plan to take a hot tub and soak myself.

648
01:01:39,230 --> 01:01:41,320
And then after that?

649
01:01:41,400 --> 01:01:46,160
After that, mmm, I plan to read some music and rest for a while.

650
01:01:46,240 --> 01:01:48,160
Tomorrow then?

651
01:01:49,240 --> 01:01:52,330
Tomorrow? Tomorrow's a full practice day.

652
01:01:52,410 --> 01:01:55,160
But the day after tomorrow I will be free.

653
01:01:55,250 --> 01:01:58,330
Carl has hydrotherapy on Tuesdays.

654
01:01:58,420 --> 01:02:01,420
-The day after tomorrow? -Will you be free?

655
01:02:01,510 --> 01:02:03,840
Yeah, I'll probably be free.

656
01:02:26,030 --> 01:02:28,950
One thing I find very difficult to imagine...

657
01:02:30,200 --> 01:02:33,450
is how one could have this incredible background in music...

658
01:02:33,540 --> 01:02:36,540
and then just walk away from it without giving it a second thought at all.

659
01:02:36,620 --> 01:02:38,290
I gave it a second thought.

660
01:02:41,210 --> 01:02:45,300
I mean, how could you no longer play at all? I think that's very strange.

661
01:02:45,380 --> 01:02:47,510
I've played a little bit here and there.

662
01:02:47,590 --> 01:02:51,800
As a matter of fact, once I was a... rehearsal pianist.

663
01:02:51,890 --> 01:02:53,560
For a ballet? An opera?

664
01:02:53,640 --> 01:02:56,430
Las Vegas musical revue.

665
01:02:56,520 --> 01:02:59,560
-You don't call that music. -Oh, yes, I do.

666
01:02:59,650 --> 01:03:01,560
It's music, you know?

667
01:03:27,590 --> 01:03:31,430
If you're not feeling good

668
01:03:41,770 --> 01:03:44,190
More gingerbread?

669
01:03:44,270 --> 01:03:45,770
No, thank you.

670
01:03:49,280 --> 01:03:51,240
Applesauce?

671
01:04:58,470 --> 01:05:01,520
You know what I suggest, Ray.

672
01:05:01,600 --> 01:05:03,520
Yeah. Well, that's-that's what I suggest...

673
01:05:03,600 --> 01:05:06,480
because I don't know how long it's gonna be.

674
01:05:09,860 --> 01:05:11,860
I have to go now.

675
01:05:13,950 --> 01:05:16,280
I have to get off now, Ray.

676
01:05:24,960 --> 01:05:28,590
Uh, I'll try and call you in a couple of days.

677
01:05:28,670 --> 01:05:31,050
If you're gone, you're gone.

678
01:05:31,130 --> 01:05:32,630
Bye.

679
01:05:35,390 --> 01:05:39,180
Robert, shh! My playing put Father to sleep.

680
01:05:39,260 --> 01:05:41,270
Would you help me with this, please?

681
01:05:43,480 --> 01:05:45,440
That's it. Ooh!

682
01:05:51,230 --> 01:05:53,990
 You sure you should be playing, Carl?

683
01:05:54,070 --> 01:05:57,740
What do you mean? I'm in superb shape-except for my neck. Hmm?

684
01:05:57,820 --> 01:06:00,120
Well, there's something funny about the way you move.

685
01:06:02,160 --> 01:06:04,790
I'm not aware of-What do you mean?

686
01:06:04,870 --> 01:06:06,040
2-18.

687
01:06:09,170 --> 01:06:12,760
I'd hate to see you walk across a concert stage like that.

688
01:06:12,840 --> 01:06:16,130
2-19.

689
01:06:18,600 --> 01:06:22,470
I'd get somebody to coach you on how to walk if I was you, Carl.

690
01:06:22,560 --> 01:06:24,640
I think it's a substantial problem.

691
01:06:25,850 --> 01:06:27,770
Damn it.

692
01:06:29,730 --> 01:06:31,650
Look at that.

693
01:06:31,730 --> 01:06:34,780
-Why are you being so mean? -Mean? I'm not being mean.

694
01:06:34,860 --> 01:06:37,780
He does walk funny. Don't you see that?

695
01:06:37,860 --> 01:06:41,080
He's walking around 

696
01:06:41,160 --> 01:06:43,910
I don't think I'd notice. I'm so used to Carl.

697
01:06:44,000 --> 01:06:45,500
Yeah, well 

698
01:06:45,580 --> 01:06:50,500
Bobby, do you think Spicer is attractive?

699
01:06:53,960 --> 01:06:56,470
I think he's got a terrific personality.

700
01:06:56,550 --> 01:06:59,130
Spicer was formerly a sailor.

701
01:06:59,220 --> 01:07:01,720
Look.  Don't you see that? Look at that.

702
01:07:01,810 --> 01:07:03,810
The guy's 

703
01:07:03,890 --> 01:07:06,230
Sailors are sadistic, I feel.

704
01:07:06,310 --> 01:07:08,980
You see? There's nothing particularly wrong with my walk, hmm?

705
01:07:09,060 --> 01:07:12,480
-Now, where were we? -At game, Carl.

706
01:07:20,990 --> 01:07:23,620
Well, that's three games to "Z," Carl.

707
01:07:24,620 --> 01:07:26,540
Well, what do you say about a rematch, Robert? Hmm?

708
01:07:26,620 --> 01:07:30,500
I thought you were going to the mainland today. You'll miss the ferry.

709
01:07:30,580 --> 01:07:33,000
Just when I was hitting my stride.

710
01:07:33,090 --> 01:07:35,090
Say good-bye to Catherine for me, will you?

711
01:07:37,420 --> 01:07:39,510
Can I play now?

712
01:07:39,590 --> 01:07:43,010
Tell her I'll be back sometime tomorrow probably, will you?

713
01:07:43,100 --> 01:07:45,680
Where is she, anyway?

714
01:07:45,770 --> 01:07:47,350
Who? Oh.

715
01:07:47,430 --> 01:07:49,440
Shopping in the village.

716
01:07:49,520 --> 01:07:51,190
My turn.

717
01:07:51,270 --> 01:07:53,190
Yeah, why don't you and Spicer play.

718
01:07:59,280 --> 01:08:00,780
Spicer.

719
01:08:14,880 --> 01:08:16,800
Hi.

720
01:08:16,880 --> 01:08:18,050
Hello.

721
01:08:20,300 --> 01:08:22,550
What's the matter?

722
01:08:22,640 --> 01:08:23,800
Nothing.

723
01:08:25,390 --> 01:08:27,350
Robert?

724
01:08:30,480 --> 01:08:32,390
Would you do something for me?

725
01:08:33,900 --> 01:08:36,060
Would you play for me?

726
01:08:36,150 --> 01:08:39,030
Catherine, your game!

727
01:08:46,490 --> 01:08:48,410
Catherine?

728
01:08:50,660 --> 01:08:51,790
Will you?

729
01:11:24,900 --> 01:11:26,900
That was beautiful, Robert. I'm surprised.

730
01:11:27,990 --> 01:11:29,110
Thank you.

731
01:11:29,200 --> 01:11:31,410
I was really very moved by 

732
01:11:33,870 --> 01:11:35,080
What's wrong?

733
01:11:35,160 --> 01:11:37,910
Nothing. It's just, um 

734
01:11:38,000 --> 01:11:41,420
I picked the easiest piece that I could think of...

735
01:11:41,500 --> 01:11:43,770
and I first played it when I was eight years old, 

736
01:11:43,770 --> 01:11:45,000
and I played it better then.

737
01:11:45,090 --> 01:11:48,970
Can't you understand it was the feeling I was affected by?

738
01:11:49,050 --> 01:11:50,840
I didn't have any.

739
01:11:50,930 --> 01:11:53,350
-You had no inner feeling? -None.

740
01:11:55,010 --> 01:11:57,520
Well, then, I must have been supplying it.

741
01:11:57,600 --> 01:12:01,690
Maybe if you'd supply a little more, it might rub off on me. Who knows?

742
01:12:02,940 --> 01:12:04,980
I doubt it.

743
01:12:05,070 --> 01:12:07,610
Oh, I could get interested.

744
01:12:07,690 --> 01:12:09,860
Well, I couldn't.

745
01:12:24,790 --> 01:12:28,710
What does it have to be with you? Grim and serious?

746
01:12:29,720 --> 01:12:32,300
Look, you played...

747
01:12:32,390 --> 01:12:35,300
I honestly responded...

748
01:12:35,390 --> 01:12:39,020
and you made me feel embarrassed for having responded to you.

749
01:12:41,940 --> 01:12:44,310
-It wasn't necessary. -Yeah, it was.

750
01:12:44,400 --> 01:12:47,270
I faked a little Chopin, you faked a big response.

751
01:12:47,360 --> 01:12:49,280
I don't think that's accurate.

752
01:12:49,360 --> 01:12:50,020
Up till now, 

753
01:12:50,020 --> 01:12:53,740
all I've been getting from you is meaningful looks at the dinner table...

754
01:12:53,820 --> 01:12:57,160
and a lot of vague suggestions about the day after tomorrow.

755
01:12:57,240 --> 01:12:59,660
I am not conscious of having given you any particular looks.

756
01:12:59,750 --> 01:13:03,330
And as for the day after tomorrow, this is the day after tomorrow.

757
01:13:03,420 --> 01:13:06,080
And I am, unfortunately, seeing you.

758
01:13:06,170 --> 01:13:08,960
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'd like to take a bath.

759
01:13:09,050 --> 01:13:11,510
-What the hell do you want anyway? -I'm getting some bath oil.

760
01:13:11,590 --> 01:13:12,840
Some bath oil? 

761
01:13:12,930 --> 01:13:15,650
How about some avocado or some of this? 

762
01:13:15,650 --> 01:13:16,430
Or some of this jasmine? How about this?

763
01:13:16,510 --> 01:13:18,510
-How about any -What are you doing?

764
01:13:18,600 --> 01:13:21,600
What are you doing screwing around with all this crap?

765
01:13:24,270 --> 01:13:27,860
I do not find your language very charming.

766
01:13:27,940 --> 01:13:30,360
It isn't. It's direct.

767
01:13:30,440 --> 01:13:34,360
I'd like you to leave so that I can take a bath.

768
01:13:34,450 --> 01:13:36,360
Is that direct?

769
01:13:42,830 --> 01:13:45,040
Serious?

770
01:13:45,120 --> 01:13:47,170
Is that what's important to you? Serious?

771
01:13:47,250 --> 01:13:48,750
Yes, that's what's important to me.

772
01:13:48,840 --> 01:13:50,960
-Okay, let's be serious. Sit down. -No, don't do that.

773
01:13:51,050 --> 01:13:53,050
Shut up!

774
01:13:53,130 --> 01:13:55,130
No inner feeling.

775
01:14:23,750 --> 01:14:25,830
I told him the truth finally.

776
01:14:27,330 --> 01:14:30,460
He was my husband, and I loved him very much.

777
01:14:30,550 --> 01:14:32,630
But my God.

778
01:14:32,710 --> 01:14:35,800
It wasn't working any better the second time than it did the first.

779
01:14:35,880 --> 01:14:38,260
He was a cellist.

780
01:14:38,340 --> 01:14:40,180
And there was I...

781
01:14:40,260 --> 01:14:43,270
no longer 17, looking up at him.

782
01:14:43,350 --> 01:14:45,270
And I said to him...

783
01:14:45,350 --> 01:14:48,940
"Joseph, you're full of beans," and I left him.

784
01:14:49,020 --> 01:14:51,270
Is that what you said to him?

785
01:14:51,360 --> 01:14:54,110
Something like that.

786
01:14:54,190 --> 01:14:57,530
As a matter of fact, Joseph introduced me to Carl right around then.

787
01:14:59,450 --> 01:15:00,870
How are you?

788
01:15:01,870 --> 01:15:03,490
I'm incredible.

789
01:15:06,870 --> 01:15:10,130
Carl restored me. He really did.

790
01:15:10,210 --> 01:15:14,170
He's much more substantial than you give him credit for being.

791
01:15:16,220 --> 01:15:19,680
Do you think you could discreetly move across the hall now?

792
01:15:20,760 --> 01:15:24,890
Yes, I think I could discreetly move across the hall now.

793
01:15:36,150 --> 01:15:38,280
Robert?

794
01:15:40,240 --> 01:15:44,870
I have free time tomorrow morning before Carl gets back-if you'd like.

795
01:15:44,950 --> 01:15:47,870
Of course I'd like it.

796
01:15:52,540 --> 01:15:56,250
Bananas, bananas!

797
01:16:13,810 --> 01:16:18,150
You certainly do have a beautiful piece of real estate out here, Mr. Dupea.

798
01:16:20,910 --> 01:16:23,240
Can he hear me?

799
01:16:23,320 --> 01:16:24,870
He's not hard of hearing.

800
01:16:24,950 --> 01:16:28,200
Oh. Well, that's a blessing at least.

801
01:16:28,290 --> 01:16:33,540
This certainly is an improvement on the motel and the coffee shop.

802
01:16:33,630 --> 01:16:36,130
How could you ever have left such a beautiful place, Bobby?

803
01:16:36,210 --> 01:16:38,760
I don't know.

804
01:16:38,840 --> 01:16:42,050
You mean you've been staying in a motel all this time?

805
01:16:42,130 --> 01:16:46,050
For two whole weeks, and there wasn't hardly nobody there to talk to but me.

806
01:16:46,140 --> 01:16:49,470
But I don't understand. Why did you stay at the motel?

807
01:16:49,560 --> 01:16:51,290
There's plenty of room here. 

808
01:16:51,290 --> 01:16:52,060
Well, I was goin' to...

809
01:16:52,140 --> 01:16:56,730
but Bobby had to kinda come up here, he said, and feel it up here first.

810
01:16:56,820 --> 01:17:00,070
But then it took so long, I run flat out of money.

811
01:17:00,150 --> 01:17:02,780
You know, you didn't leave me any number or anything, honey.

812
01:17:04,320 --> 01:17:08,580
And I had to, you know, get in a taxi and come on out here...

813
01:17:08,660 --> 01:17:11,410
in the hopes that I would not be intrudin' myself.

814
01:17:11,500 --> 01:17:14,170
Oh, no, not at all, dear.

815
01:17:14,250 --> 01:17:16,170
You're perfectly welcome to stay here.

816
01:17:16,250 --> 01:17:18,340
Well, thank you.

817
01:17:19,590 --> 01:17:22,090
That's a very nice thing for you to say.

818
01:17:22,170 --> 01:17:24,010
Not at all.

819
01:17:26,680 --> 01:17:29,350
You certainly do have a beautiful head of hair.

820
01:17:29,430 --> 01:17:31,640
Thank you.

821
01:17:31,730 --> 01:17:34,190
-Is it natural? -Rayette.

822
01:17:34,270 --> 01:17:36,440
What?

823
01:17:36,520 --> 01:17:38,190
Just finish eating.

824
01:17:38,270 --> 01:17:40,190
Oh, am I holdin' up dessert?

825
01:17:40,280 --> 01:17:43,110
No, no, not at all. Take all the time you want.

826
01:17:43,200 --> 01:17:46,410
I do eat slow as a bird.

827
01:17:46,490 --> 01:17:49,450
Whereas Bobby can pack it away like a speed swing.

828
01:17:52,120 --> 01:17:55,000
-Is there any ketchup around? -Oh, for God's sake!

829
01:17:55,080 --> 01:17:57,790
Robert, please, let's not be rude, hmm?

830
01:17:57,880 --> 01:18:01,380
It's okay. He didn't mean anything by that.

831
01:18:01,460 --> 01:18:03,380
I don't, huh?

832
01:18:07,890 --> 01:18:12,640
Bobby's just about the moodiest man I've ever been with.

833
01:19:52,660 --> 01:19:55,240
-Are you all right? -Where are you going?

834
01:19:55,330 --> 01:19:57,790
I'm going to pick up some friends of Carl's and mine.

835
01:19:57,870 --> 01:20:00,330
-I want to talk to you. -I'll be back later.

836
01:20:00,420 --> 01:20:02,580
No, I want to talk to you right now. I want to explain 

837
01:20:02,670 --> 01:20:04,090
 No, it isn't necessary.

838
01:20:04,170 --> 01:20:06,130
-Yes, it is. Yes, it is. -You don't have to do that.

839
01:20:06,210 --> 01:20:07,960
Come on, get moving!

840
01:20:08,050 --> 01:20:10,180
-Will you shut up? -Come on!

841
01:20:10,260 --> 01:20:12,090
Robert, I have to go.

842
01:20:12,180 --> 01:20:14,350
Catherine, will you just wait one minute?

843
01:20:16,350 --> 01:20:20,770
I haven't been being fair to Carl. I have to tell you that.

844
01:20:20,850 --> 01:20:22,940
Why do you have to tell me that?

845
01:20:23,020 --> 01:20:24,860
What? I can't hear you.

846
01:20:26,610 --> 01:20:29,940
I'm sorry everything's been so confusing.

847
01:20:30,030 --> 01:20:32,780
I'll see you later this evening.

848
01:20:38,950 --> 01:20:38,970
But, you see, man is born into the world 

849
01:20:38,970 --> 01:20:39,000
with his existent adversary from the first.

850
01:20:39,000 --> 01:20:41,780
But, you see, man is born into the world 

851
01:20:41,780 --> 01:20:43,880
with his existent adversary from the first.

852
01:20:43,960 --> 01:20:47,800
It is his historic, mythic inheritance. So, is this startling?

853
01:20:47,880 --> 01:20:51,970
Aggression is prehistoric. An organism behaves according to its nature.

854
01:20:52,050 --> 01:20:55,140
And its nature derives from the circumstances of its inheritance.

855
01:20:55,220 --> 01:20:57,810
The fact remains that primitive man took absolute delight...

856
01:20:57,890 --> 01:20:59,680
in tearing his adversary apart.

857
01:20:59,770 --> 01:21:03,560
And there is where I think the core of the problem resides.

858
01:21:03,650 --> 01:21:05,690
Doesn't that seem unnecessarily apocalyptic?

859
01:21:05,770 --> 01:21:08,230
I do not make poetry.

860
01:21:08,320 --> 01:21:10,490
Is there a TV in the house?

861
01:21:13,240 --> 01:21:18,540
I remarked to John that rationality is not a device to alter facts.

862
01:21:18,620 --> 01:21:21,910
But moreover, I think of it as an extraneous tool, a gadget.

863
01:21:22,000 --> 01:21:25,000
Somewhat like, uh, the television.

864
01:21:25,080 --> 01:21:27,920
To look at it any other way is ridiculous.

865
01:21:28,000 --> 01:21:30,130
There's some good things on it though.

866
01:21:31,170 --> 01:21:33,260
-I beg your pardon? -The TV.

867
01:21:33,340 --> 01:21:35,510
There's some good things on it sometimes.

868
01:21:35,590 --> 01:21:40,060
I have strong doubts. Nevertheless, I am not discussing media.

869
01:21:40,140 --> 01:21:44,020
-Oh, but there is always hope for the few. -What about love?

870
01:21:44,100 --> 01:21:46,900
What about it? Wouldn't you say that more ill...

871
01:21:46,980 --> 01:21:50,280
has been done in the name of love than in the name of abomination?

872
01:21:50,360 --> 01:21:52,530
No. No, I wouldn't.

873
01:21:52,610 --> 01:21:56,030
Well, you are a romantic, Catherine.

874
01:21:56,120 --> 01:21:58,530
And once more about to be married.

875
01:21:58,620 --> 01:22:02,950
So you can be excused from objective discussions. But ask Carl.

876
01:22:03,040 --> 01:22:07,210
Ask him if even the institution of marriage is completely free from it.

877
01:22:07,290 --> 01:22:08,630
Ask him.

878
01:22:08,710 --> 01:22:13,720
I think these cold, objective discussions are aggressive.

879
01:22:13,800 --> 01:22:16,300
-Excuse me. -That's reactive.

880
01:22:16,390 --> 01:22:18,090
 But if I may say...

881
01:22:18,180 --> 01:22:20,390
without dampening the spirit of your adventure 

882
01:22:20,470 --> 01:22:22,770
You haven't dampened my spirit, Samia.

883
01:22:22,850 --> 01:22:24,640
-Excuse me. -Well, I should hope not.

884
01:22:24,730 --> 01:22:27,230
But I want to say, though, it's still open to some discussion 

885
01:22:27,310 --> 01:22:29,900
-I'm sorry.  -that there seems to be less aggression...

886
01:22:29,980 --> 01:22:32,780
-or violence, if you like -I'm sorry. I don't speak French.

887
01:22:32,860 --> 01:22:36,070
the higher classes and loftier natures 

888
01:22:36,160 --> 01:22:37,740
What kind of doggy is this?

889
01:22:37,820 --> 01:22:39,490
This is a, uh, border collie.

890
01:22:39,580 --> 01:22:41,910
 I had a baby kitty-cat once.

891
01:22:41,990 --> 01:22:44,910
It was a little fluffy thing. Bobby gave it to me.

892
01:22:45,000 --> 01:22:47,290
Remember, Bobby?

893
01:22:47,370 --> 01:22:49,580
Little pussycat you gave me?

894
01:22:49,670 --> 01:22:51,250
Yeah.

895
01:22:51,340 --> 01:22:54,090
It had two little white front paws.

896
01:22:54,170 --> 01:22:57,090
And, oh, I was crazy after her.

897
01:22:57,180 --> 01:22:59,260
We left her at some friends' house...

898
01:22:59,350 --> 01:23:03,260
and she got squashed flatter than a tortilla right outside their mobile home.

899
01:23:03,350 --> 01:23:06,140
There. Do you see what I mean?

900
01:23:06,230 --> 01:23:10,770
The choice of words juxtaposed with the image of a fluffy kitten.

901
01:23:10,860 --> 01:23:15,940
The enchantment of words "squashed," "flat," etcetera, etcetera.

902
01:23:16,030 --> 01:23:17,200
Well, she was.

903
01:23:17,280 --> 01:23:20,370
Well, perhaps, but it was just what I was trying to point out.

904
01:23:20,450 --> 01:23:22,160
Don't sit there pointing at her.

905
01:23:22,240 --> 01:23:23,950
I beg your pardon?

906
01:23:24,040 --> 01:23:26,470
I said, don't point at her, you creep. 

907
01:23:26,470 --> 01:23:27,620
But I was just telling about

908
01:23:27,710 --> 01:23:30,380
Where the hell do you get the ass to tell anybody anything about class...

909
01:23:30,460 --> 01:23:32,630
or who the hell's got it or what she typifies?

910
01:23:32,710 --> 01:23:35,380
You shouldn't even be in the same room with her, you pompous celibate.

911
01:23:35,460 --> 01:23:38,340
-Carl, this is really too much. -Just calm down 

912
01:23:38,430 --> 01:23:40,260
You're totally full of shit!

913
01:23:40,970 --> 01:23:43,010
You're all full of shit!

914
01:23:46,520 --> 01:23:47,850
Catherine!

915
01:23:55,650 --> 01:23:57,190
Catherine.

916
01:24:08,750 --> 01:24:11,670
-Bobby -I can't talk to you. Leave me alone.

917
01:24:11,750 --> 01:24:13,840
Catherine?

918
01:24:15,170 --> 01:24:17,840
-What the hell is goin' on in here? -What are you doing?

919
01:24:19,340 --> 01:24:21,630
-Hey, where is Catherine? -Hey, get out of. This is my room.

920
01:24:21,720 --> 01:24:23,430
I don't know where Catherine is.

921
01:24:23,510 --> 01:24:26,850
I'm talking to you. I'm talking to you, Tita!

922
01:24:26,930 --> 01:24:30,270
-Be polite, will you? -I told you to take your hands off my sister, nurse!

923
01:24:30,350 --> 01:24:33,020
-Move out! -Stop it!

924
01:24:33,110 --> 01:24:35,440
Stop it! Stop it!

925
01:24:38,110 --> 01:24:40,530
Take it easy. Take 

926
01:24:40,610 --> 01:24:42,110
Take it easy, will you?

927
01:24:44,700 --> 01:24:46,700
-You stop it! -Will you give up?

928
01:24:46,790 --> 01:24:48,950
 Stop!

929
01:24:51,120 --> 01:24:55,130
-Will you give up, please? Give up, will you? -Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!

930
01:24:55,210 --> 01:24:56,540
-Give up! -No!

931
01:24:56,630 --> 01:24:59,050
Give up! Give up! Give up!

932
01:24:59,130 --> 01:25:01,840
Give up! Give up! Give up!

933
01:25:03,800 --> 01:25:05,640
Bobby!

934
01:25:14,270 --> 01:25:16,940
I just wanted to talk to you.

935
01:25:21,320 --> 01:25:23,910
It's useless.

936
01:25:24,990 --> 01:25:27,280
Look, give me a chance.

937
01:25:27,370 --> 01:25:29,910
I'm trying to be delicate with you...

938
01:25:30,000 --> 01:25:32,830
but you just won't understand.

939
01:25:32,920 --> 01:25:34,710
I couldn't go with you 

940
01:25:34,790 --> 01:25:37,670
not just because of Carl and my music, but because of you.

941
01:25:42,170 --> 01:25:44,840
You're a strange person, Robert.

942
01:25:46,850 --> 01:25:48,850
I mean, what will you come to?

943
01:25:50,430 --> 01:25:54,520
If a person has no love for himself, no respect for himself...

944
01:25:54,600 --> 01:25:59,400
no love of his friends, family, work, something...

945
01:25:59,480 --> 01:26:02,030
how can he ask for love in return?

946
01:26:02,110 --> 01:26:04,030
I mean, why should he ask for it?

947
01:26:07,370 --> 01:26:11,490
Living here in this rest home, asylum that's what you want?

948
01:26:11,580 --> 01:26:13,160
Yes.

949
01:26:13,250 --> 01:26:15,160
That will make you happy?

950
01:26:16,540 --> 01:26:18,540
I hope it will. Yes.

951
01:26:24,260 --> 01:26:25,760
I'm sorry.

952
01:26:56,500 --> 01:26:58,250
Okay.

953
01:27:17,270 --> 01:27:19,270
Are you cold?

954
01:27:38,790 --> 01:27:40,710
I don't know if you'd be...

955
01:27:40,790 --> 01:27:44,300
particularly interested in hearing anything about me.

956
01:27:45,550 --> 01:27:47,470
My life... I mean...

957
01:27:47,550 --> 01:27:51,220
most of it doesn't add up to much that I could relay it...

958
01:27:51,300 --> 01:27:53,850
as a way of life that you'd approve of.

959
01:27:55,720 --> 01:27:57,730
I move around a lot.

960
01:27:59,140 --> 01:28:03,150
Not because I'm looking for anything really, but 

961
01:28:04,480 --> 01:28:09,150
'Cause I'm getting away from things that get bad...

962
01:28:09,240 --> 01:28:11,200
if I stay.

963
01:28:13,330 --> 01:28:15,990
Auspicious beginnings-you know what I mean?

964
01:28:30,090 --> 01:28:34,100
I'm trying to imagine your 

965
01:28:34,180 --> 01:28:36,850
your half of this conversation.

966
01:28:40,020 --> 01:28:43,350
My feeling is... I don't know 

967
01:28:43,440 --> 01:28:47,190
that, uh, if you could talk, we wouldn't be talking.

968
01:28:50,030 --> 01:28:53,700
That's pretty much the way that it got to be before I left.

969
01:28:57,490 --> 01:28:59,000
Are you all right?

970
01:29:03,130 --> 01:29:05,040
I don't know what to say.

971
01:29:11,880 --> 01:29:15,640
Tita suggested that we try to... I don't know.

972
01:29:15,720 --> 01:29:17,970
I think that she feels 

973
01:29:18,060 --> 01:29:23,560
I think that she feels that we've got some understanding to reach.

974
01:29:27,650 --> 01:29:31,150
She totally denies the fact that we were never that comfortable...

975
01:29:31,240 --> 01:29:33,700
with one another to begin with.

976
01:29:45,920 --> 01:29:48,420
The best that I can do is apologize, and 

977
01:29:52,760 --> 01:29:56,590
We both know that I was never really that good at it anyway.

978
01:30:05,690 --> 01:30:07,940
I'm sorry it didn't work out.

979
01:30:14,820 --> 01:30:17,870
Bobby!

980
01:30:17,950 --> 01:30:20,870
-You're leaving. -Yeah.

981
01:30:20,950 --> 01:30:23,370
I said a week. I think I overstayed myself.

982
01:30:23,460 --> 01:30:25,960
You were going without saying good-bye to me.

983
01:30:26,040 --> 01:30:28,790
I didn't want to say good-bye to anyone.

984
01:30:29,960 --> 01:30:31,880
What about me?

985
01:30:32,880 --> 01:30:34,880
I'll say good-bye to you, Tita.

986
01:30:36,550 --> 01:30:38,220
 Oh, Robert.

987
01:30:40,310 --> 01:30:43,140
Watch the birdie.

988
01:30:46,310 --> 01:30:48,480
-Bye. -Bye.

989
01:30:50,190 --> 01:30:51,570
-Come on. -Wait a sec.

990
01:30:51,650 --> 01:30:53,530
-I want to go. -I want Tita to take a picture...

991
01:30:53,610 --> 01:30:55,990
of you and me in front of the place.

992
01:30:57,320 --> 01:31:00,910
Listen, I never got to thank you all for your hospitality.

993
01:31:00,990 --> 01:31:04,910
You tell Carl for me if any of you want to come down to our place anytime...

994
01:31:05,000 --> 01:31:06,290
you'd be more than welcome.

995
01:31:07,750 --> 01:31:09,250
Bye now.

996
01:32:22,740 --> 01:32:24,660
Cut it out!

997
01:32:24,740 --> 01:32:26,990
Son of a bitch, Bobby!

998
01:32:27,080 --> 01:32:29,580
You quit pushing me away like that!

999
01:32:29,660 --> 01:32:32,580
I've had enough of that to last me an entire lifetime.

1000
01:32:33,670 --> 01:32:36,250
Why don't you just be good to me for a change?

1001
01:32:44,430 --> 01:32:47,770
There isn't anybody gonna look after you and love you as good as I do.

1002
01:32:54,270 --> 01:32:56,520
Did you hear me?

1003
01:32:56,610 --> 01:32:58,110
Baby?

1004
01:33:21,800 --> 01:33:24,640
I'm-I'm goin' in that café for some coffee.

1005
01:33:25,640 --> 01:33:27,550
You want anything?

1006
01:33:30,810 --> 01:33:32,060
No.

1007
01:33:32,140 --> 01:33:34,140
You got any change?

1008
01:33:42,650 --> 01:33:44,820
You don't have any change?

1009
01:33:56,840 --> 01:33:59,300
Sure you don't want anything?

1010
01:34:00,880 --> 01:34:02,800
Fill it up, will you?

1011
01:35:45,940 --> 01:35:47,440
Hey, wait a minute.

1012
01:36:10,220 --> 01:36:12,720
Haven't you got a jacket or anything with you?

1013
01:36:12,800 --> 01:36:14,720
Oh, no. Uh 

1014
01:36:14,810 --> 01:36:17,890
Jesus. Uh-It got burned up.

1015
01:36:17,980 --> 01:36:20,230
Everything in the car got the shit burned out of it.

1016
01:36:20,310 --> 01:36:22,400
Uh, everything.

1017
01:36:22,480 --> 01:36:24,770
All I've got is what I've got on.

1018
01:36:24,860 --> 01:36:27,610
I got one behind the seat. If you want it, put it on.

1019
01:36:27,690 --> 01:36:29,820
No, it's okay.

1020
01:36:29,900 --> 01:36:32,910
Suit yourself. I'll tell you one thing.

1021
01:36:32,990 --> 01:36:35,490
Where we're goin', it's gonna get colder than hell.

1022
01:36:35,580 --> 01:36:38,250
No, that's okay.

1023
01:36:38,330 --> 01:36:40,000
I'm fine.

1024
01:36:41,000 --> 01:36:43,000
I'm fine.

1025
01:36:44,250 --> 01:36:45,630
I'm fine.

