What's that?
It sounds like the garbageman.
Oh? On Tuesday?
Maybe they changed the schedule.
Oh, shit.
Oh! Wait a minute!
Wait a minute!
Hey! Hold it up, you guys.
I was afraid you'd miss me.
Don't worry. We won't.
Now that is American
workmanship.
You think the Japanese invented that?
Bullshit. We did.
Oh, for a while there we lost it,
but we got it back.
- I like Cadillacs.
- You like Cadillacs? Come around,
brother, get in this Cadillac.
You're gonna love it.
This is style and beauty.
Comfy, right? Oh, I know what
you're gonna say. That's vinyl.
Take it from me, you don't
want leather, brother. Leather's hot.
It's uncomfortable. It cracks. Nothing but trouble.
Look at the headroom in here.
A guy like you is not gonna have any problem.
Go ahead, start it up.
Listen to that. That's power.
- That's performance.
- You know what I like best?
- What's that?
- The price.
Hey! Wait a minute!
You can't drive that car in here!
Hey, guys, how's it going?
Workin'. Workin'.
Oh, Daddy, put me down!
I surrender. I surrender.
I love you too.
Here come the sandwiches.
Why don't they just call him
"Girl George"?
It would cut down all the confusion.
Oh, Dad, that's so old.
When I was a boy and rock and roll
came to East Germany...
the Communists said
it was subversive.
Maybe they were right.
- What's in this?
- You don't want to know.
Dad, what's wrong?
What's that Army helicopter doing here?
You said you wouldn't go away again.
- You said you were through.
- I'm not going anywhere.
Promise?
I promise.
Jackson. Harris.
Secure the area.
John?
John, are you in there?
John, come on out.
It's Kirby.
- I know.
- Silent and smooth, just like always.
- I better be. You taught me.
- I'm getting a little rusty.
- What's going on?
- Jenny, how are you?
Hi.
- Jenny, I need to talk to your dad. Okay?
- Yeah? Got a warrant?
- Very funny.
- Jenny.
Okay.
John, we've got a problem.
Someone's killing your men.
You gave them new identities.
There must have been a leak.
Lawson, Forrestal, Bennett,
they've all been hit.
- Who is doing it?
- You've made enemies all over the world.
It could have been the Syrians,
the South Americans...
the Russians or a terrorist group.
They're gonna find you.
We were going
to make a normal life here.
You will. I promise.
I'm going into the city to coordinate
with the Federal people.
We'll nail those bastards
before they get close to you.
In the meantime, Jackson and Harris
will stay here with you.
- Are they any good?
- Real good, but not as good as you were.
Is it bad?
I'm not leaving you,
if that's what you mean.
Then it can't be bad.
- How bad are you hit?
- I can make it. I'll be all right.
I've got to get my rifle from the shed.
Keep an eye out. They'll be coming.
Remember, you're downwind.
The air current may tip them off.
- Downwind? You think
I can smell them coming?
- I did.
Okay, Jenny, you go to your bedroom, okay?
And stay out of sight. I'll be right back.
Where is she?
Mellow out, man.
We can't talk business with you
waving guns in people's faces.
Your daughter's safe, Colonel.
Whether she stays that way is up to you.
My people got some business with you.
If you want your kid back...
then you gotta cooperate.
- Right?
- Wrong.
He's coming at us with no brakes.
He's still coming, the crazy bastard.
He's gonna hit us.
Shit!
Don't move, motherfucker.
- Bennett, I thought you were—
- Dead?
You thought wrong.
Ever since you had me
thrown out of your unit...
I've waited to pay you back.
Do you know what today is, Matrix?
Payday.
Tranquilizers.
- I wanted to use the real thing!
- Where's Jenny?
Do you remember me, Colonel?
I remember you, scumbag.
Especially the people
you've tortured and killed.
Colonel Matrix.
You do not understand
a country like Val Verde.
- It is a country that needs...
a president who has
an understanding of discipline.
- Why tell me?
- Because...
you're going to return
to Val Verde...
and you are going to kill
the president...
that you helped to overthrow me.
Why don't you have Bennett do it?
Sounds like something
he would get off on.
Because President Velazquez
trusts you, Colonel.
After all, he made you
the hero of the revolution.
Captain Bennett left, shall we say,
under a cloud. Yes?
Yeah. He enjoyed killing
a little too much.
Your training, Matrix.
You can get close
to President Velazquez.
You will kill him.
You know, we went to
a lot of trouble to find you.
We had to pretend
Captain Bennett's death...
so that General Kirby would become
agitated and lead us to you...
and now that I have you,
you will do exactly...
as I tell you.
Fuck you.
- Daddy.
- Jenny.
Oh, you bastards.
Colonel Matrix, if you kill President Velazquez,
I will send her back to you.
If you try anything else...
I will mail her to you in pieces.
- Any sign of Matrix?
- No, sir. Just those bodies.
You think there's more, sir?
If he's still alive,
I'd expect a lot more.
Sully will make sure
you get on the plane.
Henriques will stay with you,
make sure you get off.
I don't hear from either one of 'em,
she's dead.
How much are they paying you, Bennett?
They offered me a hundred grand.
You want to know something?
When I found out I'd get my hands on you,
I said I'd do it for nothing.
- Hey! Hold it.
- I'll be back, Bennett.
John!
I'll be ready, John.
We're running late, buddy.
So you and Bennett
met in the service?
Me and Henriques
was in the service too.
There's nothing
like old war buddies.
Well, have a nice trip now.
Take care. Oh, here.
Have some beers in Val Verde, Matrix.
It'll give everyone a little
more time with your daughter.
You're a funny guy, Sully. I like you.
That's why I'm going to kill you last.
Move.
Hasta luego, fellas.
First class, 7-A.
And you're 7-B, sir.
- Any carry-on luggage?
- Just him.
Open your mouth again,
and I'll nail it shut.
- You must fasten your seat belt, sir.
- Thank you.
- Could I have a blanket and a pillow, please?
- Sure.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are now preparing for departure.
If you'll please make sure
all your carry-on luggage...
is safely stored
in the overhead compartments.
Make sure your seat belts are fastened
and extinguish all cigarettes.
Once we reach our cruising altitude,
we're gonna be serving our beverages...
and then, a little later on,
our dinner.
Shortly after that,
we'll be showing our feature film.
Your flight attendants
are Susan and Lance...
- and I'm Vicky.
We're here to make your trip
as comfortable as possible.
Thank you, and have a safe
and enjoyable flight.
Excuse me.
How long is the flight?
We land in Val Verde
in exactly 11 hours.
Thank you, and do me a favor.
Don't disturb my friend.
He's dead tired.
Front, please.
Thank you.
Sir, during takeoff
you must remain seated.
I'm airsick.
Yeah, the bird has flown.
Cargo's aboard.
Now go to the drop-off point.
Yes. Gracias, Sully.
Well, we are right on schedule.
With any good fortune,
today will be my last day as a civilian.
Your father seems to be cooperating.
You will be together with him soon.
Won't that be nice?
Not nearly as nice
as watching him kick your ass.
Take her below.
Yeah, that Cindy.
Well, my 7:40 flight
to Vancouver was canceled.
So how about dinner? Yeah.
Well, I could go to bed early too.
- Maybe we should do it another time.
- Sounds like he's mad at you.
Okay. Well, I like you too.
All right then.
Talk to you soon. Bye.
Well, love and careers—
It's tough, ain't it?
- Sounds like you need a date.
- Well, I don't.
I bet girls like you meet
a lot of nice boys at airports.
Listen, you're really bugging me.
Hey!
Hey! Slow down.
You know, I got something
I'd really like to give you.
- I'm not interested.
- Oh! You don't know what you're missing.
From here it looks like a nightmare.
Would you leave me alone?
You fucking whore.
Don't move!
- I'm not going to hurt you. Step aside.
- You said, "Don't move."
Do it. Get in the car.
- Do exactly what I tell you to do.
- I've got a 7:30 karate class.
- I can't help you.
- You're not gonna make it.
Follow him.
Oh, I knew you were gonna say that.
Don't get offended by this question,
but are you gonna kill me or something?
- No.
- I suppose you wouldn't tell me if you were.
- Sure I would.
- Really?
Trust me.
Stay close to him. Faster.
That's good.
- Can you tell me what this is about?
- Yeah.
- A guy I trusted for years wants me dead.
- That's understandable.
I've only known you five minutes,
and I want you dead too.
Out. Come. Hurry up.
- Listen, if you're in a hurry, I can just—
- I'm almost through with you.
Listen to me. My daughter
has been kidnapped.
He's the only chance
I've got of finding her.
If he sees me or I lose him,
he'll kill her.
What I need you to do is follow him,
tell him you're crazy about him.
Try to bring him over here.
I will do the rest...
and you can go back
to your normal life, got it?
- No.
- Please, help me. You're the only chance I've got.
She has less than 10 hours left.
Don't you understand?
They're gonna kill her.
Okay. All right.
I'll help you.
Listen, there's this huge guy outside
in a green T-shirt.
And he's a paranoid maniac
and he's kidnapped me...
and I need your help.
- I'll check it out.
- Thank you.
- I hear you're a great man with transmissions.
- That's right.
Oh, yeah.
These will work just fine.
Biggs, are you there? Listen.
There's a guy that may be a wacko.
I don't think
I can handle him alone.
I'll be right there. Wanna see me kick some ass?
- You'd better wait here, miss.
- Thank you.
Attention, all units.
Emergency on the theater level.
Suspect: Six feet two, brown hair.
He's one gigantic motherfucker.
This used to be a great place
for hunting slash.
It's got a little crowded now.
I think I found something though.
I'll see you.
What are you doing in here?
I'm waiting for my friend.
- Are you looking for me?
- You better come with us.
What? Matrix.
Give me a quarter.
Give me a quarter!
Move it!
- Oh, shit!
- Son of a bitch!
- Out of my way.
- Freeze!
- Come on! Let's go get him!
- Come on.
- Stop or I'll shoot!
- No!
Hey, Lady! Stop!
Wait! Wait for me!
Don't you go anywhere!
Who the hell are you, huh?
You steal my car.
You rip the seat out. You kidnap me.
You ask me to help you find your daughter,
which I very kindly do...
and then you get me involved
in a shootout where people are dying.
I watch you rip a phone booth
outta the wall...
swing from the ceiling like Tarzan
and then a cop is gonna shoot you...
and I save you,
and he starts chasing me!
Are you gonna tell me
what's going on or what?
- No.
- No? No? Oh, my God! Watch out!
What are you doing?
Oh! Look out!
This is not my day!
Whoa!
My car!
- Are you all right?
- I think I'm dead.
- You're all right. Wait for me.
- Okay.
- Where is she, Sully?
- Kiss my ass.
- I can't hear you.
- I'll say it louder then. Get fucked.
Your loyalty is very touching...
but it is not the most important thing
in your life right now.
What is important is gravity.
I have to remind you, Sully...
this is my weak arm.
You can't kill me.
You need me to find your daughter.
- Where is she?
- I don't know, but Cooke knows.
- I'll take you where
I'm supposed to meet him.
- But you won't.
- Why not?
- Because I already know.
Remember when I promised to kill you last?
- That's right. You did.
- I lied.
So now you don't have a car.
Now I do.
- What did you do with Sully?
- I let him go.
I'm sorry I got you involved in this.
Why don't you tell me
what this is all about?
- It's about her.
- Is this your daughter?
Some people are using her
to force me to do a job.
- If I don't get to her soon, they'll kill her.
- Did you do the job?
No. I knew they would
kill her even if I did it.
Her only chance now is that I get to her
before they find out what I'm doing.
Let's go. Out.
Stay put.
- What are you doing?
- Helping you get her back.
- Look through the drawers.
- All right.
It's Cooke.
Mess up the bed.
Okay.
Remember, you had a good time with Sully.
Open the door.
All right.
Yeah?
- Where's Sully?
- In the shower.
- Who are you?
- Room service.
Open the door.
Move back over there.
Hey, Sully!
You scared, motherfucker?
You should be.
This Green Beret's
gonna kick your big ass.
I eat Green Berets for breakfast.
And right now I'm really hungry.
I can't believe this macho bullshit.
Fuck you, asshole.
These guys eat too much red meat.
Where is she?
Cooke!
Let's go.
This must be Cooke's car.
Let's search it.
I think I found something.
- Look at this.
- What is this?
- Coastal is a fuel depot that supplies planes.
- To whom? The airlines?
- Usually smaller, private aircraft.
- Are you sure?
I'm getting my pilot's license.
This is where my instructor gets his fuel.
There are a lot of warehouses
down the street.
Arius must be keeping
a plane down there.
Let's go. We'll take Cooke's car.
He won't be needing it.
This is it.
Patria Enterprises.
I think this is where
I was this afternoon.
- You go this way and wait for my signal.
- Okay.
- Cindy. Come on.
- Yeah?
I've seen all the equipment they've got,
but there's no airplane.
- What about your daughter?
- Arius and Bennett aren't here.
- She's wherever they are.
- Okay.
Look at this.
These coordinates are
somewhere near Santa Barbara.
Longitude.
There's something going on at this island
off the coast north of here.
- This must be where they've taken Jenny.
- Look.
Here's a photo
of an amphibian airplane.
Maybe they use it to fly out there.
Yeah, let's look at that invoice.
All right.
Type four fuel is amphibian.
250 gallons is what it would take...
to fly this plane
to the island and back.
But it isn't here.
I've seen everything they've got.
It was refueled at Pump Station 32,
Pacific Pier.
That's San Pedro.
- How long does it take to fly?
- About two hours.
- Are we going to the plane?
- Not yet.
- Where are we going?
- Shopping.
Shopping?
Come on. Come on.
- What's that?
- Rocket launcher. Go!
Freeze!
Don't even think about it!
TX-94. TX-94.
- Stick him in the truck.
- Come on. Come on.
If you call General Franklin Kirby
he will explain everything to you.
Kirby, huh? Yeah, I think we ran him in last week.
- Hey! Hooker.
- Not bad.
What do you think she's doing?
- I think she's got something for us.
- I bet she does.
- Shit!
- What the hell was that?
- God!
- Jesus Christ!
- Whoa!
- Where did you learn how to do that?
- I read the instructions.
What time you expect Matrix
to arrive in Val Verde?
Just over two hours.
Do you think he's going to
give us any problems?
He'll do exactly as he's told...
as long as he thinks
he'll get his daughter back.
- It's all clear.
- Good.
Did anybody ever tell you
you have a lot of hostility?
Come on. Let's move.
I hope I can fly this plane.
Oh, shit.
- Oh, no.
- What's wrong?
This isn't a plane.
This is a canoe with wings!
Well, then get in and start paddling.
Start the engine. Hurry up!
Okay. Okay. Okay.
- Oh, my God! This plane is older than I am!
- Come on!
Look! There's no L.E.D. Readout!
I've only trained on a Cessna!
- Hurry up!
- I'm trying!
Shit!
Come on, you piece of shit! Fly or die!
Works every time.
All right, here we go.
- Watch out for the boat!
- Oh! We're not gonna make it!
Yes, we are.
We did it.
We did it. Wow.
- Well done.
- Thank you.
- Matrix?
- Call the Federal building.
Have them monitor every police,
aviation and marine channel.
- What are you expecting?
- World War III.
Repeat. This is Whiskey Xray 448
for General Kirby. Urgent you respond.
Attention unidentified aircraft.
This is the Coast Guard cutter Marauder.
You're flying over
the San Miguel Gunnery Range.
This is a highly restricted area.
You must change course,
or you will be forced to land.
- Acknowledge.
- Urgent. Repeat. Urgent.
You must contact
General Franklin Kirby.
You must first change course
or you risk being shot down. Acknowledge.
They shoot the shit out of this area all the time.
All the flights out of LAX
avoid it like the plague.
- Can you go below radar?
- Not marine radar.
Maybe if I get us close enough to the water,
the waves can camouflage us.
- Go down.
- Oh. Okay.
- Do it.
- Hang on.
We lost them, sir.
Slitting a little girl's throat...
is like cutting warm butter.
Put the knife away...
and shut your mouth.
I love listening to your little pissant soldiers
trying to talk tough.
They make me laugh.
If Matrix was here, he'd laugh too.
Mr. Bennett, my soldiers are patriots.
Your soldiers are nothing.
Matrix and I could kill every one of them
in the blink of an eye.
- Remember that.
- Are you trying to frighten me?
I don't have to try.
When Matrix finishes the job,
he'll be back for his daughter.
Whether she's alive or dead doesn't matter.
Then he'll be after you.
The only thing between
Matrix and you...
is me.
It is you that is afraid, Mr. Bennett.
You are afraid of Matrix.
Of course. I'm smart.
But I have an edge.
I have his daughter.
- Is that it?
- That's the one.
Land here. It's the most
isolated spot we'll find.
Okay, here we go.
Now, you remember the message?
Commando, Kirby, Code Red,
Coordinates. Got it.
Don't break radio silence
until they see me.
- How will I know?
- Because all fucking hell is gonna break loose.
Be careful, Matrix.
Good luck.
Thanks.
He was not on the plane.
Kill her.
Welcome back, John.
So glad you could make it.
That little...
bitch!
Commando.
I say again, Commando.
This is Whiskey Xray 448.
I have an emergency priority message
for a General Franklin Kirby.
I repeat, General Franklin Kirby.
General, you'd better get out here.
We have your message on the Teletype.
Jenny!
Jenny?
Daddy?
Jenny!
- Jenny!
- Daddy?
No. Not Daddy.
Come on!
Daddy.
- John! How's your arm?
- Come over and find out.
No, thanks.
I think I'll take a pass.
John, stick your head out.
One shot, right between the eyes.
I'll make it quick,
just for old times' sake.
Bennett, stop screwing around
and let the girl go.
It's me that you want. I have only one arm.
You can beat me.
Come on, Bennett.
Throw away that chickenshit gun.
You don't just want to pull a trigger.
Put the knife in me...
and look me in the eye
and see what's going on in there...
when you turn it.
- That's what you want to do, right?
- I can kill you, John.
Come on.
Let the girl go.
It's between you and me.
Don't deprive yourself of some pleasure.
Come on, Bennett.
Let's party.
- I can beat you.
- No.
I don't need the girl.
I don't need the girl!
I don't need the gun, John.
I can beat you.
I don't need no gun!
I'm gonna kill you now!
- Daddy.
- You're getting old, John.
You're getting old.
John, I feel good,
just like old times.
What's it feel like to be a dying man?
- You're a dead man!
- Bullshit!
John, I'm not gonna
shoot you between the eyes.
I'll shoot you between the balls!
Let off some steam, Bennett.
Daddy.
Move out!
- Leave anything for us?
- Just bodies.
I'd just like you to start up
your unit again, John.
- All it would take is your coming back.
- This was the last time.
Until the next time.
No chance.