Hey, boy!
What you doing with my mama's car?
Wait there!
Ain't you ashamed? You're trying
to steal an old lady's automobile?
What you talking about?
I've been thinking about buying me one.
Bull!
You ain't got money for dinner,
let alone buying no car.
Well, ma'am, I'll tell you something.
I got enough money for a Coca-Cola...
...and since it don't look like
you gonna invite me inside...
Ho. You'd steal
the dining room table if I did.
You wanna go into town with me?
How'd that be?
I'm going to work, anyway.
- You're going to work, huh?
- Yeah.
- What kind of work you do?
- None of your business.
I'll bet you're a movie star.
- A lady mechanic?
- No.
- A maid?
- What do you think I am?
A waitress?
What-- What line of work are you in'?
When you're not stealing cars?
Heh. I tell you, I'm looking for
suitable employment right at the moment.
Oh, yes, but what'd you do before?
I was-- I was in state prison.
- State prison?
- Uh-huh.
Well, I guess some little old lady
wasn't so nice.
It was armed robbery.
My, my-
The things that turn up in the street
these days.
Hey. Hey, what y'all do for a good time
around here? Listen to the grass grow?
I guess you had a lot more
fun up at state prison, huh?
- I tell you. You see my right foot?
- Yeah.
I chopped two toes off that foot
with an ax.
What? Why?
To get off of work detail.
You wanna see it?
No.
L-- I-- I surely don't intend to stand
here in the middle of Main Street...
...and look at your dirty feet.
Boy, did you really do that?
What's it like?
What you mean, prison?
No.
Armed robbery.
It ain't like anything.
Shoot, I knew you never
robbed any place, you faker.
Yeah.
But you wouldn't have
the gumption to use it.
All right.
You just wait right here
and you keep your eyes open.
Now.
- Hey, what's your name, anyhow?
- Clyde Barrow.
Hi, I'm Bonnie Parker.
Pleased to meet you.
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, hey, slow down,
slow down, slow down.
Take it easy, you got my hand trapped.
- Hey, out it out. Cut it out!
- Oh!
All right, now, all right, now.
I might as well tell you right off.
I ain't much of a lover boy.
That don't mean nothing personal
about you. I never saw no percentage in it.
Ain't nothing wrong with me.
I don't like boys.
Boy! Boy, boy.
Huh?
-"Boy," what?
- Your advertising is just dandy.
Folks would never guess
you don't have a thing to sell.
You'd better take me home.
- Now, wait a minute.
- Now don't you touch me.
Uhn! All right, all right...
...if all you want's a stud service,
get on back to West Dallas...
...and you stay there,
the rest of your life.
You're worth more than that, you know it,
and that's why you come along with me.
You could find a lover boy
on every corner.
Don't make a damn to them if you're waiting
on tables, but it does make a damn to me!
Why?
What you mean, why?
Because you're different, that's why.
You're like me.
You want different things.
You got something better
than being a waitress.
You and me together, we could
cut a path across the state...
...and Kansas and Missouri and Oklahoma,
and everybody'd know about it.
Listen to me, Miss Bonnie Parker.
You listen to me.
How'd you like to go walking in the dining
room of the Adolphus Hotel in Dallas...
...wearing a nice silk dress and
have everybody waiting on you?
Would you like that?
Seem like a lot to ask?
That ain't enough for you.
You got a right to that.
Hey.
When did you figure all that up?
The minute I saw you.
Why?
Because you may be the
best damn girl in Texas.
You were born somewhere
around east Texas, right?
- Yeah.
- Come from a big old family?
Yeah.
You went to school,
but didn't take to it...
...because you was smarter than everybody
else, so you just up and quit one day.
Now, when you were 16-- Seventeen.
--there was a guy who worked in a-- In a--
- Cement plant.
- Right, cement plant.
You liked him, because he thought
you were as nice as you could be.
You almost married that guy,
but then you thought no.
So then you got you your job in a everybody'd.
And now you wake up every
morning and you hate it.
You just hate it. You get on down there
and you put on your white uniform--
Pink. It's pink.
Uh-huh. Them truck drivers come in
to eat your greasy burgers and...
...they kid you, you kid them back
but they're stupid and dumb boys...
...with their tattoos
and you don't like it.
They ask for dates. Sometimes
you go, but you mostly don't...
...because all they're trying to do
is get in your pants.
So you go on home and you sit in
your room and you think, "Now, when...
...and how am I ever gonna
get away from this?"
And now you know.
Change that. I don't like it.
- Hmm?
- Mm-hm.
Hmm.
Sheeh. You're a knockout.
- Hey, that ain't ours.
- Sure it is.
No, but we come in this one.
That don't mean we
have to go home in it.
Clyde?
- Clyde?
- Hey, lady.
- Hey.
- Where you been keeping yourself?
- Oh, I slept out by the car.
- Oh.
These accommodations
ain't particularly deluxe.
If they're after us, I want the first shot.
Come on out. We got some work to do.
- Whew. You're good.
- I ain't good. I'm the best.
And modest.
Now see that there now?
Set her spinning.
Now, try-- No.
- Ah!
- It's all right.
Come on, now, try it again.
And try and get-- Now this
time come down slow. Slow.
All right.
How about that? Now,
ain't you something? I tell you.
I'm gonna get you a Smith & Wesson.
Go in your hand easier.
- I want you to try something.
- Hey, you.
No, sir. No, sir.
Y'all go right ahead.
It used to be my place.
But it's not anymore.
The bank took it.
Yes, sir, they moved us off.
Now it belongs to them.
Why, that's a pitiful shame.
You're damn right, ma'am.
Me and him put in the years here.
Yes, sir. You all go right ahead.
We just come by for a last look.
Y'all mind? Hey, Davis.
Come on over here.
That's right.
Go on.
Look.
Much obliged.
My name's Otis Harris. This is Davis.
We worked this place.
How are you?
This here's Miss Bonnie Parker.
Glad to meet you. Clyde.
I'm Clyde Barrow.
We rob banks.
Look, I don't want you
to worry about nothing.
This is gonna be the easiest thing in the
world. Your mama could take this bank.
All right?
You just be ready if I need you.
What are you waiting for?
All right, now!
This is a stickup. Just take it easy
and nothing's gonna happen to you.
- Howdy.
- Give me the money.
Give me the money.
What money, mister?
There ain't no money here.
What you talking about?
This here's a bank?
Well, it was a bank,
but we failed three weeks ago.
All right, now, you get on out here.
Come on out here!
Shhh...
You get on out there and tell my girl.
Come on, come on,
you tell her what you told me.
Oh, no.
We got $1.98, and you're laughing.
A loaf of bread, a dozen eggs...
...a quart of milk, four fried pies.
Come on, now, you sure you ain't got
no peach pies? I don't believe you--
Get the hell out of here!
Go ahead! Go ahead!
I'm on, I'm on, I'm on.
He tried to kill me. Why'd he try
to kill me? I didn't wanna hurt him.
Try to get something to eat, some son
of a bitch come up with a meat cleaver.
I ain't against him.
- What was wrong with that, boy?
- Dirt.
Dirt?
Dirt in the fuel line.
Just Shhh it away. Heh.
Excuse me, ma'am, is there
anything else I could do for you today?
You're a smart fella.
You sure do know a lot about
automobiles, don't you?
Yes. I guess I do.
Well...
Would you know what kind of car this is?
This is a four-cylinder Ford coupe?
- No.
- Huh.
Sure. It sure is.
No, this is a stolen
four-cylinder Ford coupe.
Hey, you ain't scared, are you?
Huh?
I believe he is.
That's a pity. We sure could
have used a smart boy like that...
...who knows such a great
deal about automobiles.
Hey, you a good driver, boy?
Yeah, reckon I am.
No, he's better off here.
What's your name, boy?
C.W. Moss.
Well, I'm Miss Bonnie Parker
and this here is Mr. Clyde Barrow.
We rob banks.
- Ohh...
- Hey, now...
...there ain't nothing
wrong with that, is there?
Oh. No.
Clyde, he ain't the one. Let's go.
Hey, boy. You think you got the guts
for our line of work?
What are you talking about? I spent
a year-- I spent a year in reformatory.
Hoo-hoo. A man with a record.
You got the nerve to
shortchange old ladies getting gas.
Have you got what it takes
to pull bank jobs with us?
Mr. C.W. Moss.
Sure, I do. I ain't afraid,
if that's what you think.
Prove it.
Yup. You're gonna be all right.
No.
Mmm...
Nope.
I'm afraid we're overdrawn again this time.
This is a stickup.
- Ahem. This here's a stickup!
- Oh!
All right.
Leave it. Leave it there.
Leave it there.
Come on, come on, everything.
Get it up here.
Clyde, where's the car?
What'd he do? Where's the car?
Where did he go?
Here!
What the hell you doing
parking the car?
Go. Go.
- Turn it.
- Get it out. Get it out now.
Stop that car! Stop that car!
Up ahead, cut left! Left!
We're in the money
The sky is sunny
Old Man Depression, you are through
You done us wrong
We never see a headline
About a bread line today
And when we see the landlord
We can look that guy right in the eye
Oh, we're in the money
Come on, my honey
You ain't got a brain in your skull.
Why, we're in the money
I'll bet we're in the money
We've got a lot of what it takes
To get along
On account of you, I killed a man.
And now we're all gonna be wanted
for murder, and that's you too, boy.
We never see a headline
About a bread line today
And when we see the landlord
We can look that guy right in the eye
Dummy! Stupid!
Shhh.
What was you thinking about?
Do a dumb-ass thing like that again,
boy, and I'm gonna kill you.
Shh! If you boys wanna talk,
why don't y'all go outside?
- Hey, who are you?
- You'll find out.
Come on, boys,
we might as well begin right here.
All right, come over here.
We're in the money
We've got a--
We've got a lot of what it take--
We've got a lot of what it takes
- To get along
CLYDE: Bonnie.
Hey-- Hey, honey.
Honey, come on, I wanna talk to you
for just a minute. Sit down, huh?
Look...
This afternoon we killed a man,
and we were seen.
So far, nobody knows who you are...
...but they know who I am. They'll be
after me and anybody who's with me.
That's murder.
Now it's gonna get rough.
Now, look, I can't get out,
but right now you still can.
You say the word, and I'll put you
on that bus back to your mama...
...because you mean a lot to me, and
I ain't gonna make you run with me.
- No.
- Huh?
No.
I ain't a rich man.
You could get a rich man if you tried.
I don't want no rich man.
You ain't gonna
have a minute's peace.
You promise?
Hah. At least I ain't a liar.
I told you I wasn't no lover boy.
Oh!
- Let me look at you, boy.
- Hey, hey, come on, now.
Come on. Oh!
Boy, you can do better than that.
- Hey.
- Hey, hey, how's Mama?
Fine, fine.
- Sister? Sister?
- Sent her best to you.
- Filling out there. Must be that prison food.
- No, no, no, that's-- That's married life.
You know what they say...
...it's the face powder
that gets a man interested...
...but it's the baking powder
that keeps him home. Huh?
I want you to meet my wife, Blanche.
Blanche, this is my baby brother.
- How you doing? It's real nice to know you.
- How do you do?
- Heh. Yeah. Hey, Bonnie!
- Yeah.
Hey. Hey, Bonnie! Hey.
- Hey.
- Hey! Wait. Is it--?
Oh, boy. Is this Bonnie?
Hear you're taking good care
of the baby of the family.
Sis, I'm just so glad to meet you. Come on.
I want you to meet my wife.
- Blanche, this here is Bonnie.
- Hi.
Hello.
Hey, everybody, this is C.W. Moss.
My brother, Buck, and his wife, Blanche.
Howdy, everybody. Howdy, y'all.
Howdy, Mrs. Barrow. Or may I call you--?
May I call you Blanche? Heh.
I sure am pleased to meet you. How'd you
find us here in the neck of the woods?
Boy, you sure--
You sure picked a good day for it.
Oh, is that a new Screenland Magazine?
Is there any new pictures of
Myrna Loy in there?
She's my favorite picture star. May I?
Let me get the Kodak.
We'll take some pictures.
Put your pants on.
Come on Blanche, get out of there!
I'm a mess.
Been driving all day, honey.
- Come on, now. Come on, now.
- Now hold onto her there.
- You're not a--
- I got it.
Did you take my picture, Buck? Well, I
declare. I asked you not to take my picture.
Hey, Buck, get one of this.
Hey, brother, I wanna talk
to you later on.
You devil, you.
Hold it.
- You got that? Ha-ha.
- Yeah.
Hey, now you take one
of me and my missus, here, Clyde.
- All right.
- Honey, I don't wanna.
Honestly, I don't want--
I don't want my picture taken.
- You look over there at the birdy and smile.
- Buck.
- Give old-- Give old--
- Be serious. Be serious.
Hold still.
Hey, let me take one of Bonnie alone.
Come on, honey.
Okay.
All right, now. Oh, honey. Heh.
- Hey. Come on now, a little smile.
- No.
Don't wanna smile?
Eh?
I wanna have a chat with you.
C.W., take the girls' pictures.
Why don't you step
in there with Bonnie?
- What'd you think or her? Yeah.
- Bonnie?
She's a peach.
Hey, now.
- Now. Now tell me true.
- What?
What?
Is she as good as she looks?
She's better.
Hey, listen, it was
either you or him, wasn't it?
- What?
- The guy you killed, you had to do it?
- It was you or him.
- He put me on the spot. I had to.
- You had to do it, right?
- I had to. I had to.
I knew you did. Don't say
anything to Blanche about that.
Oh, uh...
Hey, that time you broke out of jail,
that true she talk you into going back?
- Yeah. You hear about that?
- Is that true?
Yeah, yeah.
Well, I won't say
nothing to Bonnie about it.
I appreciate that.
- We're gonna have ourselves a time, boy!
- We surely are.
Yeah.
What are we gonna do?
Well, how's this?
I figured we all drive up in Missouri.
They ain't looking for me up there.
We find a nice little place to hole up in.
We have us a regular vacation.
- All right?
- Yeah, yeah.
- No trouble now.
- I ain't looking to go back to no prison.
I heard in prison you had a little trouble.
You was cutting on your toes.
Really? You heard about that, eh?
Yeah, well, I did a little toe-cutting.
That ain't half of it.
I did it so I could get off of work detail.
Breaking them rocks
with a sledgehammer.
And you know what?
The very next week I get paroled.
I walk out of that
God forsaken jail on crutches.
- Ain't life grand?
- Shoot.
Hey, you wanna hear a story? About
this boy, he owned a dairy farm, see.
And his old ma, she was
kind of sick, you know.
And the doctor, he called
him over and said:
"Listen, your ma, she lying there,
she's just so sick and she's weakly...
...and I want you to try to persuade
her to take a little brandy, see.
Just to pick her spirits up, you know."
And, "Ma's a teetotaler," he says,
"she wouldn't touch a drop."
"Well, I'll tell you what you do."
That's the doc.
"Now, I tell you what you do.
You bring in a
fresh quart of milk every day...
...and you put some brandy in it, see.
And you try that."
So he did, and he doctored it all up
with the brandy, the fresh milk...
...and he gave it to his mama, she drank
a little bit of it. She didn't--
So next day he brought it in again,
and she drank a little more, you know.
And so, it went on that way for--
The third day, just a little more...
...and the fourth day she was,
you know, took a little bit more...
...and then finally one week later,
he gave her the milk...
...and she just drank it down, boy.
She swallowed the whole thing...
...and she called him over and she said,
"Son...
...whatever you do, don't sell that cow."
"Don't sell the cow."
- You got the keys now, haven't you?
- Yeah, I got them.
Fine.
Bye-bye.
- Bye.
I gave him a month's rent in advance.
We're all set. Let's get inside.
Honey lamb, I'm taking
you to our first home. Ha-ha!
Here comes the bride.
What do you think, hon? Huh?
Just perfect.
This is your first home.
Well, he gave me the grocery number.
This is perfect for all of us, isn't it?
4-3-3-7, please.
- Hi, there, Speedie's Groceries?
- Look, it's so clean, Buck.
- And a Frigidaire, not an icebox.
- 143 Hillsdale Avenue.
Hillsdale Avenue.
Oh. They got linoleum on the counter.
- Ain't that clever?
- Eight pounds of pork chops.
Four pounds of red beans.
Some Chase and Sanborn coffee.
About eight bottles of Dr. Pepper.
You sure can play checkers.
You're killing me.
You need a haircut. You're
looking just like a hillbilly boy.
You are just like an old man.
Playing checkers all the time,
don't pay any attention to your poor wife.
Boy, you ain't gonna never beat me,
but you just keep trying.
Come on, I'm gonna whip you.
on, Daddy...
...you sure do need a haircut.
Why, you look just like a little
old hillbilly, I do declare.
Oh, mercy me, don't.
Don't talk that way when she's
right there in the next room.
There is always somebody
in the next room, in this room...
...or in every other kind of room.
Well, honey, don't you ever
just wanna be alone with me?
Well, I always feel like we're alone.
Do you, baby?
I'm hungry. Hey, Buck.
Groceries, ma'am.
- How much?
- Six dollars and 43 cents.
- Forty-three?
- Yes, ma'am.
All right.
- There you are.
- Okay.
- Let me help. Those bags are heavy.
- No, thanks, I'll get them.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Just get the door.
Yes, ma'am.
Buck, look at Bonnie. Get that--
Shh. He's still down there.
Close the door.
But few of them really are justified
If you get right down to the point.
You've heard of a woman's glory
Being spent on a downright cur--
Did you write all that yourself?
Do you wanna hear this or not?
--cur.
Still you can't always judge the story
As true, being told by her.
Now Sal was a gal of rare beauty
Though her features were coarse
and tough--
I knew that old gal.
She was cockeyed
and she had a harelip and no teeth.
Hey, Buck, come on, now.
Go ahead.
Now Sal was a gal of rare beauty
Though her features were coarse and tough
She never once faltered from duty
To play on the up and up.
Sal told me this tale on the evening
Before she was turned out free.
And I'll do my best to relate it
Just as she told it to me.
Hey, hey. The laws are outside.
They're blocking the driveway.
- Buck, get us out of here!
- Shut up!
They got us blocked.
We gotta get the car out.
Cover me!
Get out of here.
Where's Blanche? Where's Blanche?
Damn it, you almost got us killed!
What did I do wrong? I thought
you'd be happy if I got shot!
Yeah! Yeah, it would've
saved us all a lot of trouble.
Buck, don't let that woman
talk to me like that.
You shouldn't have done that, Blanche.
It was a dumb thing to do.
Oh, Buck, please, I didn't marry you
to see you get shot, honey.
Let's go. Let's leave.
Let's get out of here and leave town.
Please make him stop
the car and let us out.
I can't.
I killed a guy. Now we're in this.
- Please?!
'Wm you shut up?!
Shut up your big mouth! At least
do that much. Shut up!
Cut it out, Bonnie!
You stop the car.
I wanna talk to you.
- Get-- Get rid of her.
- I can't get--
- She's Buck's wife.
- Get rid of them both.
- Why? What's the matter with you?
- She is what's the matter with me.
She-- She's nothing but a dumb, stupid...
-...Sanborn hick.
- Look!
She ain't got a brain in her head.
What makes you better?
You so damn special?
You were a West Dallas waitress.
Spent your time picking up truck drivers.
Stop it!
Oh, big Clyde Barrow!
You're just like your brother!
- Uh-huh.
- Ignorant, uneducated hillbilly!
The only special thing about you
is your peculiar ideas about lovemaking...
...which is no lovemaking at all.
No.
Oh, Clyde, please, I didn't mean that.
Listen, it was just all--
All that shooting...
...and all those guns. I got so scared.
Please, honey, I didn't mean it.
Yeah, honey.
Come on.
"Law enforcement officers...
...throughout the Southwest
are frankly amazed...
...at the way in which the
will-0'-the-wisp bandit Clyde Barrow...
...and his yellow-haired companion,
Bonnie Parker...
...continue to elude
their would-be captors.
Since engaging in a police battle
on the streets of Joplin, Missouri...
...and slaying three of their number.
The Barrow Gang has been reported
as far west as Whites City, New Mexico...
...and as far north as Chicago.
They have been credited with robbing
the Mesquite Bank in Whites City...
...and the J.J. Landry Oil Refinery
in Arp...
- ...Texas...
- Arp.
...the Sanger City National Bank
in Sanger, Indiana...
...and the Lancaster Bank in Denton,
Texas, on three different occasions.
In addition to these robberies,
the fast-traveling Barrows...
...have been rumored
to have had a hand...
...in the robbing of two
Piggly Wiggly stores...
...in Texas
and one A&P store in Missouri.
Though Chief Percy Hammond, who first
identified Clyde Barrow's brother, Buck...
- Oh, Lord.
-...as a member..."
We ain't gonna see another toilet
for 30 miles.
Why don't you pull up over here?
Over here.
Hey, now, here's something.
"Lone cop arrests two officers
in hunt for Barrow.
Police officer Howard Anderson's heart
turned faster than his motorcycle...
...when he forced to the side of the road
a black V-eight sedan...
...in which were three men and a
blonde-headed woman yesterday afternoon.
He was certain he'd caught Clyde Barrow,
Bonnie Parker, maybe Buck Barrow...
-...and the third unidentified member.
- Heh-heh. Well...
It took a lot of telephoning
and explaining to convince...
...the motorcycle cop that his captives
were two highway patrolmen...
...and a blonde-haired stenographer
from the highway patrol.
Anderson was held up as an example...
...for every other
Texas police officer today..."
Sheriff!
30-hoo! 30-hoo!
I never seen such shooting!
All right, all right.
All right, now you just get
on right over to that car.
Well, now, lookie here. We're in the
custody of Captain Frank Hammer.
- And Frank here is a Texas Ranger.
- Sure enough is.
Say, peacemaker...
...I believe you got your spurs
all tangled up there, haven't you?
- You're in Missouri. Know that?
- Know you're in Missouri?
- He's lost, this Texas Ranger.
- I don't think he's lost.
Them banks been offering
extra reward money for us...
...and I think Frank just figured on
some easy pickings. Didn't you, Frank?
You know, Texas Ranger,
you ain't doing your job.
You ought to be home protecting the
rights of poor folk, not out chasing us.
- Come on.
- Don't take it personal.
- Protecting the poor folks.
- Why you wanna take it personal for?
Well, we gotta discourage this here
bounty hunting for the Barrow Gang.
Bounty? Huh?
What do you wanna do
with him then, huh?
- Shoot him?
- No!
Come on, now. Huh?
- Hang him. I don't know.
- Uh-uh. Take his picture.
- Huh?
- Take his picture?
- Listen, we take his picture...
...we'll send it to the newspapers.
Frank just see Captain Frank Hammer...
...of the Texas Rangers with the Barrow
Gang, and all of us just as friendly as pie.
Now, you know, we are just about the
friendliest folks you'd ever wanna meet.
Big old Texas Ranger
waves his gun at us...
...and we just welcome him
like he was one of our own.
- Hey, Buck, get the Kodak.
- Yeah.
Hot doggies! Get him up there
on the spare tire, Clyde.
Ha-ha-ha.
- All right. There we go, my friend.
Now, see what come of your mischief
of not doing your job?
You know, down in
Duncanville last year...
...poor farmers kept you laws
away from us with shotguns. Hah.
You're supposed to protect them from us.
They protect us from you.
Don't make sense.
You and Bonnie first.
Now, get right in there, now.
Go on. Friendly, like, you know.
When his Texas Ranger friends see
this, he's gonna wish he was dead.
Well, we're mighty proud to have
a Texas Ranger in the family.
Hold it, hold it.
How's this?
Oh, good, good, good. I'm getting it,
I'm getting it. Wait. Hold it. Duncanville!
How about that?
You has--
Hold on, now.
- Wet him down.
- I got the picture.
I got-- I got--
I got the picture.
- I got it! I got the--
- Ah!
I got the picture! I got the--
Oh, no.
We're gonna put that picture
in every paper in the country!
We got you! We got you.
We got you now. We got you.
Hey! We got you.
You just stay in there for a while.
- I got the picture. Ha-ha-ha!
- We'll use that picture.
We got you. We got--
We used you, boy.
- We got you!
- Come on.
Damn it.
Ahem. Good afternoon.
This is the Barrow Gang.
Now if everybody will just
take it easy, nobody will get hurt.
- Is that your money or the bank's?
- Mine.
All right, you keep it, then.
Next time I'll aim a little lower.
All right.
Let's go.
Take a good look, Pop.
I'm Buck Barrow.
We're the Barrow boys!
Come on!
Happy birthday, hon.
It was the Barrow Gang, Charlie.
I think they was headed for Oklahoma.
Mommy, come!
Mommy, come! Now!
Load this!
There I was, staring square
into the face of death.
And all I can say is
they did right by me...
...and I'm bringing me a mess of flowers
to their funeral.
Slow down, Clyde,
we're in Oklahoma now.
Whew.
Come on, let's catch them, anyway.
I ain't gonna risk my life in Oklahoma.
- Ain't much, is it?
- Well, times is hard.
Well, let's get down to it.
Mr. Buck.
Bonnie Parker.
C.W. Moss. Huh?
Oh.
I want my share.
If Bonnie gets a share,
I want a share too.
- What are you talking about?
- Tell Clyde I want my share.
All right. All right.
Clyde, uh,
what about Blanche here?
What?
Well, why not?
Well, why not? I earned my share
same as everybody.
I could have got killed same as everybody.
I'm wanted by the law same as everybody.
Well, besides I could have got snake-bit
sleeping in them woods every night.
I'm a nervous wreck
and that's the truth...
...and I have to take sass
from Miss Bonnie Parker all the time.
- I deserve mine!
- Hold on. Hold your horses.
Blanche, you gonna get your share.
Here.
I married the preacher's daughter and she
thinks she's still taking up the collection.
- Mrs. Buck Barrow.
- Thank you.
Now, honey, don't spend it
all in one place.
Hey.
Listen now. Honey, I guess
I'm gonna have to keep saying this.
Blanche is married to Buck,
and Buck is family.
My family could use some of that money.
Them laws been hanging around your
mama's house. It's too risky to go up now.
But where can we go now? We rob
the damn banks. What else do we do?
- Well, what you wanna do?
- Clyde. Clyde, there's a hole in the pan.
We're losing oil. We gotta swipe another
car if we wanna get anywhere. Look.
Huh?
Stop that now.
No, Eugene.
Eugene.
Come on!
Stop that, Eugene.
Say, isn't that your car, Eugene?
That's my car.
Hey.
That's my car! Hey!
That's my car!
- Hey, they're coming after us.
- Come on, kick in the pants.
I'm gonna tear them apart.
Those punks.
Stealing a man's car.
Wait till I get my hands
on those kids, Velma.
I'm gonna tear them apart.
What if they have guns, Eugene?
Listen, we better get the police
and let them handle this.
- Right.
- All right, now, turn around.
Turn around and let's go back to town,
and we'll go get the sheriff.
They stopped chasing us.
They're turning around there.
- Let's take them.
- Good idea, Clyde.
Oh, my Lord, they're coming after us.
Step on it, Velma.
Velma, step on it, Velma.
- Step on it, Velma.
- I am!
What do you wanna do that for, Clyde?
Step on it, Velma. Step on it, Velma.
- Come on!
- Velma, step on it, Velma.
Velma!
- Howdy.
- Hey. Hey, what are you doing in there?
Hey. Ain't it hot in there?
- How are y'all?
- Hey, look what we got here.
All right, get on out of there.
Come on, come on.
You wanna go for a little ride
in our new car? Ah.
- Oh, my, can we all fit in there?
- Come on.
- I get to ride up front now. Finally.
- Come on. Come on. Come on.
- There's not room for me in there.
- You all right?
What's your names?
I'm Eugene-- I'm Eugene Grizzard.
And I'm Velma Davis.
We're the Barrow Gang.
That there's Clyde driving, I'm Buck,
that's my wife Blanche, Bonnie Parker, C.W.
Oh, now listen, y'all, don't be scared.
It ain't like you was the law or anything.
- I mean, you're just folks, just like us.
- Yeah.
Yeah, that's the truth.
I expect you've been reading about us.
- Oh, no.
- Yeah.
Yes.
We have too.
Well, now, you two
must be in love, I bet, huh?
Now, boy, when you
gonna marry the girl?
- Buck.
- Ha-ha-ha.
So he gave her the milk, see,
and she drank a little of it.
The next day, he gave her some more and
she drank some more till one week goes by.
And he brings her the milk and
she drinks down every drop of it.
She looks at her son,
calls him over and says:
"Son, whatever you do...
...don't sell that cow."
"Don't sell the cow."
I'm from Wisconsin originally.
Where the cheese comes from.
Oh, oh, but he just loves Texas now.
Don't you, Eugene?
"Don't sell that cow."
Hey, how old are you, honey?
I'm 33.
- There you go.
- Thanks, Buck.
Now-- Now didn't I
order some French fries?
Yeah, you did. Here you are.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Now take it easy on them French fries,
Velma. Ain't that right, Eugene?
This isn't mine.
I ordered mine well-done.
Who's got the other hamburger?
Oh, is this supposed to be yours?
It's okay. Forget it.
I'm sure having a good time.
Aren't you glad we picked you up?
- You're a grand host, Buck.
- Yeah.
Maybe y'all ought to join up with us.
Boy, they sure would be surprised
to hear that back home.
What would--? What would Bill
and Martha say if they heard that?
Lordy, they would have a fit.
Hey, what do you do, anyhow?
I'm an undertaker.
Get them out of here.
Bonnie!
- Bonnie!
- Bonnie.
I don't see her, Clyde.
Bonnie, where are you?
Bonnie!
Ahh. Bonnie!
- Where do you think she could have went?
- Boy, I don't know. I just don't know.
There! Bonnie!
Bonnie!
Bonnie.
- Bonnie.
- Leave me alone!
- Where are you going?
- Get away!
- Bonnie. Honey.
- Oh-- Oh!
I want-- I wanna see my mama.
I wanna see my mama.
Please, honey, don't ever leave me
without saying nothing.
All right.
But-- No, but Clyde, listen to me.
Clyde, please.
Now listen to me, I mean it.
I been thinking about my mama...
...and she's getting so old
and I wanna see her. Please, Clyde.
- Please.
- We'll see her.
We'll see her.
Well, would you look at him?
He just don't remember me.
He'll get used to me, won't he?
We've been cutting and pasting
everything we could find about you.
Hey, hey, Clyde,
there's the shot I took of you.
It turned out real fine, didn't it, huh?
Oh, Lord, we thank thee
for the safety of our loved ones...
...and the food we are
about to receive. Amen.
- Bye, Clyde.
- Bye-bye.
Y'all be careful.
We're gonna miss you, now.
Where you all headed to
from here, Clyde?
At this point we ain't heading to
nowhere. We just running from.
Clyde.
Tom, we're going home.
Little Tom.
Matthew, fetch little Tom.
Mama. Listen.
Mama, why don't you stay
a little while longer, huh? Okay?
Listen, I want you to have this.
- Come on, boys.
- Come on, we gotta go home.
Clyde? Sugar, listen, make Mama
stay a while yet, huh?
You know, Clyde,
I read about you all in the papers...
...and I just get scared.
Now, Mrs. Parker, don't you believe
what you read in all them newspapers.
That's the laws talking there.
They want us to look big so
they can look big when they catch us.
They won't catch us. I'm even better
at running than I am at robbing banks. Heh.
Shoot, if we done half that stuff
they say we done...
...we'd be millionaires by now.
Yeah.
I ain't gonna risk my little girl
just to make money...
...uncertain as times are.
Why, I BUCK LAUGHS of a job...
You remember the time?
Why, we could have gotten $2000..
...just as easy as pie.
And I pulled up outside there
and I saw them laws...
...and I said to myself, I said,
"Bonnie could get hurt here."
So we just drove right on
and I let that money lay.
Maybe you know the way with her, then.
I'm just an old woman.
- I don't know nothing.
- Mrs. Parker.
But Mrs. Parker, this here is the
way we know best how to make money.
We gonna quit this as soon as
hard times are over, I can tell you that.
Why, just the other night,
me and Bonnie were talking...
We were talking about the time we were
gonna settle down and get us a home.
She says to me, she says,
"You know, I couldn't bear...
...to live more than three miles
from my precious mother."
Now, how'd you like that,
Mother Parker?
I don't believe I would.
I surely don't.
You try to live three miles from me
and you won't live long, honey.
You best keep running, Clyde Barrow.
And you know it.
Bye,baby.
- Goodbye, y'all.
- Bye.
Look, who is this there?
Is that your girlfriend? Hmm?
L-O-V-E.
Well, whose idea was it
to get bluebirds?
- Bonnie's. Bonnie picked it out.
- Bonnie?
Day after we robbed the armory.
Hey, hon, come over here.
I want you to touch something here.
- No.
- I want you just to touch it right there.
Go on, now.
Sweet and sour!
Why don't you all
go into your own cabin...
...if you wanna play with C.W.?
What's the matter with you,
besides your nasty disposition?
- Let me handle it.
- No. Why does she have to wait'?
Hold on. Hold on!
I saw a chicken place a few miles back.
Who all wants to get some food?
I certainly do. I'm sick to death
of sitting around.
- You can't even drive the car.
- I'll go. What do y'all want?
Just get us five chicken dinners.
Hey, get some dessert there too, some
peach ice cream or something, will you?
Oh, baby, I got the blues so bad.
Yeah.
Well, is it what your mama said?
What mama?
She's just an old woman now.
I don't have no mama.
No family either.
Hey, I'm your family.
You know, when we started out...
...I thought we was
really going somewhere.
But this is it.
We're just going, huh?
I love you.
- You sure are smoking a lot lately.
- So what?
Nothing.
Oh, Lord.
Why don't you go back
to your pa's house?
If I only could.
If I could only just do that one thing.
There's no telling
how all this happened.
I was a preacher's daughter.
- What church was your pa affiliated with?
- Baptist.
He thought the world of Buck,
my daddy did.
Even though Buck
was serving time in jail.
He forgave him
because he paid his debt to society.
We were Disciples of Christ.
Hey, I ain't got no money.
Give me some, will you?
Get me Sheriff Smoot on the phone.
Yeah.
That's more like it.
Look how much better
it fits since I took it up.
The men are on the other side.
All right, let go.
C.W., C.W., grenades.
Hold it, hold it!
Get out!
Wait, Buck!
Bring your fire around there.
- No!
- Oh!
Get on!
Give me a gun, please!
I don't have a gun.
- Listen to me.
- Get down. Stop that. You going crazy?
Oh, no!
Please be quiet! Please be quiet!
We're trying to get out.
It didn't happen, Daddy.
It didn't happen. I know it--
- Blanche, stop that!
- You stop it!
I'd rather go to jail
than go on like this.
He ain't got a chance.
Half his head's blown off.
- Here we go.
- Oh, God. Oh, God.
Dear Lord, it happened.
Please help us.
And Buck will never do anything
wrong again in his life.
My eyes!
I think I'm blind.
MY eyes!
The light hurts so bad!
- The light hurts so bad!
- Here, hon, here.
There.
- Tell Clyde to get us to a doctor.
- Shh.
Bonnie! We are dying!
Buck can't be moved now, hon. Shh.
- Clyde! Clyde! Clyde.
- I'm right here, boy.
I believe I lost my shoes, Clyde.
I think the dog got them.
Surrender!
- Buck, in the car.
- Surrender!
Come on, keep low!
Hey, Clyde, we're going this way.
Crossfire! Keep low! Crossfire.
Move up!
Charlie, don't shoot!
The kids are in the crossfire!
- I'll go get the car. I'll get the car.
- Buck.
Now, Buck, this way.
- Come out through here.
- Buck!
They're heading for the other car!
Shoot it! Knock the hell out of it!
Hold your fire!
Daddy, don't die!
- Hold your fire!
- Leave him alone.
He's dying. Can't you see he's dying?
You gotta let me go! Daddy!
You killed him! He's dying!
God, can't you see him dying?
Daddy. Don't. Daddy!
Don't! Oh, Daddy.
Daddy!
- Maybe--
- Shh!
Shh.
Can you all
spare us some drinking water?
- Who are you, boy?
- My name is Moss.
That's Clyde Barrow and Bonnie Parker.
What happened to them?
Hush.
Are they famous?
- Is that really Bonnie Parker?
- Yeah.
Daddy! Daddy!
- Who's there? Huh?
- C.W.
- Clarence.
Oh, it's good to see you, boy.
Oh, boy, it's good to see you.
- What's that on your chest?
- A tattoo, Daddy. Come on.
Come on.
- You gotta help them.
- Huh?
Help me get them in.
What happened to them?
Are you in trouble, son?
Clyde Barrow and Bonnie Parker.
Come on. Help me get them in.
How come you marked yourself
all up with that tattoo?
What the hell made you do
a damn fool thing like that?
- You hear me?
- Just open the door, Daddy.
I come here to question Blanche Barrow.
- So you're the Frank Hammer, huh?
- Hammer.
I figure to have my picture
took with them two...
...just one more time.
It says here Clyde fled
his dying brother.
What do they mean, fled?
How could I leave my brother to die
when he was already dead when I left him?
Fled!
Newspapers.
While we're around here near dead...
...they said we held up
the Grand Prairie National Bank.
Guess they hung that
one on us just for luck.
I'll tell you, as soon as we get well, we
gonna hold up that bank! We gonna take it!
They don't know nothing, do they, honey?
Hey, how come they're always
referring to me, the newspapers, as...
-...unidentified suspect?
- You just be glad that's all you are.
Long as they don't know your last name.
That's right, boy. Mr. Barrow's
looking out for your interests.
Hey,Pa.Heh.
How does it feel to have a couple
of big deals stay in your house?
That's something for me, ain't it?
You've been mighty nice to us.
And I want you to let us pay you,
say, $40 for your hospitality.
No, no. no. I'm just happy to
have y'all folks here as company.
Anybody's a friend of
my boy, you know, l...
Come on, let's go have some supper.
I'm starving.
Y'all are welcome here.
You know that.
And you just make yourself right at
home and stay as long as you want to.
You look like trash,
all marked up like that.
Cheap trash!
Bonnie says it looks good.
What does Bonnie know? She ain't
nothing but cheap trash herself.
Look what they do.
Don't ever get your name in the paper.
You just get them pictures printed
on your skin by Bonnie and Clyde.
Shoot, they ain't nothing
but a couple of kids.
- But, Daddy...
- I'm so glad your ma ain't alive...
...to see this here thing. Hah!
- All jellied up like that!
- Ah!
I don't see what's so bad about it.
You wouldn't.
All right, I'll go.
Look, the word is out that Bonnie and
Clyde are holed up just out of town.
And they're fixing to bust in here
and take Blanche out. So...
All two of them?
- Blanche Barrow.
- Ahh!
Who is it?
I guess it's been kind of
rough on you, hasn't it?
Being the daughter of a preacher,
like you are.
I imagine old Buck wasn't
a bad sort, was he?
No, he wasn't.
I reckon...
...Clyde just sort of...
...led him astray, didn't he?
That's a shame, Blanche.
Yes, ma'am. That's a shame.
They done led your Buck astray.
Clyde, his own brother...
...Bonnie.
And that little feller.
The one that was with you when you
took that Texas Ranger in Missouri.
He was with you all along, wasn't he?
C.W.
That's right, C.W.
I, uh...
I don't recollect his last name.
Moss.
C.W. Moss.
He was there that day we met them.
I didn't wanna go. I didn't want to.
And Buck said we was just
going on a visit...
...and we wouldn't
do no stealing or robbing.
And we went up to Joplin,
and all of a sudden...
All of a sudden...
...they all just started shooting.
What you writing?
I'm writing a poem about us.
- Yeah? Let me hear it.
- Mm-hm.
- Come on.
- Okay. Just let me finish this line.
Um... It's called
"The Story of Bonnie and Clyde."
You've heard the story of Jesse James
Of how he lived and died.
If you're still in need
Of something to read
Here's the story of Bonnie and Clyde.
You think if I sent that into
the newspapers, they'd print it?
I'm gonna do it.
Now Bonnie and Clyde are the Barrow Gang
I'm sure you all have read.
How they rob and steal
And those who squeal
Are usually found dying or dead.
They call them cold-Smoot killers
They say they are heartless and mean
But I say this with pride
That I once knew Clyde
When he was honest
And upright and clean.
But the laws fooled around
Kept taking him down
And locking him up in a cell.
Till he said to me, "I'll never be free
So I'll meet a few of them in hell."
if a policeman is killed in Dallas
And they have no clue to guide.
If they can't find a fiend,
They just wipe their slate clean
And hang it on Bonnie and Clyde
If they try to act like citizens
And rent them a nice little flat
About the third night
They're invited to fight
By a sub-gun's rat-a-tat-tat.
Someday they'll go down together
They'll bury them side by side.
To few it'll be grief
To the law a relief
But it's death for Bonnie and Clyde.
You know what you done there?
You told my story.
You told my whole story right there.
Right there.
One time I told you I was gonna make you
somebody. That's what you done for me.
You made me somebody
they gonna remember.
Damn.
- Hey, how you feel?
- Fine.
You feel the way you're supposed to feel
when you--? After--?
- Yeah, just.
- Mm-hm.
Well, that's-- That's good, isn't it?
Look, I-- I figure
it's a good idea to ask...
...because how else are
you gonna know if it...?
Hey. You did just perfect.
I did, didn't I?
I mean, I really did.
I never figured on that. Damn.
Clyde, now why do you wanna marry me?
To make an honest woman out of you.
What would you do...?
What would you do
if some miracle happened...
...and we could walk out of here
tomorrow morning...
...and start all over again clean...
...with no record and nobody after us?
Hmm?
Well...
I guess I'd do it all different.
First off...
...I wouldn't live in the same state
where we pull our jobs.
I mean, we'd live in another state
and stay clean there.
And then when we wanted to take
a bank, we'd go into the other state.
Huh?
Bonnie?
Bonnie.
Boy, did they expect you to go
downtown with them tomorrow?
Who?
Bonnie and Clyde, that's who.
Sure, I always go with them.
Yeah.
Yeah, you'd better. You'd better go.
But when they go to get in their car
to come on home...
-...don't get back in there with them.
- Why, Daddy?
You listen to your pa for once,
can you do that?
I'm your pa, I'm your kin!
Not that there Clyde Barrow.
What do you want me to tell them,
"I can't get back in the car with you"?
You tell them nothing, you hear?
I made a deal and got you off
with a couple of years.
You just be sure that you're
off the streets in that town...
...when they go to get in their car.
You think laws are gonna
catch Bonnie and Clyde in town?
Clyde's got a sense.
Don't you know that, Daddy?
Nobody catches Clyde. Never.
Never!
What happened to C.W.?
He's over there in the hardware store
getting some light bulbs for his daddy.
- Huh. You gonna wear them like that?
- Drive with one eye closed.
- Want some ice cream?
- No.
Look here. Isn't that just
the prettiest thing you ever saw?
Look, you see, you can see
every fingernail of her hand. Look.
That's the prettiest thing.
Hey, where is that boy?
Listen, I'll go get him, okay?
Gladys Jean!
Time to go home now.
We'll get back there in about 20 minutes
and we'll pick him up.
I tell you, if that boy didn't have
his head strapped on him, he'd lose it.
Hey, isn't that Malcolm there?
What you got there?
I got a flat tire. I ain't got no spare.
Hey.