Turn him over.
Oh, no!
"Do not drink wine nor strong drink...
"thou, nor thy sons with thee...
"lest ye shall die.
"Look not thou upon the wine
when it is red...
"and when it bringeth his color
in the cup, when it moveth itself aright.
"At the last it biteth like a serpent...
"and stingeth like an adder."
Now, folks...
that's from the Good Book...
but in this here town...
it's five cents a glass.
Five cents a glass.
Does anyone really think
that that is the price of a drink?
The price of a drink? Let him decide...
who has lost his courage and his pride...
who lies a groveling
heap of clay not far removed...
All's quiet, sir.
Let's fall in.
Follow me.
I beg your pardon, ma'am.
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- Allow me, ma'am.
Thank you.
May I?
Thornton, wake up! Soldiers!
Take a look.
I don't care what you meant to do...
it's what you did I don't like.
You inconvenienced this lady,
and made a fool of yourself...
and this railroad in the bargain.
Now, I want you to apologize to this...
Yes, sir, can I help you?
If they move, kill them.
Is he with them?
He's there.
Hold your fire! Get down!
Wait till they come out.
I can nail him.
I said, wait!
What if they slip out the back way?
It's covered.
You two-bit redneck peckerwood.
Abe?
I solemnly promise...
God helping me...
"I solemnly promise, God helping me."
...to abstain from all distilled,
fermented malt liquors...
including wine, beer and cider.
"To abstain from liquor,
wine, cider and beer."
People marching and singing,
coming down the street.
They're gonna pass by the horses.
We'll join them.
The Temperance Union?
They should have been told.
Told what?
How long do you think
anybody in this manure pile...
could keep his mouth shut?
Yes, we'll gather at the river
The beautiful, beautiful river
Gather with the saints at the river
Rifles.
One?
No, three!
Maybe more, there, on the roof.
Get down.
Son of a bitch!
- Lyle, Dutch.
- What are they, bounty hunters?
Hell, I wouldn't know.
Buck, with Abe.
- I kill them now?
- No.
Hold them here as long as you can
until after the shooting starts.
I'll hold them till hell freezes over
or you say different.
When I kick him out, blast them.
We'll make a run for it.
C.L., give me that shotgun.
The beautiful, beautiful river
Gather with the saints at the river
That flows by the throne of God
Set?
Let's go!
Good luck, boys!
They're blowing this town all to hell!
You're trash!
Now, you just hush now.
They was playing Gather at the River.
You know that one?
Sing it!
Shall we gather at the river
Where bright angel feet have trod
Hurry!
River that flows by the throne of God
Come on, you lazy bastard!
I'm coming, damn it!
They've cleared out, for Christ's sake!
Let's go, T. C!
Put some more on!
Let's go!
Take him!
He's mine!
- He's mine!
- Mr. Harrigan.
He's mine!
I shot this one!
Look at the size of that hole!
You just dig out that bullet
and see if it ain't my.06!
You know I shot him.
You'd claim the whole thing,
wouldn't you?
- Daddy! Daddy!
- Did he have any money?
Damn, I can't get his belt off!
You stupid, damn fools!
Why did you shoot this employee
and let the others get away?
I didn't shoot that employee!
My first shot killed this man right here!
Liar!
He shot that employee while I was
dropping this bandit and them others, too.
I must've killed all three of them.
Killed all three of them?
What were we doing up on that roof?
Liar! Black liar!
You shouldn't talk like that to me.
I'm sorry.
Come on, T.C., help me get his boots.
I think this will do pretty good.
Harrigan!
Next time, you better plan the massacre
more carefully, or I'll start with you.
Why didn't you kill Pike
when you had the chance?
Stop!
Feathers flew like a turkey!
They shouldn't have run.
Say!
How'd you like to kiss
my sister's black cat's ass?
This is better than a hog-killing!
Get them out of here!
We're holding you and your whole damn
railroad responsible for this carnage!
- Mr. Benson...
- Innocent people are dead!
Women dying and mangled because
you used our town as a battlefield!
You're going to pay! The railroad
is going to pay for our loss of blood!
We were trying to catch
a band of outlaws!
You lured that gang in here!
The railroad has been blabbing their
mouth about a big payload for weeks!
We represent the law!
Pike, is that you?
I can ride, Pike.
I can ride.
I can't see, but I can ride.
God!
No!
I can't ride.
Finish it.
You boys want to move on,
or stay and give him...
a decent burial?
He was a good man.
I think we ought to bury him.
He's dead!
He's got a lot of good men back there
to keep him company!
Too damn many!
I think the boys are right.
I'd like to say a few words for the dear,
dead departed.
Maybe a few hymns'd be in order!
Followed by a church supper...
with a choir!
You crazy bastards, both of you!
Bishop, Engstrom, the Gorch brothers!
Amounts to a total of $4,500
and you let them ride out on you!
When the hard-money value
of the men you killed...
less my commission, adds up to $500!
Any one of those pelts would've
not only cleared you with the company...
but given you a bundle of money
to raise hell with!
We'll do better next time!
We'll do anything you say, but we sure
would appreciate liquor money for tonight.
There won't be any tonight!
You go after them in ten minutes!
Get them! Get Pike and you'll be rich!
If one of you tries to quit on me...
I'll pay a bonus of $1,000...
to the man that kills him!
Let's pack it up then!
- Mr. Harrigan.
- Why should I let you go with them?
We've been over that.
You might run off with them.
Might even join them again.
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
What I like and what I need
are two different things.
Listen, Mr. Harrigan.
I don't want to go back to prison,
never again.
But it's got to be my way!
I need some good men!
You saw what happened
out there this morning!
You'll use what you have and you'll see
to it that it doesn't happen again...
or I'll see you spend the rest of your life
behind bars.
Try to run,
I'll be after you and so will they.
I gave you my word.
Well, we'll see what it's worth!
Six minutes.
Tell me, Mr. Harrigan, how does it feel...
getting paid for it?
Getting paid to sit back and hire your
killings with the law's arms around you?
How's it feel to be so goddamn right?
Good.
You dirty son of a bitch!
You've got 30 days to get Pike
or 30 days back to Yuma.
You're my Judas goat, Mr. Thornton.
I want all of them back here,
head down over a saddle.
Thirty days to get Pike
or 30 days back to Yuma.
I don't see nothing so lindo about it.
Just looks like more of Texas
as far as I'm concerned.
You have no eyes.
Got a half-hour of light. Let's go.
Hello, little fella.
- Them other fellas...
- They're not coming!
- None of them?
- No.
- But I got horses and saddles for them.
- We'll need them, they won't.
Now, about the sharing up.
The sharing up will be the same as always.
Well, me and Tector don't think that
he ought to get the same amount.
He's just starting out, and this is mine
and Tector's opening for a new territory.
That's right.
And I figure a share to that old goat
for watching them horses...
is damn sure a share too much.
So, we decided...
it ain't fair.
If you two boys don't like equal shares,
why in the hell don't you just take all of it?
Well, why don't you answer me,
you damned, yellow-livered trash?
Now, Pike, you know damn well...
I don't know a damned thing except that
I either lead this bunch or end it right now.
All right.
We divide it up just like you say.
Chick, chick, chick, chick.
Silver rings.
Silver rings, your butt!
Them's washers! Damn!
Bastards!
Washers!
We shot our way out of that town
for a dollar's worth of steel holes!
They set it up!
They? Who in the hell is "they"?
"They?"
Why, "they" is just plain and fancy "they."
That's who "they" is.
Caught you, didn't they?
Tied a tin can to your tail!
Led you in and waltzed you out again!
Oh, my, what a bunch!
Big tough one!
Here you are with a handful of holes,
a thumb up your ass...
and a big grin to pass
the time of day with.
"They!"
Who the hell is "they"?
Railroad men.
Bounty hunters.
Deke Thornton.
Deke Thornton?
He was one of them?
How the hell come you didn't know that?
Hey, gringo.
You can have my silver.
Come on, gringo, don't kill me.
You can have the silver.
But don't kill me.
Please?
Go on...
go for it.
Fall apart.
Walk softly, boys.
What's our next move?
I figure Agua Verde is the closest.
Three days, maybe.
We'll get the news and drift to the border.
Maybe a payroll, maybe a bank.
Maybe that damn railroad!
That damn railroad you're talking
about sure as hell ain't getting no easier.
And you boys ain't getting
any younger, either.
We gotta start thinking beyond our guns.
Those days are closing fast.
All your fancy planning and talking
damn near got us shot to pieces...
over a few lousy bags of washers.
Well, this was going to be me and Tector's
last job before we quit and headed south!
We spent all our time and money
getting ready for this!
You spent all your time and money
running whores in Hondo...
while I spent my stake setting it up!
Hell, I should have been running whores
instead of stealing army horses!
While you was doing all that planning...
me and Tector was getting
our bell rope pulled by two...
two, mind you, Hondo whores!
And Pike was dreaming of washers!
He was.
You were matching whores...
in tandem!
What's that?
That's one behind the other.
That's right! That's what we was doing!
Mr. Thornton?
You rode with Pike.
What kind of man are we up against?
The best.
He never got caught.
This was going to be my last.
Ain't getting around any better.
I'd like to make one good score
and back off.
Back off to what?
Have you got anything lined up?
Pershing's got troops spread out
all along the border.
Every one of those garrisons
are gonna be getting a payroll.
That kind of information is kind of hard
to come by.
I didn't say it's going to be easy,
but it can be done.
He'll be waiting for us.
I wouldn't have it any other way.
Come on, Pike, let's go.
You sound like you're all caught up.
Caught up enough to know
we've overstayed our welcome.
What the hell's the matter with you?
We've got plenty of money to spend,
and not a worry in the world.
They're not going to look for us
in their own backyard.
How can you be so damn sure?
Being sure is my business.
- Hold it!
- Relax.
It's just some champagne we ordered.
Relax. It's just some champagne
we ordered.
Being sure is my business.
Did you get him?
No, the bastard got away.
Damn, you sure must have hurt
that railroad.
They spent a lot of money
setting up that ambush.
I caught up with them.
Two or three times.
There was a man named Harrigan.
He used to have a way of doing things.
I made him change his ways.
And a hell of a lot of people...
that just can't stand to be wrong.
Pride.
And they can't forget it.
That pride, being wrong, or learn by it.
How about us, Pike?
You reckon we learned...
being wrong today?
I sure hope to God we did.
Them's hot.
Damn!
Where in the hell did you ever find him?
He used to run with Thornton and me.
Did his share of killing, and more.
Around Langtry.
Yeah, only now he does his killing
with a coffee cup.
Pike...
I wouldn't have it any other way either.
Watch out, boys!
Go on, easy.
Watch it, Tector!
That goddamned son of a bitch!
Get those horses up!
What the hell is going...
Damned old punk! Bastard!
Get up now! Get up there, goddamn it!
Get over here!
What in the hell's the matter with you,
old man?
Leave him alone!
He's going to get us all killed!
I'm going to get rid of him.
You're not getting rid of anybody! We're
gonna stick together, like it used to be.
When you side with a man,
you stay with him.
And if you can't do that,
you're like some animal!
You're finished!
We're finished! All of us!
Mount up.
Appears Brother Pike needs help,
Brother Lyle.
That Brother Pike and the old man Sykes...
makes a man wonder if it ain't time...
to pick up his chips
and find another game.
How in the hell are you going
to side anybody...
when you can't even get on your horse?
That was a mighty fine talk you gave the
boys back there about sticking together.
That Gorch came near killing me.
Or me him.
Damned old fool like me's
not worth taking along!
- We started together, we'll end it together.
- By God, that's the way I see it.
That's the way it's always been with me.
Sorry about Deke.
I never figured him that way.
Say, back there in Starbuck...
how did my boy do?
Your boy?
Crazy Lee?
Yes, C.L., Clarence Lee.
My daughter's boy.
Not too bright, but a good boy.
I kill them now? I kill them now?
No, you just hold them here.
Hold them here.
Why didn't you tell me
he was your grandson?
You had enough things on your mind.
Besides, he had to pull his own weight
just like the rest of us.
I just wanted to make sure he didn't
let you down, run, when things got hot.
No, he did fine.
Just fine.
All clear!
From here on it's Mexico, Mr. Thornton.
What's the closest town of any size?
Agua Verde.
What's in Agua Verde?
Mexicans, what else?
A headquarters for regulars
fighting against Villa.
Mapache territory.
Don't we follow?
No, we go back and wait.
- Damn it! Go find...
- Shut up!
Why in the hell won't you tell your folks
to feed them dogs?
Won't find very much around here.
That damn Huerta's scraped it clean.
I have invited you to my village,
to my home.
Any disrespect to my family
or to my people...
I will kill you.
Ashamed of having us meet your people?
Yes. They don't know about
my life when I leave the village.
- You got a sister?
- Yes.
I'd be proud to make her acquaintance.
And that of your mama too.
That goes for your grandma too, sonny.
How bad did they hit you?
Seven of the villagers were killed.
Two of them hung.
Our horses, cattle and corn, stolen.
What about the federal troops?
Didn't they give you any protection?
They were federal troops...
commissioned by the traitor, Huerta.
And the soldier who shot my father?
What was his name?
- What the hell difference does it make?
- Your father died like a man.
Names in this matter
do not have any importance.
How was he called?
Mapache.
That is name enough.
In Mexico, seńor...
these are the years of sadness.
But if we had...
rifles like these...
And Teresa? Did they molest her?
She went with them
because she wished to.
She became the woman of Mapache...
and the others.
She went with them, laughing.
Drunk with wine and love.
To him, Teresa was like a goddess,
to be worshipped from afar.
I tell you, she was a mango...
ripe and waiting.
Angel dreams of love
and Mapache eats the mango.
That's a good trick.
Now that I find hard to believe.
Not so hard.
We all dream of being a child again.
Even the worst of us.
Perhaps the worst most of all.
You know what we are, then?
Yes, just so, the both of you!
And you!
Where is Mapache?
All right, Pike? All right?
Tector, let's swap!
Come on, let's swap!
You must tell me. Where is Mapache?
Why do you wish to know?
For your father?
Or the whore?
Either you learn to live with it
or we'll leave you here.
I go with you, Jefe.
You know what I'm going to do?
I'm gonna steal his girl.
You are?
Here I go.
Dutch, I'm cutting in.
Come on, lady!
No gringos?
Only federales.
All soldiers.
Not a bounty hunter in sight.
Now, what in the hell is that?
I saw one just like it in Waco.
Run on steam?
No, on alcohol or gasoline.
Hey, Pike, you know what I hear?
I hear they got one of those things
up north that can fly.
That was a balloon, you damned old fool.
No, the old man's right.
They've got motors and wings
and go 60 miles in less than an hour.
Going to use them in the war they say.
Well, let's go and talk to the General...
about his automobile
and our extra horses.
Nice and easy.
Probably talking about us
behind our backs.
I'm down to about twenty in silver.
With the way the Generalísimo's
cleaned out this part of the country...
he ought to have a lot to spare.
Generalísimo, hell.
He's just another bandit
grabbing all he can for himself.
Like some others I could mention.
Not so as you'd know it, Mr. Bishop.
We ain't nothing like him.
We don't hang nobody.
I hope someday
these people here kick him...
and the rest of the scum like him
right into their graves.
We will.
If it takes forever!
Look here.
Pretty good-looking old pony, ain't he?
Boy, do you know them beauties?
Come on.
- She was my woman.
- I know.
Sure ain't your woman no more.
Just look at her licking
inside that general's ear.
Why did he try to kill His Excellency?
He didn't try to kill His Excellency.
He was after the girl.
He went a little crazy
when he saw her with you.
Are you men associated
with the American Army?
No, we're not associated with anybody.
I see.
I was curious about the equipment
which you are carrying. That pistol...
is restricted for the use
of army personnel.
It can't be purchased or even owned...
legally.
- Is that so?
- Weapons are a specialty of mine.
I am Commander Frederick Mohr
of the Imperial German Army.
It would be very useful for us
if we knew of some Americans...
who did not share their
government's naive sentiments.
Well, we share very few sentiments
with our government.
He's asking us to have a drink with him.
Good.
Shoot him.
I gave it to him, T.C.
- You mean here?
- No, no, not there!
Wait a minute, now,
what you going to do?
We got to show a little class here.
Right here!
It must be that garrison rail spur.
I know it's the easiest to hit, but I gotta
figure some way to get it out of there.
What do you think, Dutch?
Getting pretty close to home, ain't it?
Look at them gathered around
that big table.
Here we sit like kitchen help.
Why do you want us to hit a train
like that at the border?
Can't the General just go up there
and take over the whole thing?
General Huerta is anxious to better
relations with the United States...
not to cross the border and destroy them.
Usually these arms shipments
are kept pretty secret.
How'd you find out about this one?
Mapache has a superb intelligence force...
organized under supervision
of my commanding officer.
Now, gentlemen,
we are quite well organized...
and able to pay $10,000...
in gold.
Of course, if you're not able
to do the work, we'll find someone else.
We can do it. It's just that we're
going to need special equipment.
Do not worry.
Our accountant will
take care of everything.
General...
soon you will be the best-equipped
general in Mexico.
Well, look here...
ain't he the one?
To the host!
With your permission, I need a bath.
With my permission,
I think you all need a bath.
I don't need no bath!
What me and Tector need is a couple
of them women you're hogging.
You think you can fix that up for us?
Gentlemen, you will excuse me, I'm sure.
I'm sure.
- Herrera.
- Let's get Angel.
Por favor, General, I need him.
I'll give you someone
much better than that.
If you don't mind, I'll make my own choice.
All right.
He is not important to me. Take him.
I think we're gonna get on the wagon now.
Hey, here come our sweeties.
Ain't them pretty?
I don't know about yours, Lyle, but...
I think I got more than I can handle.
Hey, get out of there.
You know what they told me?
The dons of Spain built this
over 300 years ago.
- Is that right?
- That's right.
I tell you, Lyle, I'm all for them dons.
Let's have a little target.
She ain't going to get away.
Turn her loose.
Why not!
Tector, look at them beauties!
How in the hell can you stand it that hot?
I'm going to build me one of these
some day and live in it.
Hell, Lyle, look here.
Come on, sweetheart,
let me see your teatsies.
I don't know why the hell
I didn't let them kill you.
Listen, I'm not going to steal guns for
that devil to rob and kill my people again.
Noble, noble. Very noble.
I didn't see no tears rolling down your
cheeks when you rode in from Starbuck.
They were not my people.
I care about my people, my village.
Listen, boy, you ride with us,
your village don't count.
If it does, you just don't go along.
Then I don't go along.
Angel, one load of guns ain't going
to stop them raiding villages.
Why, you ought to be thinking about
all the money you're gonna have.
Buy them a ranch. Move them 1,000 miles.
- Buy them two or three ranches.
- One.
A very small one.
Don't you see? This is their land.
No one is going to drive them away.
I'll drink to that sentiment.
And to love.
But most of all, I'll drink to gold!
Angel.
You're a pain in the ass.
Would you give guns to someone
to kill your father...
or your mother, or your brother?
Ten thousand cuts an awful lot
of family ties.
My people have no guns.
But with guns...
my people could fight.
If I could take guns...
I would come with you.
Say, how many cases of rifles
did Zamorra say was in that shipment?
Sixteen.
Well...
give him one.
All right.
One case and one case of ammo.
But you give up your share of the gold.
I will.
- We know you will.
- Sure glad we got that settled.
Why, you reprobate!
Boys...
I want you to meet my fiancée.
They just got engaged.
I'm a son of a bitch!
Trot them on in, fellas.
I'm hell on packing mules,
but I'm a delight with a pretty girl.
You want to gamble everything
that this one shipment will be attacked?
If they're in Agua Verde, they'll try for it.
- If? What about Juarez?
- If he was, we would've heard about it.
If they are in Agua Verde,
they will have seen Mapache.
And who in the hell is Mapache?
A killer for Huerta who
calls himself a general.
He's been fighting Villa and losing.
But with enough guns, he could become
a power in northern Mexico.
My guess is,
Pike will try to get them for him.
How can he? The train will be guarded
by regular troops.
Not regular troops,
green recruits not worth a damn.
I need 20 trained men, not recruits.
And not this
gutter trash you've given me.
What you've got is 24 more days.
Never told me how you got
all torn up like that.
I met a woman I wanted to marry.
- Is your husband coming back?
- No.
He's never coming back.
But you are late.
Two days late.
She had a husband.
If I'd had any sense, I'd have killed him.
He wasn't around.
I got careless.
One night, he walked in on us.
Got her with the first shot,
and got me here with the second.
Then the damn coward turned and ran.
Ever catch up with him?
No, but there isn't a day or an hour
that passes that I don't think about it.
Come on, pretty! We've got a long way!
This is our last go around, Dutch.
This time, we do it right.
Just do your work.
Let's go!
They're coming!
Faster!
Get over!
Get that ramp up!
Get that horse out of here!
Bring them all out! Get them out!
Get over here!
Get them over here! Get those horses!
Hurry up!
Your horse kicked me.
Run them up along here!
Where the hell is my horse?
Hey, we got grenades!
- Hurry up! We gotta get out of here!
- Be careful with this, boys!
Let's go on this.
Here we go.
All right, line up in a column of twos!
Corporal, give us a hand here!
Hey, Pike, we're all ready!
Let's go!
Come on!
Get after that horse!
That was my horse!
Get after him!
You men get out!
Get that damn horse off my butt!
Get those horses out of here!
The train's coming back!
Train?
- Where?
- What train?
I don't see any train.
Get the goddamn horse off my foot!
Corporal, ride back to the telegraph
at Todos Malos...
and tell the railroad deputies
they robbed the train...
and we're in pursuit!
Yes, sir!
Come on!
Dutch!
Damn son of a...
Come on! It's lit!
Get them horses going!
Don't shoot at the army, you idiots!
Come on, Pike!
Let's go!
Come on, you lazy bastard!
I'm coming, damn it!
- Is it all right?
- Yep.
Where are they supposed to meet us?
Agua Verde or before.
But when we do meet them,
don't expect any open arms.
Least we won't have to worry
about Deke Thornton.
Hell, no. Not after riding a half a case
of dynamite into the river.
Don't expect him to stay there.
He'll be along and you know it.
I sure would like to get hold
of that fool horse of mine.
Some Mex kid's probably riding him home
right now.
I don't see how I could've lost
both my boots.
They always were hard as hell to get on.
That damn river sucked them right off.
That damn dynamite helped some.
Maybe the same kid that's riding T.C.'s
horse is wearing your boots right now.
You stupid bastards!
Why did you fire at those soldiers?
Huey started firing at them.
I even tried to stop him.
- One of the bandits...
- Don't blame it on me!
Liar!
Shut your mouths!
Are we going after them?
We are,
unless you want to face a firing squad.
Come on, T. C!
Why the hell do we have to leave now?
Besides, my hair's wet!
Impossible! We have no arms
or ammunition.
The gringos assaulted the train!
They got the guns.
We must go!
Take the necessary people
and take the road to Agua Verde.
Convince the gringos to give you the guns.
I'll wait for you in the village.
If the gringos refuse?
He's still heading east.
Are they bluffing,
or did they really miss it?
I'd say they missed it. Here, take a look.
There's only five left.
- Hell, we lost them.
- I don't see how we lost them.
Unless it was in the big valley
where the ground was hard.
Wasn't but one way they could take
a wagon out of there, and this here is it.
They didn't take it out.
And we haven't lost them.
I could point to them right now.
Sit still, damn it!
You think Pike and old Sykes
haven't been watching us?
They know what this is all about.
And what do I have?
Nothing but you egg-sucking,
chicken-stealing gutter trash...
with not even 60 rounds between you.
We're after men.
And I wish to God I was with them.
The next time you make a mistake,
I'm gonna ride off and let you die.
Come on.
I never figured they'd come down here
after us.
How much you reckon we could be worth?
Depends on how hungry they are.
You better stay here
and look out for big hats.
I'll go down and
start rigging the fireworks.
All right.
Angel...
get that case of explosives
off the back there!
Lyle...
hand me down those blasting caps.
What're you gonna do with the dynamite?
I figure that damn general will try
to take this load without paying for it...
and shoot us in the bargain.
The only thing to change his mind
is if something happened to these guns.
I'm gonna make sure
something could happen.
Pike, take a look at this.
Think you can handle that?
What I don't know about,
I sure as hell am going to learn.
My people are here for their guns.
Where the hell were you when you were
supposed to be guarding us.
I never heard them, didn't even see them.
They apologize and ask you
to forgive them for their lack of trust.
But only by caution do they remain alive.
Tell them not to break that fuse.
These people from your village?
They are part of the village,
but not from it.
They are puro Indio and these mountains
belong to them.
I'd say those fellows know
how to handle themselves.
They've been fighting Apaches
for 1,000 years. That's a sure way to learn.
If they ever get armed, with good leaders,
this whole country will go up in smoke.
That it will, son. That it will.
They made damn fools out of us,
Mr. Bishop.
Getting so a fella can't sleep
with both eyes closed...
for fear of getting his throat cut.
Where in the hell were you?
Now, you listen to me, Lyle.
If you got up off your ass and helped
once in a while...
I wouldn't have got caught near so easy.
With the new guns and ammunition,
this could never have happened.
Swing your leaders wide, old man!
Bring them on!
Come on, horse!
- Hold up!
- Whoa there!
Mapache's?
Let's just hope they don't belong to Villa.
We are friends.
We are from el General Mapache.
Tell the one out in front
to come over here.
Alone.
I am coming.
I am your friend, remember?
We are friends. All of us.
I bring you love and affection
from el General.
You bring the guns with you?
What bravery you have done!
I am to escort you to the General.
- Tell him to come closer.
- I hear.
I am coming, my friend.
You know what this is?
Any trouble, no guns for the General.
Very smart!
That's very smart for you damn gringos.
So nobody can rob the guns.
Nobody.
I am not afraid. They are not afraid.
You blow up the wagon, you die.
Or we kill you pretty soon.
- But we are amigos.
- Show them, boys.
Start the ball, Tector.
Please, cut the fuse.
Please.
El General waits in Agua Verde
to meet with you.
Tell the General one of us
will be there to trade tomorrow.
Any trouble, no guns.
Damn gringos!
Get them up there, Freddie!
Pull them over!
You bring the guns?
Don't worry, we've got them.
Hidden.
When I get my share of the gold,
$2,500 worth...
I'll tell you where four cases are.
The others are waiting for me
back at the wagon.
If I don't show up pretty quick,
they'll blow it.
You fix it goddamn good, no?
You fooled me.
Our accountant will pay you immediately.
When do we get our guns?
The quicker I get back,
the quicker you get the next load.
Open it up.
Up the arroyo, about two miles...
you'll find three cases of rifles...
and one case of ammunition
hidden in the bush behind them.
I understand you have a machine gun.
Our contract called for 16 cases of rifles...
and ammunition for $10,000.
Not a machine gun.
That's our present to the General.
Gringo, you fight with Mapache...
I'll think about it.
In case he don't find them...
Go. I trust him.
- Why the hell don't you stir up some grub?
- Why don't you go to hell?
Shit!
Damn it!
Damn it, Pike must've found you
under a rock.
You gonna whip me?
Nope.
But you better just hope
I don't get riled enough...
to start dogging you when this is over.
You're not going to get a chance
to dry gulch me, old man.
We'll see.
Pike's coming!
He's got it. Carrying gold.
Any trouble?
Just from carrying this weight.
- Pike, I want to go next.
- All right.
You and your brother take the next load,
along with the machine gun.
Then Angel and Dutch. Freddie,
you follow and pick up the pack horses.
It must be mounted on a tripod!
Crazy bastards!
Put it on the tripod!
We brought the last of it, General.
At the head of the arroyo, in the wagon.
You can have the wagon,
we'll take the horses.
How many cases did you take
from the train?
Sixteen cases of rifles.
We lost one on the trail.
He stole it.
The mother of the girl he killed told me so.
Well, I'm wasting time here.
He's a thief. You take care of him.
Well, he had guts.
We're just lucky he didn't talk.
He played his string right out to the end.
Her own mama turned him in
like some kind of a Judas.
Sykes says we ought to go after him.
How in the hell are we gonna do that?
They got guns and 200 men.
No way.
No way at all.
Is that Sykes?
Mapache!
Thornton.
I got him.
They got Freddie.
Looks like he's hit pretty bad.
Damn that Deke Thornton to hell!
What would you do in his place?
He gave his word.
Gave his word to a railroad.
It's his word!
That ain't what counts!
It's who you give it to!
We can stay up here
and kick hell out of them!
That's what we can do.
No, we're running short of water.
Make a run for the border?
They'd follow us every step of the way.
I know Thornton.
I'm tired of being hunted.
Let's go back to Agua Verde.
Let the General take care of those boys.
You're crazy.
That general would just as soon kill us
as break wind.
He's so tickled with those guns...
he'll be celebrating for a week
and happy to do us a favor.
Thornton's not gonna follow us in there.
While they're busy picking over Freddie...
we'll find a back trail off this mountain
and head for town.
What about our gold?
We'll take one sack to pay our way.
Bury the rest.
Together.
Look out!
Lots of blood, then it stops. No track.
- $10 says he's dead by now.
- Take us a day to find him if he is.
If he isn't, he has a gun on us right now.
Let's go after the others.
Just leave him here? He's worth money.
Yes, you ride out tomorrow,
that is if you can stay on your horse...
and watch the buzzards.
They'll show you where he is.
What if he ain't dead, Mr. Thornton?
That's your problem. Let's go!
- God, I hate to see that.
- No more than I do.
Welcome, amigos!
You come for your friend, no?
I want to buy him back.
I don't think he looks worth too much.
I don't think he's going to live too long.
I'll give you half of my share for him.
I need no gold and I don't sell this one.
Why not? You've had your fun with him.
El Generalísimo's happy with the guns.
Why don't you go and get a drink?
Enjoy yourself.
There are women everywhere.
Don't be foolish and change his mood.
Son of a bitch!
Why not?
There ain't nobody here!
There's wagon tracks
and somebody was here!
They sure as hell ain't here now!
Army patrol!
Coming this way!
You said dos for two!
Here's your dos and one to grow on.
That's all you're gonna get out of me.
Let's go.
Why not?
What do you want?
We want Angel.
You want Angel, no? All right.
I'm going to give him to you.
Bitch!
Come on, you lazy bastard!
Give them hell, Pike!
No, Pike!
Pike.
Look at them.
- Come on.
- I'm coming.
Wait for me!
- Come on, let's get all the guns.
- This is fine!
This is just like a big old picnic!
Here's a rifle for you.
He's got a gun.
T.C., it's them!
It's the Gorches!
Get up there, Coffer. Come on.
Mr. Thornton, it's them.
It is them.
Here's a boy's got some gold in his teeth.
Let me see your knife.
- Here.
- Let me see your knife!
Mr. Thornton.
Should we load up?
Are we going to wait for Jess
or meet him on the way?
If he's waiting for them buzzards to lead
him to old Sykes, he's got a long wait.
Look! We got them all.
T.C., there he is.
There's Pike.
There, you ain't so damned much now,
are you, Mr. Pike?
You ain't coming?
No.
Maybe we ought to wait here for Jess.
No, we pick him up on the way.
I want to get out of this damn place.
Anyway, these boys'll start
going ripe on us by tomorrow.
We got to move.
I went to the river
and I couldn't get across
Singing 'polly wolly doodle'all the day
I jumped on a buzzard 'cause
I thought he was a horse
Singing 'polly wolly doodle'all the day
Fare thee well
- Didn't expect to find you here.
- Why not?
I sent them back.
- That's all I said I'd do.
- They didn't get very far.
I figured.
What are your plans?
Drift around down here.
Try to stay out of jail.
Well, me and the boys here...
we got some work to do.
You want to come along?
Ain't like it used to be, but it'll do.
English