Your son is arrived from London.
Father.
John.John.
You will see in my will...
...the estate of Norland
was left to me in such a way...
...as prevents me from dividing it
between my two families.
Calm yourself,
this cannot be good for you.
Norland, in its entirety...
...is therefore yours by law.
And I am happy for you and Fanny.
But your stepmother,
my wife and daughters...
...are left only 500 pounds a year.
Barely enough to live on.
Nothing for the girls' dowries.
You must help them.
Of course.
You must promise to do this.
I promise, Father.
I promise.
Help them? What do you mean?
I mean to give them 3000 pounds.
The interest will provide them
with a little extra income.
The gift will fulfil my promise.
Without question. More than amply.
One had rather, on such occasions,
do too much than too little.
Of course, he did not stipulate
a particular sum.
What do you say to 1500, then?
What brother would be so kind to his
real sisters, let alone half-blood?
They can hardly expect more.
The question is,
what can you afford?
A hundred pounds a year
to their mother, while she lives...
...is better than losing 1500 at once.
Should she live longer than 15 years
we'd be completely taken in.
People live forever
when an annuity is to be paid them.
Twenty pounds now and then
will discharge my promise.
- You're quite right.
- Indeed.
Although to say the truth,
I'm convinced...
...that your father had no idea
of giving them money.
- They will have 500 a year.
- What more could they want for?
Their housekeeping will be nothing.
They'll have no carriage, no horses,
hardly any servants...
...and keep no company.
Conceive how comfortable
they will be!
They will be much more able
to give you something.
Marianne,
can you play something else?
Mama has been weeping
since breakfast.
I meant something less mournful.
A visitor in my own home!
It is not to be borne, Elinor.
Mama, we have nowhere to go.
John and Fanny will be here soon.
Do you expect me to be here
to welcome them? Vultures!
I will start making enquiries
for a new house at once.
Until then, we must try
to bear their coming.
Margaret, are you there?
Come down.
John and Fanny will be here soon.
Why are they to live at Norland?
They have a house in London.
Houses go from father to son,
not father to daughter.
It is the law.
If you come,
we'll play with your atlas.
It's not mine anymore,
it's their atlas.
Do sit down.
As you know,
we are looking for a new home...
...and can only retain
Thomas and Betsy.
We're sorry to have to leave you all.
But we are certain you will find the
new Mrs. Dashwood a fair mistress.
My only real concern is how long
it will take them to move out.
How is Mrs. Ferrars?
She is always in good health.
My brother is with her this season.
Quite the most popular bachelor.
He has his own barouche.
You have two brothers?
Yes. Edward is the elder.
He's travelling up from Plymouth
and will break his journey here.
If that is agreeable to you.
My dear John...
...this is your home now.
Fanny wants the key to the silver.
What does Fanny want with it?
One can only presume
she wants to count it.
What are you doing?
Gifts for the servants.
Where is Margaret?
She's taken to hiding.
At least she can escape Fanny.
You do your best.
You've not said a word to her.
I have. I've said yes and no.
Good morning, Fanny.
Good morning, Miss Marianne.
How did you find the silver?
Was it all genuine?
Pray, when may we
expect your brother?
Edward is due tomorrow.
Oh, and my dear Mrs. Dashwood.
In view of the fact
that he will not stay long...
...I wonder if Margaret
will give up her room for him?
The view is incomparable, and I
want him to see Norland at its best.
Mrs. Dashwood,
Miss Dashwood, Miss Marianne.
My brother, Edward Ferrars.
- Do sit down.
Where is Miss Margaret?
I'm beginning to doubt
of her existence.
Forgive us, Mr. Ferrars. My youngest
is shy of strangers at present.
Naturally.
I am shy of strangers myself,
and I have nothing like her excuse.
How do you like your view,
Mr. Ferrars?
Very much.
Your stables are handsome
and beautifully kept.
Stables?
Your windows overlook the lake.
An oversight, Fanny, had led me
to one of the family rooms...
...but I've rectified the situation.
I am happily installed
in the guest quarters.
Tea!
They're all spoilt, I find.
Miss Margaret is always up trees
and under furniture.
I've barely had a civil word
from Marianne.
My dear Fanny,
they've just lost their father.
Their lives will never be the same.
That is no excuse.
Library.
These are mostly foreign.
Indeed. Magnificent.
I've never liked the smell of books.
No, it is the dust, perhaps.
I hear you have great plans
for the walnut grove.
Oh, yes. I shall have it knocked down
to make way for a Grecian temple.
That does sound interesting.
Would you show me the site?
Too expensive.
And we do not need four bedrooms.
We can share.
This one, then.
We have only 500 a year.
I'll send out more enquiries today.
Pardon my intrusion...
...but I think I have found
what you were looking for.
Won't you come out?
We haven't seen you all day.
We'll have to enlarge it.
Mattocks will help you adjust
to our hours.
Oh, Miss Dashwood.
Forgive me, do you by any chance
have a reliable atlas?
- I believe so.
- I must check the Nile's position.
My sister tells me
it is in South America.
No.
No, she's quite wrong.
I believe it is in Belgium.
Belgium?
Surely not.
You must be thinking of the Volga.
- The Volga?
- Of course, the Volga...
-...which, as you know, starts in--
- Vladivostok, and ends in--
- Wimbledon.
- Precisely.
Where coffee beans come from.
The source of the Nile
is in Abyssinia.
Is it?
Interesting.
- How do you do? Edward Ferrars.
- Margaret Dashwood.
Delighted to meet you.
- It adjoins this property.
- Quite so.
It cannot be
but a most desirable addition.
I'll ride there tomorrow
and speak to... Who is it?
- Gibson.
He'll be pleased enough to sell.
He'll want more than it is worth.
- Lunge.
- Have I hurt you?
- No, no.
Thank you. Forgive me.
That was my father's favourite.
Thank you for helping Margaret.
She's changed since you came.
Not at all, not at all.
I enjoy her company.
- Has she shown you the tree house?
- Not yet.
Would you do me the honour,
Miss Dashwood?
- It is very fine out.
- With pleasure.
Margaret always wanted to travel.
I know. She's off to China soon.
I'm to go as her servant.
But only on the understanding
that I'll be very badly treated.
What will your duties be?
Sword fighting and swabbing.
Which will take precedence?
Swabbing, I would imagine.
All I have ever wanted
is the quiet of a private life.
But my mother is determined
to see me distinguished.
- As?
- Anything.
Orator. Politician.
Even a barrister would do,
if I drove a barouche.
What do you wish for?
I prefer the church, but that is not
smart enough for my mother.
She prefers the army,
but that is too smart for me.
- Would you stay in London?
- I hate London.
Country living is my ideal. A small
parish where I might do some good.
Keep chickens.
Give very short sermons.
You talk of feeling idle and useless.
Imagine how that is compounded
when one has no hope...
...and no choice of
any occupation whatsoever.
Our circumstances are therefore
precisely the same.
Except that you will inherit
your fortune.
We cannot even earn ours.
- Perhaps Margaret is right.
- Right?
Piracy is our only option.
What is swabbing exactly?
"No voice divine the storm allayed.
No light propitious shone.
When snatched from all effectual aid,
we perished, each alone.
But I, beneath a rougher sea,
and whelmed in deeper gulfs than he..."
No, Edward, listen.
"No voice divine the storm allayed.
No light propitious shone.
When snatched from all effectual aid,
we perished, each alone."
Can you not feel his despair?
Try again.
"No voice divine the storm allayed.
No light propitious shone.
When snatched from all effectual aid,
we perished, each alone."
Mama.
Look. This has just arrived.
"I should be pleased to offer you
a home at Barton Cottage...
...as soon as ever you have need--"
It's from my cousin,
Sir John Middleton.
Even Elinor must approve the rent.
Has she not yet seen this?
- No. I will fetch her.
- Wait, no.
Let us delay.
Why?
I think...
I believe that Edward and Elinor
have formed an attachment.
It would be cruel to take her away
so soon. Devonshire is so far.
Why so grave?
Do you disapprove her choice?
By no means.
- Edward is very amiable.
- Amiable? But...?
There is something wanting.
He is too sedate.
His reading last night--
Elinor has not your feelings.
His reserve suits her.
Can he love her?
Can the soul be satisfied
with polite affections?
To love is to be on fire.
Like Juliet, Guinevere, Heloise.
- They made rather pathetic ends.
- Pathetic? To die for love?
How can you say so?
What could be more glorious?
That may be taking
your romantic sensibilities a little far.
"Is love a fancy or a feeling?
No, it is immortal
as immaculate truth.
'Tis not a blossom shed
when youth drops from life's stem.
For it will grow in barren regions
where no waters flow...
...nor ray of promise
cheats the pensive gloom."
What a pity Edward has
no passion for reading.
You asked him to read,
then you made him nervous.
- Me?
- Yes.
Your behaviour is cordial. You like him
in spite of his deficiencies.
I think him everything
that is amiable and worthy.
Praise, indeed.
He shall have my devotion when
you tell me he is to be my brother.
How shall I do without you?
Without me'?
I'm sure you will be very happy,
but promise you won't live far away.
Marianne, there is no question of--
That is, there is...
There is no understanding.
Do you love him?
I do not deny that I think
very highly of him.
That I...
...greatly esteem him.
- I like him.
- Esteem? Like?
Use these words again
and I shall leave the room!
Very well. Forgive me.
Believe my feelings to be stronger.
Further than that, do not believe.
Is love a fancy or a feeling?
- Or a Ferrars?
- Go to bed.
"I do not deny that I think
very highly of him.
That I greatly esteem him.
That I like him."
We are so happy
that you invited Edward to Norland.
He's a dear boy.
We're all very fond of him.
We have great hopes for him.
Much is expected of him by our mother
with regard to his profession.
Naturally.
And in marriage.
She's determined both he
and Robert will marry well.
Of course.
But I hope she desires them
to marry for love.
Love is all very well...
...but the heart doesn't always lead us
in the most suitable direction.
Edward is a compassionate person.
Penniless women prey on that type.
Having entered into any understanding,
he would never go back on his word.
He is simply incapable of doing so.
But it would lead to his ruin.
I'm worried. Mother will withdraw
all financial support from him...
...should he plant affection in less
exalted ground than he deserves.
I understand you perfectly.
To Devonshire?
My cousin, Sir John Middleton,
has offered us a small house.
Sir John Middleton?
He must be a man of property.
He's a widower from Barton Park.
It is Barton Cottage he offers us.
Oh, a cottage? How charming.
A cottage is always very snug.
But...
You will not leave
before the summer?
We can no longer trespass
upon your sister's goodwill.
You will come and stay with us.
I should like that.
Edward has long been expected
by our mother.
Come as soon as you can, Edward.
Remember, you're always welcome.
Can't you take him with you?
We can't afford him.
Perhaps he could
make himself useful in the kitchen.
Forgive me.
Miss Dashwood...
Elinor...
...I must speak to you.
There is something of
great importance that I need to...
...tell you about my education.
Your education?
Yes.
It was conducted,
oddly enough, in Plymouth.
- Indeed?
- Yes.
- Do you know it?
- Plymouth?
- Yes.
- No.
Well...
I was four years there.
In a school run by Mr. Pratt.
- Pratt?
- Precisely. Pratt.
And...
While I was there...
That is to say, he had a...
- Has a...
- Edward!
Edward.
I've been all over for you.
You're needed in London this instant.
I'm leaving this afternoon.
That will not do.
Mama wishes you to leave at once.
Excuse me.
Edward promised
he would bring the atlas to Barton.
Did he?
I'll wager he will do so
in less than a fortnight.
Dear Edward.
- Hello there!
- Mrs. Dashwood!
Yes.
Sir John.
Dear ladies!
Upon my word! Here you are!
- Sir John, your kindness--
- None of that! Hush, please!
Here is my dear mama-in-law,
Mrs. Jennings.
- Now get down, dog!
- This must be Mrs. Dashwood.
Was your journey tolerable?
Poor souls!
Why did you not
come up to the park first?
- We saw you pass.
- I made John call the carriage.
- She would not wait.
- We have so little company.
Oh, I feel as if I know you already.
- Delightful creatures!
- Are they not.
- You'll dine at Barton Park daily.
- Oh, every day.
- Dear Sir John, we cannot--
- No, no, no.
No refusals! I'm quite deaf to them.
But I insist!
Let us only settle in a few days.
But thank you very much.
No, no, no thanks.
Send your man up for the carriage
as soon as you're ready. Goodbye.
- Thank you.
- Don't thank us.
Good day to you.
Your feet are cold.
What have you been doing?
Your neck is so dirty
you could grow potatoes on it.
It's cold. I'm cold.
- Hot.
- Thank you, Elinor.
It's hot.
Where can Brandon be?
I hope he's not lamed his horse.
Colonel Brandon is the most
eligible bachelor in the county.
Oh, indeed.
He is bound to go for one of you.
He's a better age for Miss Dashwood.
But I dare say she's left her heart
behind in Sussex.
I see you, Miss Marianne!
I think I've unearthed a secret.
You've sniffed them out.
You're worse than my best pointer.
Is he a butcher, baker,
candlestick maker?
- I'll Winkle it out of you.
- She's good at winkling.
We've none of us any secrets here.
Or if we do,
we do not keep them long.
- He's curate of the parish.
- Or perhaps a handsome lieutenant.
Give us a clue. Is he in uniform?
He has no profession.
No profession? He's a gentleman?
Margaret, you know perfectly well
there is no such person.
There is. His name begins with F.
Margaret.
An F? There's a promising letter.
- F? F?
- Foster?
- There's one.
- Forrest? Fotheringay? Featherty?
- Fortescue?
- Fondant?
Sir John,
might I play your pianoforte?
Yes, of course.
My goodness.
We don't stand on ceremony here.
Please forgive her--
An entertainment, I declare.
I cannot remember when we had
a songbird in the house.
Lovely, love-- Brandon!
Come and meet our beautiful
new neighbours.
What a pity you're late.
You have not heard our songbird.
A great pity.
This is my dear friend Colonel Brandon.
We served in the East Indies.
Not a better fellow in the world.
You've been to the East Indies?
- I have.
- Vvhat's it like?
Like? Hot.
The air is full of spices.
Now, Miss Dashwood,
it's your turn to entertain us.
Oh, no
And I believe I know
what key you will sing in.
F-major--
You have no right to parade
your ignorant assumptions--
They're not assumptions.
You told me.
I told you nothing.
They'll meet him when he comes.
You don't speak of such things
before strangers.
- Everyone else was.
- Mrs. Jennings is not "everyone."
I like her. She talks about things.
We never talk about things.
Hush, please.
That is enough, Margaret.
If you can say nothing appropriate,
limit your remarks to the weather.
Surely they have enough reeds
for a Moses basket.
Mama, we've got lots.
You know what they're saying?
Word is, you've developed
a taste for certain company.
And why not, say I?
A man like you in his prime.
She'd be a fortunate young lady.
Marianne Dashwood would
no more think of me than of you.
Don't think of yourself so meanly.
And all the better for her.
Oh, no.
Besotted.
An excellent match.
He's rich and she's handsome.
How long have you known him?
As long as I've been here,
and I came 15 years back.
His estate is but four miles hence.
He and John are very thick.
He has no wife and children.
He had a tragic history.
He loved a girl once.
Twenty years ago now.
A ward to his family.
They were not permitted to marry.
- On what grounds?
- Money. Eliza was poor.
When the father discovered
their amour...
...she was flung out of the house,
and he was packed off to the army.
I think he'd have done himself harm
if not for John.
What became of the lady?
She was passed from man to man.
Disappeared from good society.
When Brandon returned from India
he searched heaven knows how long...
...only to find her dying
in a poorhouse.
Once, I thought my daughter Charlotte
might have cheered him up.
But she's better off where she is.
But look at him now! So attentive!
- I should try a little experiment.
- Oh, no. Please, let the colonel alone.
No, no, no, my dear.
All suitors need a little help.
Colonel Brandon,
we haven't heard you play of late.
There's a simple reason, my dear.
You have a superior musician here.
Our dear Brandon shares
your passion for music.
He plays the pianoforte well.
Oh, come, you know as many
melancholy tunes as Miss Marianne.
You must play us a duet.
Let us see you both side by side.
I do not know any duets.
Forgive me, colonel.
Will we never have peace? The rent
is low, but it comes on hard terms.
Mrs. Jennings has nothing to do but
marry off everyone else's daughters.
There's a parcel arrived.
- Parcel?
- Look!
Oh, my goodness.
It is too ridiculous.
When is a man safe from such wit
if infirmity does not protect him?
- Infirmity?
- If Brandon is infirm...
...I am at death's door.
A miracle your life
has extended this far.
- He complained of rheumatism.
-"A slight ache" was his phrase.
But Edward said
he would bring it himself.
"Dear Mrs. Dashwood, Miss Dashwood,
Miss Marianne and Captain Margaret.
It gives me great pleasure
to restore this atlas to its owner.
Business prevents my delivering it,
which will hurt me more than you.
Memories of your kindness
must sustain me, and I remain...
...your devoted servant always,
E.C. Ferrars."
- Why hasn't he come?
- He says he's busy, dear.
He said he'd come.
- Why hasn't he come?
- I'm taking you for a walk.
- No, I've been a walk.
- You need another.
- It is going to rain.
- It is not going to rain.
You always say that
and then it always does.
I fear Mrs. Jennings
is a bad influence.
You must miss him, Elinor.
We are not engaged, Mama.
But he loves you, dearest.
I am by no means assured of that.
And had he such a preference...
...we should be foolish to assume
there would not be many obstacles...
...to his marrying a woman of no rank
who cannot afford to buy sugar.
- But your heart must tell you--
- It is better to use one's head.
- It can't be good for me.
- It is. Stop complaining.
- It's giving me a cough.
- It is not giving you a cough.
Please, can we go back?
It's lovely. Come on, catch up!
Over there is a field of rabbits.
- I don't want to see rabbits.
- Yes, you do.
- Is anything superior to this?
- I told you it would rain.
There's blue sky! Let us chase it!
I'm not supposed to run.
Marianne!
Are you hurt?
I cannot walk. Run and fetch help.
I will run as fast as I can.
Margaret!
Don't be afraid. He's quite safe.
- Are you hurt?
- Only my ankle.
May I have your permission to
ascertain if there are any breaks?
It is not broken.
Now, can you put your arm
about my neck?
Allow me to escort you home.
At last!
She fell down and he's carrying her!
What?
Marianne, are you hurt?
- It's a twisted ankle.
- Do not be alarmed, Mama.
It's not serious.
I felt the bone, and it's sound.
I cannot begin to thank you.
Do not think of it.
I'm honoured to be of service.
- Will you not be seated?
- I don't desire to leave a water mark.
But permit me to call tomorrow
and enquire after the patient.
We shall look forward to it.
- You're most kind.
- I'll show you out.
Thank you.
Margaret, get the gentleman's hat.
- His name, his name!
- His name.
To whom are we so much obliged?
John Willoughby of Allenham
at your service.
John Willoughby of Allenham.
What an impressive gentleman!
He lifted me as if I weighed no more
than a dried leaf.
Is he human?
- Tell me if I hurt you.
- She feels no pain, Mama.
Margaret, ask Betsy to make up
a cold compress.
- Quickly as you can.
- Please don't say anything important.
Go on, go on.
He expressed himself well,
did he not?
- With decorum and honour.
- And spirit and wit and feeling.
- And economy. Ten words at most.
- Oh, Elinor.
- And he is to come tomorrow.
- Change, or you'll catch a cold.
What care I for colds?
- You'll care when your nose swells.
- You're right. Help me.
He's worth catching. Marianne must
not have all the men to herself.
But what do you know of him?
Decent shot.
There's not a bolder rider.
- But what is he like?
- Like?
But what are his tastes,
his passions, his pursuits?
Well...
He has a smart little pointer.
Was she out with him?
- Where is Allenham?
- Allenham?
Nice little estate three miles east.
He is to inherit it from a relative.
Lady Allen is the name.
It's Colonel Brandon.
I should go out and keep watch.
Hello, colonel.
You're looking out for Willoughby.
You'll not think of Brandon now.
Come in.
- Colonel.
- Good morning, Brandon.
Good morning.
How is the invalid?
Oh, thank you so much, colonel.
Elinor, would you?
I cannot think why you should
set your cap at Willoughby...
...when you've already made
such a splendid conquest?
I've no intention
of setting my cap at anyone.
Lady Allen's nephew?
He visits every year,
for he's to inherit.
He has a pretty estate of his own.
Combe Magna in Somerset.
I'd not give him up to a younger
sister for tumbling down hills.
Marianne!
- Don't run.
- The man himself. Come, Brandon.
We know when we are not wanted.
Let us leave him to the ladies.
Thank you so much for calling.
Marianne, the colonel and Sir John
are leaving.
Goodbye, Sir John.
Colonel, thank you for the flowers.
How do you do, colonel?
How does he do?
How do you do, more like.
Go on in, they're waiting for you.
Come.
Stop it.
- Mr. Willoughby, what a pleasure!
- The pleasure is all mine.
Miss Marianne
has not caught cold?
- You've found out my name.
- But of course.
The area is crawling with my spies.
And since you cannot
venture out to nature...
...nature must be brought to you.
Oh, how beautiful.
These are not from the hothouse.
I see mine is not the first offering.
Nor the most elegant.
I'm afraid I obtained those
from an obliging field.
- I always prefer wild flowers.
- I suspected as much.
- Elinor, would you?
- Yes. Excuse me.
- Our gratitude is beyond words.
- But it is I who am grateful.
I've often passed this cottage
and grieved for its lonely state.
Then I heard it was taken.
I felt an interest which nothing can
account for but my present delight.
Oh, Elinor, put them here.
Pray sit, Mr. Willoughby.
Who is reading
Shakespeare's sonnets?
- Marianne.
- I am.
- Marianne is reading them out.
- And which are your favourites?
Without a doubt, mine is 116.
"Let me not to the marriage
of true minds admit impediments.
Love is not love which alters
when it alteration finds...
...or bends with the remover
to remove..."
How does it continue?
-"Oh, no, it is an ever fixed mark...
- It is an ever fixed mark...
-...that looks on storm--"
-...that looks on tempests--"
- Is it "tempests"?
- I do believe it is "tempests."
Let me find it.
It's strange you are reading these.
- I carry them with me always.
- Oh, how beautiful.
Until tomorrow then.
My pocket sonnets are yours.
A talisman against further injury.
Goodbye. Thank you.
Good work, Marianne.
You covered Shakespeare, Scott,
all forms of poetry.
Meet again, we'll ascertain his views
on nature and romantic attachments.
Then you'll have nothing left
to talk of and the relationship will end.
I suppose I erred against decorum.
I should have talked of the weather.
No, but Mr. Willoughby can be in
no doubt of your enthusiasm for him.
Why should he doubt it?
Should I hide my regard?
No particular reason,
only that we know so little of him.
Time does not determine intimacy.
Seven years is too little for some,
seven days is enough for others.
Or seven hours, in this case.
I feel I know him already.
Had I more shallow feelings, I could
perhaps conceal them as you do.
- Marianne, that is not fair.
- I'm sorry, Elinor. I did not mean--
Don't trouble yourself, Marianne.
I do not understand her.
Marianne.
- Haven't you finished yet?
- No. Patience.
You're not going to deny us
beef as well as sugar?
There is nothing under 10 pence.
Do you want us to starve?
No. Just not to eat beef.
If my behaviour was improper,
I should be sensible of it.
It has caused impertinent remarks.
Do you not doubt your discretion?
If Mrs. Jennings' remarks prove
impropriety, we are all offending.
Morning.
Good morning, colonel.
Miss Dashwood, Miss Marianne,
I come to issue an invitation.
A picnic on my estate at Delaford.
If you would care to join us
on Thursday next.
Mrs. Jennings' daughter and husband
are travelling up especially.
We should be delighted, colonel.
I will, of course, be including
Mr. Willoughby in the party.
I should be delighted to join you.
Good morning, Miss Dashwood.
Good morning, colonel.
Good morning, Mr. Willoughby.
The colonel has invited us to Delaford.
Excellent.
I hear you have a fine pianoforte.
- A Broadwood Grand.
- A Broadwood Grand?
- Then I shall play for you all.
- We shall look forward to it.
Good day. Walk on, walk on.
Good bye.
Your sister seems very happy.
Yes.
She does not approve
of hiding her emotions.
Her romantic prejudices
tend to set propriety at nought.
- She is wholly unspoilt.
- Rather too unspoilt, in my view.
The sooner she is acquainted with
the ways of the world, the better.
I knew a lady very like your sister.
The same impulsive
sweetness of temper...
...who was forced into, as you put it,
a better acquaintance with the world.
The result was only
ruination and despair.
Do not desire it, Miss Dashwood.
Colonel Brandon's lawn
is perfect for kite launching.
We must test your sky kite.
Mind the pretty ribbons.
Imagine my surprise when Charlotte
and her master appeared with Lucy.
The last person I expected to see.
She came to join in the fun.
There is no such luxury at home.
I'd not seen you for so long.
I couldn't resist the opportunity.
You sly thing! It was the Dashwoods
she wanted to see.
I've heard nothing but "Dashwood"
for I don't know how long.
What do you think of them
now you see them?
My mother wrote of little else
in her letters since you came.
- Are they not as she describes?
- Nothing like.
You are quite rude today.
He's to be an MP,
and it is very fatiguing for him...
...for he is forced
to make everybody like him.
I said nothing so irrational.
Mr. Palmer's so droll.
He's always out of humour.
Here he comes!
Now you shall see, Charlotte.
Hello, Mr. Willoughby!
You must meet my daughter,
Charlotte, and Mr. Palmer.
- How do you do?
- And our cousin, Miss Lucy Steele.
Welcome to our party.
- Turn about.
- Come round, boys, come round.
May I sit beside you?
I've longed to meet you.
I've heard nothing but praise of you.
I would be delighted.
Sir John and Mrs. Jennings
are excessive in their compliments.
- Oh, no.
- I am sure to disappoint.
The praise came
from another source.
One not inclined to exaggeration.
What can this be?
- Colonel Brandon here?
- Over here.
There he is.
- My horse!
- What's the matter?
- I must away to London.
- Impossible!
Imperative.
We can't picnic without our host.
Come up to town tomorrow.
Or wait until we return.
I can't afford to lose one minute.
- Forgive me.
- I hope it's nothing serious.
Upon my soul,
this is all very unusual.
Frailty, thy name is Brandon.
Some cannot bear pleasure.
You are a wicked pair.
Colonel Brandon will be missed.
Why?
Everyone speaks well of him,
but no one remembers to talk to him.
- Exactly.
- Nonsense.
He is highly respected at Barton Park.
- Which is enough censure in itself.
- Really, Willoughby.
Come, come, Mr. lmpudence.
I know your wicked ways.
Reveal your beau.
Reveal him, I say.
No secrets between friends.
I'll Winkle them out of you.
I'll have you married to the colonel
by tea, or I'll swallow my bonnet.
As if you could marry him.
Why should you dislike him?
Because he threatened me with rain
when I wanted it fine.
He found fault with my high flyer
and will not buy my brown mare.
If it will be of satisfaction to you...
...I believe his character to be,
in all other respects, irreproachable...
...then I'm ready to confess it.
In return for this acknowledgement,
don't deny me the privilege...
...of disliking him as much as I adore...
...this cottage.
I have plans for improvements.
Now, that I will never consent to.
Not a stone must be added
to its walls.
Were I rich enough, I'd rebuild
Combe Magna to this exact image.
With dark, narrow stairs, a pokey hall,
and a fire that smokes, I suppose?
Especially the fire that smokes.
Then I'd be as happy at Combe
as I've been at Barton.
But this place has one claim on
my affections none other can share.
Promise never to change it.
I'm honoured you risk your honour...
...by seeing me to the gate
unaccompanied.
That is what Elinor would say.
And she would be right.
Miss Marianne, will you grant me
an interview tomorrow?
Alone?
- Willoughby, we are always alone.
- But there is...
There is something very particular
I should like to ask you.
Of course.
I shall ask Mama
if I may stay behind from church.
Thank you.
Until tomorrow, then.
Miss Marianne.
Oh, Virtue.
Silently and with fear, enter the hearts
of all that hear me this clay.
Will he kneel down
when he asks her?
They always kneel down.
What is wrong, dearest?
Willoughby? What is the matter?
I am s--
Forgive me, Mrs. Dashwood.
I am sent...
Lady Allen exercised the privilege
of riches upon a dependent cousin...
...and is sending me to London.
- This morning?
- Almost this moment.
What a disappointment. Your business
won't detain you for long, I hope?
You are kind, but I have no idea of
returning immediately to Devonshire.
I am invited only once a year.
For shame, Willoughby.
Can you wait for our invitation?
My engagements at present
are of such a nature...
...I dare not flatter my...
It's folly to linger in this manner.
I will not torment myself further.
Willoughby, come back!
Margaret, ask Betsy
to make a cup of tea for Marianne.
- What is wrong, my love?
- Do not ask me questions.
Please, let me be.
They must have quarrelled.
That is unlikely.
Perhaps Lady Allen disapproves
of his regard for Marianne.
And has invented an excuse
to send him away.
Then why did he not say so?
It's not like him to be secretive.
What do you suspect?
Why was his manner so guilty?
You think he's been acting a part?
No. He loves her. I am sure.
Of course!
Has he left her any assurance
of his return?
Cannot you ask if he proposed.
No! I cannot force a confidence
from Marianne. Nor should you.
We must trust her to confide in us
in her own time.
There was something underhand
in his manner.
- You're resolved to think the worst.
- I'm not resolved.
I prefer give him the benefit of my
good opinion. He deserves no less.
From all of us.
I am very fond of Willoughby.
Mama. Mama!
She would not let me in.
Oh, if only this rain would stop.
If only you would stop.
'Twas you took her off my hands,
Mr. Palmer. A good bargain too.
Now I have the whip hand over you,
for you cannot give her back.
Marianne, play with us. Looking at
the weather will not bring him back.
- She ate nothing at dinner.
- We're all forlorn these days.
Dear Miss Dashwood, perhaps now
we might have our discussion.
Our discussion?
I've longed to ask you something.
You might think me impertinent.
- I cannot imagine so.
- It is an odd question.
- Forgive me, I've no wish to trouble you.
- No, no.
Miss Dashwood...
...if only he'd gone to Combe Magna,
we could have taken you to see him.
We live but half a mile away.
- Five and a half.
- No.
I cannot believe it is that far.
Is it really five and a half--
I can't believe it.
Try.
You may ask any manner of question,
if that is of any help.
Thank you.
Are you acquainted with your
sister-in-law's mother Mrs. Ferrars?
With Fanny's mother?
No, I have never met her.
You must think me strange to ask.
If only I dared tell...
Lucy, if she tells you of the famous
Mr. F, you must pass it on.
Will you take a turn with me,
Miss Dashwood?
Oh, certainly.
I had no idea you were at all
connected with that family.
Oh, I am nothing to Mrs. Ferrars
at present.
But the time may come...
...when we may be very
intimately connected.
What do you mean?
Do you have an understanding
with Fanny's brother Robert?
The youngest? No.
I never met him in my life.
No. With Edward.
Edward? Edward Ferrars?
Edward and I have been
secretly engaged these five years.
You may well be surprised.
I only mention it because I entirely
trust you to keep our secret.
Edward would not mind
my telling you.
For he looks on you
quite as his own sister.
I am sorry.
Surely we...
We surely do not mean
the same Mr. Ferrars.
Yes. He was under the tutelage
of my uncle, Mr. Pratt, in Plymouth.
Has he never spoken of it?
Yes. Yes, I believe he has.
I wanted his mother's approval...
...but we loved each other so much.
Though you do not know him
as well as I, Miss Dashwood...
...you must have seen how capable he is
of making a woman attached to him.
I cannot pretend it has not
been hard on us both.
We can scarcely meet
above twice a year.
You seem out of sorts.
Are you quite well?
Perfectly well, thank you.
- I have not offended you?
- On the contrary.
I must know what you are saying.
If anyone finds out, it will ruin him.
Promise me you'll not tell a soul.
Miss Dashwood is quite engrossed.
I give you my word.
What has so fascinated you?
Tell us all!
We were talking of London.
Do you hear that, Charlotte?
Charlotte and I concocted a plan.
The best plan in the world!
I make for London shortly,
and I invite you, Lucy...
...and both the Misses Dashwood,
to join me.
- Splendid idea.
- London?
- Can I go?
- You know you're too young.
You will all come to my Chelsea home
and taste of the season's delights.
Please, can I go? I'm 12 soon.
Do you not long for it to be so?
I came here with no other view.
You're kind,
but we can't leave our mother.
- She can spare you very well.
- Of course I can.
- Of course she can!
- I could not be more delighted.
I will brook no refusal.
Let us strike hands on the bargain.
If I don't have you married
by Michaelmas, it will not be my fault.
I've never been so grateful.
I shall see Willoughby,
and you will see Edward.
Are you asleep?
With you in the room'?
You can't feel as calm as you look.
Oh, I will never sleep tonight.
What were you and Miss Steele
talking about so long?
Nothing of significance.
How do you think I like poking about
in that big house without Charlotte?
I wrote to Edward, yet I do not know
how much I may see of him.
Secrecy is vital.
He'll never be able to call.
I should imagine not.
It's so hard. My only comfort has been
the constancy of his affection.
You're fortunate,
over such a lengthy engagement...
...never to have had
any doubts on that score.
Oh, I am of a jealous nature.
Had he talked more of one young woman
than any other...
But he's never given a moment's alarm
on that count.
Imagine how glad he'll be
to learn that we are friends.
- Have you missed me, Pigeon?
- Very much, ma'am.
You always say so
and I never believe you.
- I trust everything is in order?
- I suggest the ordering of coal.
Don't talk to me of coals.
There you are, Pooter.
Still alive, I see. Tea, Pigeon.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Hello, my dears.
Well, you do not waste any time.
Give it to Pigeon.
Let us hope
they are definitely engaged.
Mrs. Jennings says your sister will
buy wedding clothes in town.
Indeed, Miss Steele,
I know of no such plan.
John and Fanny are in town.
We shall be forced to see them.
I think it was for next door.
Yes, you're right.
Do sit down for two seconds.
You're making me nervous.
- Good afternoon, sir.
- Good afternoon.
Oh, Elinor, it is Willoughby.
Indeed it is.
Excuse me, colonel.
Colonel.
What a pleasure to see you.
- Have you been in London all this while?
- Forgive me, Miss Dashwood.
I have heard reports
through town that...
Tell me once and for all:
ls everything resolved between
your sister and Mr. Willoughby?
Though neither one has informed me
of their understanding...
...I have no doubt
of their mutual affection.
Thank you, Miss Dashwood.
To your sister,
I wish all imaginable happiness.
To Mr. Willoughby,
that he may endeavour to deserve her.
What do you mean?
Forgive me, l...
Forgive me.
Where is dear Edward, John?
- And who is Edward?
- Who, indeed.
My brother. Mr. Edward Ferrars.
Indeed. Is that Ferrars with an F?
- Are there any messages?
- No.
- No messages at all? No cards?
- None.
- You do not ask for your messages.
- No, for I do not expect any.
I have no--
Very little acquaintance in town.
Not another word about the ham bone.
You and Cartwright sort it out.
No messages.
Do not fret, my dear.
This good weather is keeping
many a sportsman in the country.
But the frost will soon
drive them to town. Depend on it.
Of course. I had not thought of that.
Thank you, Mrs. Jennings.
And Miss Dashwood
may set her heart at rest...
...for your sister-in-law is inviting
Mr. F to the ball tonight.
Do be careful, clears,
the horses have been here.
It is beginning to rain also.
Follow me.
Oh, Mama! This is very merry!
- Do you spy anyone we know?
- No. Mr. Palmer has a better view.
Mr. Palmer?
Do you see anyone we know?
Unfortunately not.
How can you be such a tease?
There is Mrs. John Dashwood.
Mrs. Dashwood!
Come along, my dears.
There you are!
- Oh, goodness. How hot it is.
-lndeed.
You are not alone, I trust?
John is just gone
to fetch my brother.
Your brother! I declare,
this is good news, indeed.
I shall faint clean away.
Mrs. Jennings,
I am pleased to see you.
May I present my brother-in-law,
Mr. Robert Ferrars.
Miss Dashwood,
Miss Steele, Miss Marianne.
My dear ladies, we meet at last.
You must be the younger brother.
ls Mr. Edward not here?
Miss Dashwood was counting on him.
He is far too busy.
There's no special acquaintance here
to make his attendance worthwhile.
What are the men about these days?
Are they in hiding?
In the absence of your brother,
you must dance with Miss Dashwood.
It would be my honour.
Perhaps Miss Steele might consider
reserving the allemande?
You reside in Devonshire,
Miss Dashwood?
Yes.
- In a cottage?
- Yes.
I am excessively fond of a cottage.
If I had any money to spare,
I should build one myself.
Mr. Willoughby.
- How do you do, Miss Dashwood?
- Very well.
- How is your family?
- We are all extremely well.
Thank you for your kind enquiry.
Willoughby!
Good God, Willoughby.
Will you not shake hands with me?
How do you do, Miss Marianne?
What is the matter?
Why have you not come to see me?
Were you not in London?
Have you not received my letters?
I had the pleasure of receiving
the information you sent to me.
For heaven's sake, Willoughby,
tell me what is wrong.
Thank you. I am most obliged.
Excuse me, I must rejoin my party.
Go to him, Elinor.
Force him to come to me instantly.
You must come away.
Do you know them?
Acquaintances from the country.
Indeed.
Wearing their country fashions, I see.
Come away, dearest.
Come away.
I do not understand.
I must speak to him.
There you are, my dear.
My goodness. Come, dear.
You need some air.
Lucy! Come, dear. We must go.
Oh, we're leaving so soon?
It would be our pleasure
to escort your young charge home.
- How very kind.
- That is very handsome of you.
She actually sent him messages
during the night?
Yes, indeed.
- Marianne, please tell me.
- Do not ask me questions.
You have no confidence in me.
This reproach from you?
You who confide in no one?
- I have nothing to tell.
- We neither of us do.
I, because I conceal nothing.
You, because you communicate nothing.
Lady Charteris ought to limit her
invitation list. It was very warm.
I am glad we left early.
There now.
Lovers' quarrels are swift to heal.
That letter will do the trick.
I must be off.
I do hope he doesn't
keep her waiting much longer.
It hurts to see her this way.
What a welcome I had
from Edward's family.
You never said how agreeable
your sister-in-law is.
Robert, also.
It is fortunate that none of them
knows of your engagement.
"Dear Madam...
...I am at a loss to see
how I might have offended you.
If I have given rise to a belief of
more than I meant to express...
...I shall reproach myself
for not having been more guarded.
My affections
are engaged elsewhere.
It is with regret that I return
your letters and the lock of hair.
I am, et cetera, John Willoughby."
Oh, Marianne.
Dearest...
It is best to know
what his intentions are at once.
Think about if your engagement
had carried on before he ended it.
We're not engaged.
I thought he left you
with some kind of understanding.
No.
He's not so unworthy as you think.
Did he tell you that he loved you?
Yes.
No.
Never absolutely.
It was implied but never declared.
Sometimes I thought it had been,
but it never was. He broke no vow.
He made us all believe
he loved you.
He did! He loved me as I loved him.
I had to come straight up.
How are you, Miss Marianne?
Poor thing, she looks very bad.
No wonder, for it is but too true.
I was told by Miss Morton,
a very great friend...
...that he is soon to marry
a Miss Grey with 50,000!
If true, he is a good-for-nothing
who used my young friend ill.
And I wish with all my soul that his
wife might plague his heart out.
He's not the only young man
worth having.
With your pretty face
you'll never want for admirers.
Better let her have her cry out
and have done with it.
I will go look out something
to tempt her.
Does she care for olives?
I cannot tell you.
Apparently, they never were engaged.
Miss Grey has 50,000 pounds.
Marianne is virtually penniless.
She couldn't expect him
to go through with it.
But I feel for her.
She will lose her bloom
and end a spinster like Elinor.
We might have them to stay
for a few days. We are, after all, family.
- And my father--
- My love...
...I would ask them with all my heart,
but I've already asked Miss Steele.
And we cannot deprive
Mrs. Jennings of all her company.
We can invite your sisters
some other year.
Miss Steele will profit more
from your generosity.
- Poor girl.
- Excellent notion.
Colonel Brandon to see you.
Colonel.
Thank you so much for coming.
How is your sister?
I must get her home.
Palmer can take us to Cleveland,
a day from Barton.
I'll take you to Barton myself.
I confess, that is what I hoped.
Marianne suffers cruelly.
What pains me most is how hard
she tries to justify Mr. Willoughby.
But you know her disposition.
Perhaps...
... | ...
May I relate some circumstances
which only a desire to be useful--
You have something to tell me
of Mr. Willoughby?
When I quitted Barton last...
No, I must go further back.
No doubt...
...Mrs. Jennings has apprised you
of certain events in my past.
The sad outcome of my connection
with a young woman named Eliza.
What is not commonly known...
...is that 20 years ago, before she died,
Eliza bore an illegitimate child.
The father, whoever he was,
abandoned them.
As Eliza lay dying, she begged me
to look after the child.
I had failed her in every other way,
I could not refuse her now.
I placed the child, Beth,
with a family in the country...
...where I knew she would be
looked after. I saw her whenever I could.
She grew up so headstrong...
...and, God forgive me,
I allowed her too much freedom.
- Almost a year ago she disappeared.
- Disappeared?
I instigated a search, but for
eight months I imagined the worst.
On the day of the Delaford picnic,
I received the first news of her.
She was with child.
And the blackguard who had left her
with no hint of his whereabouts...
Oh, good God.
Do you mean Willoughby?
Before I could confront him,
Lady Allen had turned him out.
- He fled to London.
- He left without any explanation.
Lady Allen had annulled his legacy.
He was left with next to nothing.
He risked losing the estate, and the
money that remained, to his debtors.
So he abandoned Marianne...
...for Miss Grey and her 50,000.
Is Beth still in town?
She has chosen to go to the country
for her confinement.
I would not burden you,
had I not, from my heart...
...believed it might, in time,
lessen your sister's regrets.
I have described Mr. Willoughby
as the worst of libertines.
But I learned from Lady Allen that
he did mean to propose that day...
...and I cannot deny that his intentions
towards Marianne...
...were honourable.
I feel certain
that he would have married her.
Had it not been...
For the money.
- Was I right to tell you?
- Of course.
Whatever his past actions,
whatever his present course...
...you may be certain
that he loved you.
But not enough.
Not enough.
Here is someone to cheer you up.
How is your dear sister?
Poor thing.
I do not know what I'd do if a man
treated me with so little respect.
Are you enjoying your stay
with John and Fanny?
Oh, I was never so happy in my life.
Your sister-in-law has taken to me.
You cannot imagine what happened.
No, I cannot.
Yesterday I was introduced
to Edward's mother.
She was more than civil.
I have not yet seen Edward,
but I feel sure to, very soon.
Come in.
There is a Mr. Edward Ferrars
to see you, Miss Dashwood.
Do ask him to come in.
This way, sir.
Mr. Ferrars.
Miss Dashwood.
- What a pleasure to see you.
- Miss Dashwood, how can I--?
You know Miss Steele, of course.
Indeed.
How do you do, Miss Steele?
I am well, thank you.
Do sit down.
Thank you.
Yes.
Are you surprised to find me here
and not at your sister's house?
Let me fetch Marianne.
She would be disappointed to miss you.
Edward?
Edward! I heard your voice.
- At last you found us.
- My visit is shamefully overdue.
You're pale. Are you not well?
Don't think of me. Elinor is well.
That is enough for both of us.
Indeed. How do you enjoy London?
The sight of you is all the pleasure
it has afforded.
Is that not so?
Why have you not visited before?
I have been much engaged elsewhere.
Engaged elsewhere?
What was that when there were
such friends to be met?
Perhaps you think young men
never honour their engagements?
No, indeed.
Edward is the most incapable of
being selfish of anyone I ever saw.
Edward, will you not sit?
Help me to persuade him.
Forgive me. I must take my leave.
You are only just arrived.
Excuse me, but I've an urgent
commission for Fanny.
Perhaps you might escort me
back to your sister's house.
It would be an honour.
Miss Dashwood.
Marianne.
Why did you not urge him to stay?
He must have had his reasons.
Yes, your coldness.
Were I Edward,
I'd assume you didn't care for me.
Marianne looked badly.
It makes me fear
that I shall never marry.
Nonsense. You will marry far better
than the Dashwood girls.
But I have no dowry.
There are other important qualities
that you have in abundance.
It would not surprise me if you
married beyond your expectations.
Oh, I wish that might be so.
There is a young man.
Is he of good fortune and breeding?
Of both. But his family
would certainly oppose the match.
Hush. They will allow it
as soon as they see you.
It is a very great secret.
I've told nobody in the world
for fear of discovery.
I am the soul of discretion.
If I dared tell...
I can assure you,
I am as silent as the grave.
Viper in my bosom!
Stop this!
What a commotion!
Edward Ferrars,
the one I used to joke you about...
...is engaged these five years
to Lucy Steele.
Poor Mr. Ferrars. His mother,
who by all accounts is very proud...
...has demanded he break the
engagement or suffer disinheritance.
But he refuses to break his promise.
He has stood by her, good man,
and is cut off without a penny.
She settled it all on Mr. Robert.
I cannot sup. I must go to Lucy.
Your sister-in-law
drove her to hysteria.
How long have you known?
Since the night Mrs. Jennings
invited us to London.
Why did you not tell me?
Lucy told me in confidence.
- I could not break my word.
- He loves you!
He made me no promises.
He tried to tell me about Lucy.
He cannot marry her.
Should he treat her worse
than Willoughby treated you?
No.
But he can't marry without love.
He promised a long time ago.
He may harbour some regret,
but he will be happy...
...that he did his duty
and kept his word.
After all...
...it is bewitching to think one's
happiness depends on one person...
...but it is not always possible.
We must accept.
Edward will marry Lucy,
and you and I will go home.
Always resignation and acceptance.
Always prudence
and honour and duty.
Elinor, where is your heart?
What do you know of my heart,
or anything but your own suffering?
For weeks this has been pressed on me,
when I could not speak of it.
Forced on me by the person whose
prior claims ruined all my hopes.
I endured her exaltation, knowing
I was divided from Edward forever.
If not bound to silence, I'd have
produced proof of a broken heart.
I have heard your Mr. Ferrars...
...has lost his fortune to his brother.
- Have I been rightly informed?
- It is indeed so.
Are you acquainted with him?
No, we have never met.
But I know only too well the cruelty...
...of dividing two young people
long attached to one another.
I have a proposal that may allow him
to marry Miss Steele immediately.
As he is a friend to your family,
perhaps you'd mention it to him.
I'm sure he'd be delighted
to hear it from your own lips.
I think not.
His behaviour has proved him proud.
In the best sense.
I feel certain this is the right course.
Mr. Edward Ferrars.
Mr. Ferrars.
Miss Dashwood.
Thank you for responding
so promptly.
I was grateful
to receive your message.
God knows what you
must think of me.
- Mr. Ferrars--
- I have no right to speak--
I have good news.
Do please sit down.
You know of Colonel Brandon.
I've heard his name.
Colonel Brandon desires me to say...
...that as you wish to join the clergy...
...he has pleasure in offering
you the parish at Delaford...
...in the hope it may enable
you and Miss Steele to marry.
Colonel Brandon?
Yes.
He means it as testimony of his
concern for this cruel situation.
Colonel Brandon give me a parish?
Can it be possible?
The unkindness of your family...
...makes you astonished
to find friendship elsewhere.
No.
Not to find it in you.
I cannot be ignorant that it is
certainly to you that I owe this.
I'd express it if I could,
but I am no orator...
You are mistaken.
You owe it to your own merit.
Colonel Brandon must be a man
of great worth.
He is the kindest and best of men.
May I ask why the colonel
did not tell me himself?
I think he felt it would be better
coming from a friend.
Your friendship has been
the most important of my life.
You will always have it.
Forgive me.
You honour your promises. That is
more important than anything else.
I wish you both very happy.
Miss Dashwood.
What luck for them
to find a parish so close to Barton.
You'll all be able to meet very often.
I've never disliked a person so much
as I do Mr. Willoughby.
To think we can see
his house from the hill!
I'll ask Jackson to plant trees.
You'll do nothing of the sort.
I hear Miss Grey's bridal gown
was everything of the finest...
Mrs. Bunting!
We're in desperate need of tea.
Thank you, colonel.
She's not drawn breath since London.
Had I only found another way home.
There was no other way.
I'll just take a stroll. A moment's peace.
- I think it is going to rain.
- Come have tea.
- No, it will not rain.
- When you say so, it always does.
I shall keep to the garden.
We are very proud of our Thomas.
His papa has such a way with him.
Oh, there you are, Miss Dashwood.
Come and meet little Thomas.
I cannot see Marianne.
Love is not love which alters
when it alteration finds...
...or bends with the remover to remove.
Oh, no, 'tis an ever fixed mark...
...that looks on tempests
and is never shaken.
Willoughby.
Marianne?
- She'll be wet through.
- Thank you for pointing that out.
Do not worry, Miss Dashwood.
Brandon will find her.
We can all guess where she went.
- Miss Dashwood.
- Oh, thank you.
She's not hurt,
but we must get her warm.
There is a fire lit in my room.
Do hurry!
Miss Dashwood.
I think Marianne may need a doctor.
You'll wear yourself out.
A day or two in bed
will set her to rights.
You can rely upon Harris, colonel.
I've never found a better physician.
- What is the diagnosis?
- It is an infectious fever.
It has taken far more serious hold
than I would expect in one so young.
- I recommend removing your child.
- Mrs. Bunting!
Miss Dashwood,
I am more sorry than I can say.
If you prefer me to stay, I shall.
That is very kind.
But Colonel Brandon and Dr. Harris
will look after us.
Thank you for all you have done.
She's not doing as well as I would like.
What can I do?
You've done so much already.
Give me an occupation,
or I shall run mad.
She would be easier
if her mother were here.
Of course.
I must fetch more laudanum.
I cannot pretend
that your sister's condition...
...is not very serious.
You must prepare yourself.
I will return shortly.
Marianne.
Marianne, please try.
Please try.
Icannotu.
I cannot do without you.
Oh, please.
I've tried to bear everything else.
I will try...
But please, dearest...
...beloved Marianne...
...do not leave me alone.
Elinor.
My mother.
Mama! Mama!
She is out of danger.
Oh, my Mar)'-
- Where is Elinor?
- I'm here.
Dearest, I am here.
Colonel Brandon.
Thank you.
He's not so dashing as Willoughby,
but he has a pleasing countenance.
There was something in Willoughby's
eyes at times that I did not like.
"Nor is the earth the lesse,
or loseth aught.
What from one place doth fall...
...is with the tide unto another brought.
For there is nothing lost
but may be found...
...if sought."
Shall we continue tomorrow?
No, for I must away.
Away? Where?
That I cannot tell you.
It is a secret.
You will not stay away long?
There.
There I fell,
and there I first saw Willoughby.
Poor Willoughby.
He will always regret you.
Does it follow that, had he chosen me,
he would have been content?
He would have had a wife he loved,
but no money...
...and might have learned to rank
his pocketbook above his heart.
If his regrets are half as painful
as mine, he will suffer enough.
Do you compare
your conduct with his?
No.
I compare it with what it
ought to have been.
With yours.
- Oh, Thomas.
- I fetched those beef fillets, ma'am.
Beef is less expensive in Exeter.
Anyway, it's for Marianne.
- Was Exeter crowded?
- It was, ma'am.
Mrs. Braintree said Miss Pothington
has had another stroke.
And Miss Murden has turned away
Coles for his drunkenness.
Oh, and Mr. Ferrars is married,
but of course you know that.
But, Elinor--
Who told you he was married?
I seen Mrs. Ferrars myself.
She and Mr. Ferrars
stopped at the inn.
I saw it was Miss Steele,
so I took off my hat.
And she enquired after all of you,
especially Miss Dashwood.
She bade me give
their compliments.
They're sending a piece
of the cake.
- Did Mrs. Ferrars seem well?
- She said she was vastly contented.
As she was always an affable lady,
I made free to wish her joy.
Thank you, Thomas.
- What is it, Thomas?
- I'm not sure, but it's heavy.
"It is small enough for the parlour.
When I follow shortly, I expect...
...that you've learnt the enclosed.
Your friend, Christopher Brandon."
Oh, my darling, look. It fits perfectly.
Here you are, Miss Marianne.
Fetch some tea.
He must like you very much.
It is not just for me,
it's for all of us.
Here is Colonel Brandon.
I do not think it is the colonel.
He said he would arrive today.
Play your new song for him.
Edward!
It is Edward!
Calm. We must be calm.
Mr. Ferrars for you, ma'am.
Edward.
What a pleasure to see you.
Mrs. Dashwood.
Miss Marianne, Margaret...
...Miss Dashwood.
I trust I find you all well?
Thank you. We are all very well.
We've been enjoying fine weather--
Well, we have.
I'm glad to hear it.
The roads were very...
---dry-
May I wish you great joy, Edward.
Thank you.
I hope you have left Mrs. Ferrars well.
Tolerably. Thank you.
- Is Mrs. Ferrars at the new parish?
No, my mother is in town.
I meant Mrs. Edward Ferrars.
Well, then you...
You've not heard?
I think you mean my brother.
Mrs. Robert Ferrars.
Mrs. Robert Ferrars?
Yes.
L.
I received a letter from Miss Steele...
...or Mrs. Ferrars, I should say...
...communicating to me...
...the transfer of her affections
to my brother Robert.
It seems they were much
thrown together in London.
In view of my new circumstances,
I felt it only right...
...that she be released
from our engagement.
At any rate, they were married
last week in Plymouth.
Then you...
...are not married?
No.
Elinor...
...I met Lucy when I was very young.
Had I had a profession, I would not
have felt such an idle inclination.
My behaviour at Norland
was very wrong.
I convinced myself that
you felt only friendship for me...
...and that it was my heart alone
that I was risking.
I have come with no expectations...
...only to profess, now I am able...
...that my heart is, and always will be...
...yours.
- He's sitting next to her.
- Margaret, come down.
- Will you stop that?
- What else?
- Oh, Marianne.
- Tell us!
Wait.
He's kneeling down!