Crimson and clover
Over and over
Crimson and clover...
...believe your eyes...
those are the northern lights
on view above the city...
for the first time in nearly eighty years.
Oh, Susie Q, baby, l love you...
lt's 5.00 a.m.
Hello, New York.
The big story this morning
is the Amazings...
taking the field today in Baltimore...
for their final practise
before tomorrow's opener...
of the 1969 World--
Early this morning,
sanitation workers...
discovered the dead body
of another nurse...
in a Dumpster in Queens.
This is the third nurse killed
in what New York papers...
are now calling the Nightingale murders.
All three victims have been nurses...
each of them found strangled...
with their hands gruesomely
bound behind their backs...
with glass tape.
The lights, also known
as the aurora borealis--
Look out.
Manhattan calling Eye of the Storm.
Engine company one-two,
ladder company nine-three...
respond to Manhattan box...
one-three-two off-ramp
on George Washington Bridge.
On our way.
Frank, we're the second in.
We got the rescue.
Great.
Commander,
what do you need done?
That dike's about to go.
We're one spark away
from losing the block.
ls there another way in?
Only that manhole leads to the vault.
Forget it, Sullivan.
Vault door's rusted shut,
and they can't kill the juice.
Frank, you're not going to make it.
There's not enough time.
What, miss the World Series?
Not a chance.
Give me my tools.
Sullivan,
this is Commander O'Connell.
Can you hear me?
l hear you, Commander.
The gasoline is rising in the vault.
Those downed cables
hit that gas, it's going to blow.
Way to go, Gib.
l should have been a goddamn mailman.
Clear this channel.
Explosion's imminent.
Guys. Can you hear me?
We're in here.
- Coming in.
Get us out.
- He's got a broken leg.
Frank, it's going to flash.
Get out of there.
The dike isn't holding.
Get us out.
Frank, did you hear me?
l hear you, Butch.
Grab that axe.
Here.
Give me a whack. No sparks.
Again.
One more.
OK, stand back.
Thank God.
My leg's all busted up.
Please hurry.
We're in, Butch.
Get them and get the hell out.
Hey, fellas.
Time to go home.
Watch it. Watch it.
lt's falling.
lt's going to break.
Let's go. That's an order.
Everybody goes.
All right. Let's move
before the gas lights up.
Watch that wire.
Get out, for Christ's sake.
l got you.
Butch,
we're coming out right now.
Go.
You all right?
Watch your head.
Get up that ladder.
Go ahead.
Get up. Get up.
Go on up.
Go. Right behind you.
l am going.
Pull him up.
Come on.
Come on. l got you.
Welcome to the company, Gib.
Hey, fellas?
Hey, Dad.
Hey. Hey, Gordo.
Hey, Mr Sullivan.
How you doing?
How's my Little Chief?
- Good.
Where's your mother?
- lnside the house.
Hey, Jules.
Hey, bud.
- Hey, bud.
How about a little bit of the King?
Yeah, why not a little of the King?
Damn.
You all right?
Yeah. l think l ruined the sauce...again.
What's the matter, bud?
Trouble working an 8-hour shift
at the hospital...
watching the kid,
whipping up a little Bolognese?
You didn't marry Donna Reed.
l'd go for you...
and Chinese takeout over her any day.
Because l love you too much,
baby
Why can't you see
What you're doing to me...
How was your tour?
- The usual.
Butch called.
Did he?
- He did.
lt was under control, bud.
Butch, he's getting
a little tight in his old age.
Nothing wrong with old age,
as long as you get there.
All right, Chief.
When l let go,
l want you to keep pedalling.
Put the wheels back on.
l am going to fall.
Don't worry about falling.
You're ready to do this.
Come on.
Spirit and guts, OK?
All right.
Keep pedalling.
l am going to let go. That's it.
Keep pedalling. Keep pedalling.
Keep pedalling.
You all right?
Johnny?
You OK? Are you hurt?
Are you OK? You OK?
Go on, honey. lt's OK.
Come on, Chief.
Don't quit on me now.
Don't be so tough on him.
He's just a kid.
He just needs to know you're behind him.
OK. You're right. All right.
CQ-22, this is W2QYV,
by for call.
...because of the solar activity.
lt's beautiful.
We got the sky lit up like a bonfire.
Word is the sunspots
are shooting off flares...
that stretch out half a million kilometres.
Tell me about it.
l am picking up signals
l could never reach before.
Francis, is that you?
How are you doing, my friend?
l am doing great.
How you doing?
Fantastic.
My wife, Sophia,
she's giving me another baby.
So, that's it, Samantha?
You're just walking out?
l have been walking out for six months, John.
You just didn't notice or care.
You're right.
We should have quit a long time ago.
l am sorry.
l know it's my fault.
l can't change, Sam.
l wish l could, but l can't.
No, John,
it's that you won't change.
And that's what hurts so much.
Goodbye, Chief.
Next up, Johnny Sullivan.
lt's a hit up the middle.
And Johnny's going to hold at first.
Now batting for Johnny's father,
Coach Newman.
He checks the runner and fires.
Lined hard to right.
No problem.
One on. One out.
Hi, Uncle John.
- l am not your uncle, kid.
Hey, Sully. ls that you?
Gordo, what are you guys
doing in my house?
My TV's out again.
Hey, you want a brewski?
Do you believe Linda still
won't let me cook in the house?
l melt one lousy frying pan,
you know?
John, guess what?
Dad's taking me fishing.
want to come?
- l wish l could, Gordy.
But you bring me back a big one, OK?
ls it OK if Gordy uses your old gear?
l think it's somewhere in the hall closet...
if you can find it.
Gordy, have a look.
Yahoo went up another five points today.
Did l miss the boat on that one.
Should have, would have, could have, pal.
So Sam called Linda.
Dad, John, come here.
Gordy, what are you doing back there?
Dad, check it out.
Fire department.
Can l open it up?
Sure.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Give me that gun.
All right?
What's this, Dad?
Oh, my God.
John,
it's your dad's old ham radio.
Remember how we used to beg him
to let us talk on this thing?
This...is not a toy.
- ls not a toy.
Can we try it, Dad?
Ask Uncle John.
Can we try it?
What the hell.
All right. Here.
Let's grab this baby out.
This is what we used when l was your age.
Let's go over to the den.
Plug it in, like the old times.
We want CW or LSB.
Stand by function.
Operator. Come on.
l don't know what's going on.
Let's take a look under the hood.
See what we got here.
Check this baby out.
There she is.
This is what people used before the Net?
Not exactly.
l will tell you.
Hams were--Ah, bingo.
These babies were different.
Not everybody had one of these...
and you needed a special licence
just to be able to talk on them.
Damn. l just----
l don't think it's going to work.
lt's junk, kid.
Nobody uses those things anymore.
Gordo,
do you know what time it is?
Hey, John.
- Hi, Linda.
Come on, Gordy. Let's go.
l will catch you later,
if l am lucky.
Hi. This is Julia Sullivan.
Please leave a message after the tone.
Hey, Ma. lt's me.
Just checking in.
You're probably at work.
Anyways,
l will see you tomorrow night.
Love you.
The aurora borealis,
to anyone who's seen it.....
is one of the stunning events
of your lifetime.
They're brighter these days.
ls something going on there?
Do they tie in with your field?
Where do they come from?
lt's truly a stunning sight.
lt's beautiful to look at.
l don't think we have seen one
this bright for thirty years.
From the point of view
of physics and string theory...
there's nothing really that we gain...
from studying the aurora borealis.
History does teach us.....
that every time we thought
we had it figured out...
there was some major discovery
right around the bend...
that required complete dramatic change...
in our understanding
of the laws of physics.
This is a phrase people have
begun to hear, string theory.
Yes, that's right.
String theory dramatically
changes our understanding...
of space and time.
For example, it turns out that string theory...
requires our universe to have 10
or possibly even 11 dimensions.
The strange thing is.....
some physicists
are even pursuing the idea.....
that there might be more
than one time dimension.
So in addition to time as we
know it, psychological time...
which seems to organize events
in the universe around us...
there may be a second time dimension...
where the universe evolves
in some different manner.
Another phrase...
CQ-15. Come in, 15.
W2QYV here. Who have l got?
Name's John.
You licensed to broadcast,
buddy?
Look. l really don't remember
how this thing works.
Listen. You can't broadcast
without a licence.
Unless this is an emergency,
you have to get off the band.
Hey, pal,
my whole life's an emergency.
Where you transmitting from?
Queens, New York.
What do you know?
Bayside, born and raised.
No kidding?
l thought these things were
for talking around the world.
The 15 band closes down at night...
but during the day...
you can chew the band with China
if you want.
l can't believe people
are still using these things.
You must be a real old-timer.
Days like this, l feel like
l am getting there, you know?
So, Queens,
you psyched for the series?
You know, l really don't
follow baseball anymore.
What?
l got fed up with all the bullshit.
What are you talking about?
Let me tell you something.
A thousand years from now...
when school kids study about America...
they're going to learn about three things.
The Constitution,
rock 'n' roll, and baseball.
How can you live in Queens
and not love the Amazings?
The Amazing Mets?
What, the '69 series?
Man, l will love Ron Swoboda till the day l die.
Now l am with you.
He's got the heart of a lion.
Mets can't win game one without him.
Can you hear me?
Game one?
What are you talking about?
lt was all over after Buford...
nailed Seaver's second pitch
out of the park.
No way, buddy.
Ain't going to happen.
Hey, CQ-15.
CQ-15, are you there?
Who the hell was that?
Queens, are you there, Queens?
Did l lose you?
Hey, Frank.
Give the radio a rest.
Your son wants to say good night.
All right.
l will be right there.
Would parallel universes
ever become aware of each other?
Who knows?
lt's a strange idea...
Elvis, you all right?
l am sorry.
You OK, Frank?
- We're fine.
You all right, buddy?
You OK, buddy?
The sunspots are going to
have a serious impact...
on radio communications
for the next six or seven days.
ln fact,
quantum theory tells us...
that the rigid notions
of past, present and future...
although useful in day-to-day life...
may dissolve and be replaced
by a complex formulation...
in which time is far more fluid...
than anybody would have imagined.
Take me out to the ball game
Take me out with the crowd
Buy me some peanuts and Cracker Jacks...
l don't care if l never get back...
because it's root
Root, root for the home team...
lf we don't win
Two, three strikes you're out
....At the old ball game....
That's perfect.
Butch,
you got to turn the whole set.
Can't wait till the game.
lt's not the tuner.
lt's the antenna.
Proby.
- What?
Point the antenna out from under the house.
There it is.
Proby, walk away.
Satch, grab a seat.
Sully, l think l need a new set of cleats.
l lost my footing there.
Dr. De Leon,
you decided to join us.
You don't want to know.
Thirty-six hours,
l was bouncing off the walls.
That's why you're the doctor,
l am the nurse.
Can l get you something?
No. lt's all right.
ln left field, Don Buford.
Paul Blair is in centrefield.
How you boys doing?
- Good, Satch.
OK. l have got something for you.
l can't believe it.
And l got something for you.
Dad, look.
- What? You got to be--
Hey, Satch, what are you,
Santa Claus or something?
Game three tickets.
Did you say thank you?
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
Thank you, Satch.
Hey, all right.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Everybody.
Everybody say, 'Amazing Mets.'
Amazing Mets.
Don't choke on your pride, Sul.
You ain't never going to
find another one like Sam.
She made up her mind, Satch.
Nothing l do is going to change it.
Nothing you're willing to do.
What's the story?
- Construction crew found a body.
Actually, a skeleton.
OK. Well, be real careful
when you pull it out.
Make sure you get the dirt around it.
What's this construction?
l think l will visit the neighbours, Satch.
Yeah, OK.
What did they tear down here?
Greek diner.
l used to get breakfast there all the time.
Them Greeks were good people.
Careful. lt's hot.
Thank you, Mrs Shepard.
Once that McDonald's
opened up on Dyckman...
they lost all their business.
l see your son's on the job.
- Was.
Jack died a while back.
lt's hard. l know.
lt just seems like yesterday.
My son lived and bled blue.
Get out of here.
- OK, Detective.
Give my regards to Beth.
- Sure will.
This isn't going to be anything
but a history lesson.
Let's go back to the house.
Hey, Barney. How you doing?
Good.
Here you go. Have a good night.
l thought it'd be nicer to eat here.
Sounds good.
l am sorry Samantha couldn't make it.
Those grad school applications
are driving her crazy.
How's it coming?
l got the VCR hooked up.
lt's just this frigging clock.
Doesn't matter.
l am sorry, Mom.
l know. lt's all right.
l am sure everything will work out.
What's that?
With Sam.
Oh, yeah, you know,
just a tough time right now.
So how are things at the hospital?
Fine.
Dr Schwartz retired last month.
No kidding.
He must have been pushing 90.
- Close, yeah.
So how'd you like 'The Lion King'?
l loved it.
lt was sweet, kid.
l wish you'd gone.
Yeah, l know.
l am sorry. lt's work.
Yeah, well, you work too hard.
Look who's talking.
lt's tomorrow.
- Thirty years.
l wish l could remember him better.
He was just a big kid.
He wanted to play baseball forever.
And fighting fires,
he loved that.
And you, he loved you.
OK, guys. Bedtime.
Looking good.
We will do it again tomorrow,
Chief.
Good night, Dad.
CQ-15. CQ-15.
W2QYV calling unidentified station Queens.
CQ-15?
CQ-15, come in, Queens.
ls that you?
l have been trying to 'Q' you
all night. Where you been?
How the hell did you do it?
Do what?
Do what? The series.
You called Buford's homer.
How the hell did you do it?
lt wasn't too tough, buddy.
The game happened 30 years ago.
Yeah, right. Yeah,
thirty years ago. Yeah, sure.
l suppose you could tell me
what happened in game two?
Sure. Top of the ninth, Al Weis,
game-winning RBl single.
Brooks Robinson
grounds out to end the game.
Daddy, come up
and sing the baseball song.
Hey, Little Chief.
You all right?
Just go on up.
l will be there in a minute.
Sorry about that.
That was my kid.
What'd you just say?
Sorry about that.
My kid just came in.
You call your son 'Little Chief'?
What'd you say your name was?
Frank. Frank Sullivan.
ls this some kind of joke?
Gordo, is that you?
Are you messing with me?
l ain't messing with you.
l am just trying to figure out--
You're telling me
your name is Frank Sullivan...
you live in Queens,
and you want to know......
how l called the first game
of the 1969 World Series?
Yeah, that's exactly what l want to know.
Gordo, if this is you,
so help me.
What'd you say--
- Gordo?
What'd you say your call station
or your call letters were?
W2QYV.
Now you listen to me.
My name is John Francis Sullivan.
l live at 343 42nd Avenue,
where l have lived my whole life.
l saw the first game
of the 1969 World Series...
right here in this house thirty years ago.
Bullshit.
My father's name is Francis Patrick Sullivan.
He was a fire-fighter and a die-hard Metsfan.
Every night...
- Bullshit.
...he sang to me
'Take Me Out to the Ballgame.'
Who the hell are you?
Son of a bitch.
What's going on?
Nothing's going on.
Oh, my God.
You burnt the desk.
l can see it.
Are you still there?
You burnt the desk.
l can see it.
Come back. Talk to me.
Listen to me.
You listen to me right now.
l don't know who you are
or why you're doing this.
But let me tell you something,
asshole.
You stay away from me and my family.
No, no, no.
You got to believe me.
l don't know how this is happening...
but it's me, Little Chief.
Hey. Look. l am warning you.
lf you touch my kid...
l will hunt you down till
the day l die. You got that?
But you already died.
What are you talking about?
The Buxton fire.
When did that happen,
thirty years ago?
October 12, 1969.
Tomorrow. You're telling
me l am going to die-----
l ain't dying in no fire tomorrow.
My God, tomorrow. Listen.
Tomorrow hasn't happened.
Right. lt hasn't happened.
lt ain't going to happen.
You got to listen to me.
lt was an abandoned warehouse.
Butch always told Ma it wasn't your fault.
You went with your instincts.
l am warning you.
- Listen to me.
lf you'd gone the other way,
you would have made it.
Hello? Shit.
Sully, what are you doing, man?
l talked to him, Gordo.
l talked to my dad.
Sully, go in the house.
l am going to come over,
and we will hang out.
No. l got to get him back
so he doesn't go in.
Go in? Go in where?
The warehouse in Buxton.
lt's tomorrow.
Yeah, right. Yeah,
thirty years ago. Yeah, sure.
l suppose you could tell me
what happened in game two?
Sure. Top of the ninth, Al Weis,
game-winning RBl single.
Come on. Come on.
Hit it out, Al.
Look at the stats.
Look at them.
Yeah, all right.
We have a 3 and 2 response.
Ladder 93.
You're first due.
Flash is reported to be
an abandoned warehouse...
at the foot of Water Street and Third.
You got some construction-limited access.
Al Weis is having a great series.
Yeah. We won.
Frank. You all right?
We know it's vacant.
Nobody goes in.
Surround and drown.
Call for a tower.
Help.
Shit. We got squatters inside.
Help. Help.
My sister.
She's up there. She passed out.
Where's your sister?
What floor?
l tried to help.
- Tell me what floor.
On the top floor.
l tried. l tried.
Please help her. Please.
Take her. Come on, Proby.
Anybody else up there?
Ryan, get her medical treatment.
Give me my gear.
Hey, Sul.
- Satch.
Here he is.
How you feeling, Sul?
What can l tell you?
Here you go.
Better.
No visible fire first or second floor.
Watch your step, Proby.
This floor's rotten.
We got fire on the third floor.
We're going up.
Frank, we got two lines coming behind you.
Back out, kid.
Wait for the line.
The hell with the line.
l will find another way up.
No, you can't help me, kid.
So you doing OK, John?
Yeah. Tough day, you know.
Here's to your dad.
Thirty years today.
To your dad.
To my dad.
We're pulling everyone out of the building.
Get that up to the top floor.
lt's cooking up here.
So after that Halloween thing
with the fire truck, remember?
l remember riding around
with Butch and your dad...
and the whole neighbourhood
was watching.
l remember.
l wanted to go as a cop.
Yeah, so then Jules makes your dad...
buy you that cop kit for your birthday.
l remember that.
l was always the robber.
l was always being handcuffed.
That's right.
l taught you to do that.
Ten-forty-five.
l found the girl.
She's breathing.
- Get them out.
Hang on.
What the hell is going on?
Gino, what's the matter?
The gear box, it's cracked.
Frank. Frank.
The ladder's jammed.
You got to find another way out.
Frank, can you hear me?
lt worked out OK.
You're a better cop than a fireman.
No doubt about it.
Worked out good for me, too.
l am glad l didn't have to spend
ten years as his hose man.
Yeah, l bet you are.
The Buxton fire.
lf you had just gone the other way.
Frank,
we're losing the building.
l know.
Hey, hey, hey.
This is not a toy.
Wave to Ma.
Ma, look at us.
He's some ball player.
John, you all right?
l am sorry.
- What is it?
ls everything OK?
- Yeah. Can you bring a towel?
Satch, my father didn't die in a fire, right?
Gordo,
my father didn't die in a fire.
What are you talking about,
Johnny? He had cancer.
Cancer. Because it was
the cigarettes, right?
Yeah, lung cancer,
ten years ago.
Little Chief.
Gordo, l ain't dreaming here.
l talked to him. lt was real.
Little Chief.
What are you talking about?
lt was a ham radio.
That's how come he didn't die.
Little Chief.
John. John Sullivan,
are you there?
Come on. Answer me.
Chief. Chief, are you there?
l am right here, Daddy.
Come here.
Come on.
Where's Elvis?
- He's sleeping.
Why aren't you sleeping?
- You woke me up.
l did?
l got an idea.
What's that?
All right, Chief.
What do you say we tame this bronco?
l am scared.
l know.
And you know what?
l am going to be right here with you.
Always.
Daddy, l can't.
Well, we can.
We can do it together.
You and me.
Spirit and guts.
What do you say?
All right. Come on.
Now, you just take your time.
l am not going to let go until you say it's OK.
All right.
Start pedalling.
That's it.
Get your balance.
Ready?
- Wait.
OK, l am still here.
All right.
lt's all you.
Look at me.
lt's all you, Chief.
Look at me, Dad.
Look at you.
You're doing it.
l am doing it.
- You're doing it.
How's it feel?
- Good.
This is great.
lt's like l am on a flying trapeze.
Look at you.
- This feels great.
You're going around the world.
- lt's like flying.
Wait will your mother sees this.
- Look at me.
Let's wake up the world, huh?
Oh, my God.
John Sullivan?
lt's me.
You're the voice of an angel.
Reached right out of heaven...
and you pulled my butt out of the fire.
Tell me l am not dreaming here.
Tell me it's really you.
lt's me, John.
This ain't no dream.
But how could it be?
l don't know.
But we got to be talking off
the mother sunspot of all time.
Yeah, l'd say so.
You OK, Chief?
Yeah, l am fine.
You sure?
Yeah, it's...
lt's tough to explain.
l mean, l got all these
new memories, but it's...
it's like l don't know what to believe.
What do you mean?
because l still remember what it was like...
when you died in the fire.
But l am the only one.
l don't understand
what you're talking about.
l remember both...
at the same time.
And...it's like waking up from a dream...
and you're not sure what's real.
l remember you being here, but l
also remember when you weren't.
l am sorry, John.
l am sorry.
l never thought that--
Well,
you got to think about that...
and you got to be more careful,
because l can't lose you again.
Not like that.
You won't, John.
You won't.
l swear to God,
no matter what, not like that.
You got it? You hear me?
You hear me, Chief?
l hear you.
So how old are you?
l am thirty-six.
Thirty-six.
You're all grown up.
You got to be married and everything.
No, l am not married.
What, you're too busy playing ball?
No, it didn't work out.
l gave it up.
What happened?
l just...blew my arm out my senior year.
Didn't have a shot.
Oh, l am sorry.
l am sorry, Johnny.
l know that had to hurt.
Yeah. Thanks.
So, what'd you wind up doing?
You join the department?
Actually, l went the other way.
l am a cop.
You're third-generation fire-fighter.
l thought you were going to
grow out of that cop phase.
You got Satch to thank for that one.
You got to be kidding me.
Satch.
He always crazy about you
ever since you were born.
You're still my Little Chief.
Right?
Yeah, l am trying to be.
l am trying.
Well, tell me about yourself.
Tell me about your life.
l mean,
where do l start, you know?
Mustang? l don't own a Mustang.
Well, you will,
and you loved it.
Fire-engine red.
Four on the floor.
Seventy home runs?
That's a record that will never be broken.
l wouldn't be too sure.
The other guy hit sixty-six.
Really? You mean like
those bigfield radios...
they use in the army?
No, much smaller.
Works off a satellite or something.
You carry it around in your pocket.
What about 'Apollo'?
How did it all work out?
lt was a great series, Pop.
Amazing.
We win, right?
Hold your horses.
l am getting there.
Game three,
Agee came through...
homered off Palmer in the second.
l knew Agee was going to have
a great series.
Forget about Agee.
Wait until you hear
what happened to Cleon Jones.
Now you sound like your mother.
- No, l am serious.
Come on. Your grandfather...
he smoked two packs a day,
and he's still kicking.
Not you. lt's going to get the better of you.
Well, l just knew.
She melted my heart.
That was it.
You got anybody?
Yeah. Kind of.
Something l got to work out,
but...
she's worth it.
No, you...go ahead.
You get some rest.
l am tired, too.
l almost don't want to click off here, like...
maybe we won't get this back.
We will.
l will be here tomorrow.
l know.
l love you, son.
l...
l love you, too, Dad.
And...
l have missed you so much.
Hi. This is Julia Sullivan.
Please leave a message after the tone.
Hey, Ma. lt's me.
Just call me. We got to talk.
Take over for me?
- All right.
Frank, what's going on?
Nothing. l just wanted to see you, that's all.
l am not going anywhere, Jules.
Not for the rest of your life.
l got a bad feeling today.
l was worried.
Look at me.
Not a scratch.
Where's Johnny?
He's at Gordo's.
l tucked him in.
You give him his drops?
One in each ear.
What would you do without me?
Probably marry some rich doctor.
Never have to work.
Oh, my God.
What is he doing?
Frank, l got to--
Excuse me, Doctor.
ls that Benazepril?
l gave this patient fifty mils of Benadryl.
Mix them and he's dead.
Why wasn't l informed?
- lt's in his chart.
Hello, Ma?
Noah's Deli.
Oh, no. Sorry.
This is Noah's Deli.
Sam, l got to talk to you.
Excuse me?
l am sorry,
but l got to talk to you.
How do you know my name?
Who are you?
Who am l?
Look. l don't know you.
You don't know me?
What do you mean,
you don't know me?
Wait. l do know you.
You're Linda and Gordo's friend.
The neighbour. The cop.
What are you doing here?
l shouldn't have come here.
l didn't mean to upset you.
l am sorry.
Yeah, l will take care of it.
What?
Another rough night?
ls that it?
Yeah, that's it.
Do not disrespect me, John.
Disrespect yourself all you want to...
but not me or anybody else here.
You got that?
We got the preliminary forensics
back on the skeleton.
You want to take a look at this.
Bad memories.
You imagine the odds of us
digging up a Nightingale murder?
She makes ten.
Ten?
No, l remember this case.
lt was three.
He killed three women.
What are you talking?
You know better than anybody,
John.
You looked at these files a thousand times.
Dad? You there?
Can you hear me?
Dad, l need you to be there.
Yeah. Yeah, Chief.
l am coming, l am coming.
Listen.
There's something l need to tell----
Right here, Chief.
Something happened.
Something pretty bad.
What's the matter, Johnny?
What is it?
Mom. Something happened to her.
Your mom? What?
She's not here.
What do you mean,
she's not there?
She died. But it's like
it just...happened, though.
She died?
Your mom just died?
No. Dad, it happened a long time ago.
A long time ago for me.
When?
October 22, 1969.
That's now, Johnny.
That's next week.
You got to tell me how.
She was murdered.
Murdered?
What are you talking about?
There was this case, a serial.
They never caught him,
but he murdered three women...
all nurses,
between 68th and 69th.
They call him the Nightingale.
The Nightingale?
We have been watching that
on the news. l was worried--
Dad, we did something.
Something to make it worse.
l don't understand.
He didn't just kill three women
anymore. He's killed ten.
Something we did changed the past.
But how come your mother--
Everything you did is different
than what would have happened.....
if you would have never
gotten out of that warehouse.
Now what'd you do last night,
Dad?
l talked to you.
l put you on the bike.
l tucked you in over at Gordo's...
and l went to see your mother
over at the hospital.
Oh, shit. That's it.
She wasn't supposed to be there.
Butch went and got her.
That was the night of the fire
when he brought her home.
You're saying something happened
at that hospital?
That's just the beginning.
lt could have been anywhere, place, time...
that she wouldn't have been
if you would have died.
l will take her away from here,
Johnny.
l have to take her away.
He cannot hurt her if l take her away.
What about the others, Dad?
l will warn them.
That will never work.
They will just think you're crazy.
But l got to do something.
l.....
You don't even know
what this guy looks like.
Nobody got any-- Hold on. Wait a minute.
Dad, l may not know who he is...
but l know where he's going to be...
and what he's going to do
before he gets there.
What do l do?
Do l call the police?
They're not going to believe me.
They will if they catch him in the act.
You can make that happen, Dad.
No, Johnny. l don't know.
l am a fire-fighter.
l am a cop.
This is what l do.
This is something we have to do.
What if the ham stops working?
What if l can't reach you?
Then you get Mom the hell out.
But, Dad, those other women
were not supposed to die.
lf we don't do something
and try to stop this guy...
we will have to live with that
for the rest of our lives.
OK, tell me what to do.
All right.
The next victim is Carrie Reynolds.
lt happens tomorrow.
Case file said she left
the Roosevelt Hospital at 6.00.
Showed up at Cozy's Bar around 6.30.
She walked out of that bar around 7.30...
and they found her dead in
an alley behind the bar at 8.00.
l want you to follow her...
see if anybody's watching her
or hitting on her.
because l am betting when she
walks out of that place...
somebody's going to come
out of there with her.
When they do,
you call the cops.
Hi, Carrie.
Hiya, Glen. How you doing?
Real good.
From the girls, pal.
Thanks.
l was...
Sit down.
Fireman, huh?
- Yeah. l am not really....
Ah, a married fireman.
What the hell.
What do they call you?
7-4 Homicide.
Yeah, it's me.
You're kidding.
Hold on. Spell that for me.
OK. Thanks, Mario.
Our lucky break.
Mario lD'd the dental.
Her name is Mary Finelli.
Reported missing April 16, 1968.
April 16?
That means she was the first.
Which means he probably knew her.
This case just got hot.
She's gone.
Carrie Reynolds isn't in here.
Who?
He did it.
Carrie Reynolds is alive and well, Dad.
l will be damned.
Did you see him?
Figure who he is?
- No, l messed up.
l just kept talking to her.
l was afraid to let her out of my sight.
Whoever it was,
he must have backed off.
That's OK. We're going to get him.
This is going to work.
l hope so.
So, what else you got?
We caught a break.
Found his first victim.
Her name is Mary Finelli.
Thanks, Mrs Sullivan.
- Hang on a sec, John.
Hey, Jules, there's somebody
l want you to talk to. OK?
Remember l told you about this guy, John?
l want you to say hello to him.
Say hello to my wife, Julia.
Frank tells me you're a cop.
Yeah, that's right.
My six-year-old keeps telling us
he wants to be a policeman...
right after he retires from the majors.
We just bought him a badge
and a whistle for his birthday.
Yeah, l remember. l used to play
cops and robbers all the time...
but you....my mom wouldn't
let me have a toy gun.
Sounds like your mom
and l would get along.
Yeah, she's pretty special.
l am real proud of her.
l bet she's proud of you, too.
Being a cop and all.
l hope so.
l hope she knows how much l love her.
Oh, she knows.
Moms always know how much
their kids love them.
Even if they don't tell them
all the time, like they should.
Well, l got to go.
lt was good talking to you,
John.
Yeah, you, too.
l want to talk on Daddy's radio.
OK, go ahead.
OK, sweetheart.
Say good night to John.
Good night, John.
Good night, there, Chief.
OK, guys. Bedtime.
No. l want to talk on the radio, too.
All right, Gordo. Come here.
OK, Gordo, two minutes,
then bedtime.
Sit right there.
Just one more cookie, Mom.
No more cookies.
- Just one more.
This is the space cowboy.
l am an intergalactic traveller...
from the Federation planet Earth.
How do you know my name, mister?
Listen, Gordo,
my name is Santa Claus.
l am going to give you...
the biggest Christmas present
that you ever had.
l better give you my address, then.
No, don't worry about it, kid.
This is important.
Something you got to remember
for a long time: Yahoo.
What's that?
lt's a magic word.
lt's like...
like abracadabra,
but even better.
Try it out, kid. Yahoo.
Yahoo.
You got it, Space Cowboy.
OK, Gordo.
Your two minutes are up.
Go upstairs and write it down.
OK, mister. l mean, Santa.
Come on. Let's go.
Stay there, John.
l will be right back.
Come on. Upstairs.
Jules, we got a live one
down here. Coming your way.
Yeah, Chief.
You still there?
Yeah. What do we do now?
Sissy Clark.
423 Greenwich Street--
Hang on. Go ahead.
Sissy Clark.
423 Greenwich Street,
Apartment 2E. Tomorrow.
OK. 2E.
Nurse. Moonlights as a cocktail waitress...
at the Kaleidoscope on West sixty-third.
Left work at 2.00 a.m.
Was killed in her apartment
between 2.15 and 5.00.
OK, l got it.
l don't know how long this thing
is going to keep working.
Hope we will be able to talk again.
Just be careful, all right?
l am happy you found her,
Detective.
lt makes it easier now to know for sure.
You know.
Can l keep these for a while,
Mrs Finelli?
OK, just let me walk you through it.
l am all ears.
Three guys show up in both
the yearbook and diary.
First guy passed away ten years ago.
Second guy died in Vietnam.
And the third one's Daryl Simpson.
So l ran him through B.C.l.
Got a hit.
Busted for sexual assault...
eight days after
the last Nightingale murder.
March 22, 1970.
You think the murders stopped
because he was off the street...
and by the time he got paroled...
he had smartened up enough
to control himself?
That's not the first time that's been true.
l got a feeling about this guy.
This is him, Satch.
Can l get you another one?
No, thanks. l am good.
Anything else?
Sexual assault, Daryl.
Five years.
But you got lucky, right?
You got away with something else.
Something you figured
nobody knows about.
What l know is what l told you.
Let me tell you what l know.
You went to St. Ambrose with Mary.
You lived five blocks from her...
and you liked her,
but she ain't interested.
That must have hurt, huh?
- So what?
So what'd you do about it?
- Nothing.
Can l have a smoke?
Here. l am trying to quit.
Oh, my God. What is this?
Ah, Jesus.
Get that away from me.
Sandra Moore. Patti Ryan.
Mary Finelli.
These names mean anything to you, pal?
Julia Sullivan.
Does she mean anything?
Well, she means something to me.
See you, fireman.
Don't talk so much next time.
Gus, will you run my
tips while l go change?
Sure, Sissy.
- Thanks.
You know, Daryl...
sometimes,
despite all the training...
that we cops go through...
despite all that we are taught
about right and wrong...
despite all that we would
like to honour in ourselves...
we can come to a place...
where we don't give a damn.
Know what l mean?
You're going to tell me
everything l need to know.
John. You got a minute?
Yeah. Sure.
He ain't the guy, John.
Just because he didn't want
to look at the photos...
doesn't mean he isn't the one.
Not everyone fits the profile.
lf he was going to give up something...
he would have done it already.
You following me?
Huh? You following me?
l asked you a question, asshole.
Mary Finelli.
Dude, what happened to him?
lt was a bad trip, man.
A little time kissing
the porcelain, he will be fine.
Yeah, l understand that.
All right. Come on, pal.
Open up. Miss Clark.
Open the door.
lt's the police.
lt's OK, ma'am. Go back inside.
Are you in there? Open up.
l know you're in there.
Sissy Clark. Open the door.
Open the door.
He killed her.
l couldn't do a damn thing to stop it.
Dad, it's not your fault.
Yes, it is.
We changed everything, Johnny.
lt's like we cheated.
Dad? We can't go back...
because you didn't die in that fire.
No matter what you do,
nothing is going to change it.
All we can do is deal with this
and try to make it right.
l am not a cop.
l am not fooling anybody.
l know, but we can.
We can do it together.
Remember spirit and guts?
John,
he's got my driver's licence.
What?
He took my driver's licence.
He knows where we live.
He took your dr....
He took your wallet?
Well, he tossed the wallet,
but he kept the licence.
He touched your wallet?
Where's your wallet?
lt's in my pocket.
We got him, Dad. You got him.
His prints. You got his prints.
You got to get me that wallet.
How the hell am l supposed to do that?
As carefully as possible.
Take your wallet out,
but just touch the corners.
What are you talking about?
- Just do it.
OK, all right.
All right.
Right.
- OK. All right. l got it.
All right. Now. Listen.
l want you to wrap it up.
Put it in one of them plastic bags...
you keep extra transistors in.
Yeah. l see where you're going.
Beautiful. OK.
Now hide it somewhere.
Somewhere where nobody's going to
find it for the next 30 years.
l think maybe....
- Where?
The window seat in the dining room.
There's a loose board
on the left, on the bottom.
Perfect. Beautiful.
lt's in.
Great. OK, l am after it.
We're in business.
Now just sit tight and don't worry.
And the winner is....
Oh, man. lt's a cop.
What the hell?
Son of a bitch.
Hey, Mr Shepard.
How are you?
Who's that?
Oh, hi, Detective.
l just came by to wrap things up over there.
Thought l'd say hello.
Glad you did. Come on in.
Thank you.
Buy you a cup of coffee?
- Sure.
Black? Sugar? Milk?
You know. lt's all good.
You will get black.
Fresh pot.
You know Jack?
No. Not really.
He still on the job?
He does a little P.l. work now and then...
but he's mostly retired.
Living off his pension, huh?
Jack got caught up
in them Knapp hearings.
Set up by some dirty cops
who needed a fall guy.
Hurt him bad. Would have
broke his mother's heart.
ls she around?
Who?
- Your wife.
No. She passed on.
Long time ago.
l am sorry.
That's OK.
Can l ask how she died?
Well, she...
she was murdered, Detective.
An ugly one,
to tell you the truth.
Mother of a cop...
and they never found the bastard who did it.
You on the job?
A long time ago.
Do l know you?
l look familiar?
What house you work?
The 7-4 Homicide.
A hotshot.
No, just...working the job.
Yeah, l hear that, pal.
As a matter of fact...
l caught a case that goes back to your day.
One of the Nightingale murders.
No kidding?
No. Missing teenager.
Disappeared back in '68.
They found her bones last week...
buried behind some diner
out by Dyckman Street.
Mary Finelli.
Yeah, talk about dumb luck.
The odds of anybody finding
that girl thirty years later...
and the chances of hitting a dental--
Forget about it.
The best part is,
she's the first victim.
And she knew the killer.
So...
l am betting those old bones
are going to do a lot of talking.
Not for nothing.
The past is a funny thing.
We all have skeletons in the closet.
You never know when they will
pop up and bite you in the ass.
Huh, Jack?
You changed your m.o.
because if they knew your mother
was a Nightingale...
they would have looked at the family.
They would have looked at you.
What are you looking at?
Stealing your life away.
You went down thirty years ago,
pal.
You just don't know it yet.
A cop? He's a cop?
What am l supposed to do with that?
Call the F.B.l.
Use a pay phone.
Don't give them your name, Dad.
Tell them Shepard killed Finelli
and Clark and the others...
that he's the Nightingale.
Then, tell them where Finelli's buried.
They will be able to connect him to her.
They search his place,
they will find some souvenirs.
He always took a piece of
jewellery from his victims.
What are you doing here?
Are you off today?
We need to have a conversation.
Dad?
- Hang on a sec, John.
l am kind of in the middle
of something important here.
Mind if we do this--
- l am sorry, Frank.
We need to step outside right now.
Dad, what's going on?
John, Satch is here,
and he's with his partner.
What the hell's going on?
Hang on a sec.
What's your partner doing here?
What happened to your eye?
l banged it up.
Let's go outside and talk.
We need to do that.
About what?
Let's go,
do us both a favour, huh?
All right.
Stay there, John.
l will be right back.
Be right back. All right?
Where were you last night,
Frank?
Where do you think l was, Satch?
Same place l found this.
Under the body of a dead woman.
No. This isn't what you think, OK?
This isn't what you think.
l want to be wrong here.
Let's take a ride to the precinct and talk.
l want to talk to you, too.
l need to talk to you.
Come on.
We will take a ride.
Let me just go inside,
tell my family where l am going.
All right?
Be right back.
Everything's all right.
Don't worry.
Chief, you there?
They found Sissy Clark.
They think l did it.
Just give me a second.
You have got to talk to Satch.
What's going on?
Uncle Satch, stop.
He's a cop.
- A cop?
Jack Shepard.
He's a detective at the 15th Precinct.
l swear, Satch.
And you got all of this
from the guy on the radio.
From your son in the future.
Yeah.
As nuts as that sounds, yeah.
You got to listen to me, Satch.
You got to open up your mind....
You got to understand what l am saying.
You got something going on with this girl...
that's one thing.
But you got to tell me.
Are you listening to me?
You're in a world of shit.
An eyewitness put you outside
the dead girl's apartment.
Your prints are all over the place...
not to mention
the goddamn driver's licence.
Chuck is getting
a search warrant for your house.
What's he going to find there?
- Nothing.
You got to give me something,
something l can believe.
What if l can prove it to you?
How's that?
World Series.
Where are they right now?
What, fourth, fifth inning?
What if l was to tell you...
that in the bottom of the sixth inning...
the Mets are going to be down three-zip?
And Cleon Jones,
he's going to come to bat.
He's going to get hit in the foot
by a wild pitch.
And it's going to leave
a shoe polish mark on the ball.
Hear me out, all right?
He goes to first.
Clendendon comes up.
He's going to hit a two-two pitch
into the left-field bleachers.
This is insane, Frank.
ln the bottom of the seventh,
Weis hits a solo home run.....
and then Jones and Swoboda
score in the eighth.
The Mets, they're going to win,
five to three.
Go watch.
lf it don't happen, l am a liar.
Watch the game?
Watch the game.
Frank, they're going to make you
for Sissy Clark's murder.
And they're going to match that
with the Nightingale murders.
Do you understand what that means?
His wife is here.
She wants to talk to you.
One-two pitch to Anderson.
Fly ball to right.
Let's walk, Jules.
Get a cup of coffee.
The guy went crazy.
Know what l mean?
Started tearing things apart.
Throwing things.
How you doing?
You got a collar in here
for the Nightingale murders?
Everything OK with you and Frank?
Yeah, we're good. He works hard.
l work hard. We're good.
Who's Sissy Clark, Satch?
Do you know where Frank was last night?
Yeah. He was working.
He had a tour.
Sit down.
Did you just hear what l said?
So how'd you know?
How you doing?
- What's up in here?
Shut up, asshole.
He tried to kill me.
Go find Satch.
Find Satch.
He's trying to kill me.
What are you doing with my collar?
Sorry, pal. l didn't mean
to step on your toes.
They sent me up from downstairs.
l thought you'd be in there with him.
What are you looking at him for?
He matches a description
of an armed-robbery suspect.
So tell me about the radio.
Who's he talking to on that thing?
John. He's a cop.
He talks to him all the time.
l have talked to him, too.
You talked to Johnny on the radio?
John. What's going on, Satch?
You come into my house,
take Frank...
and now you're talking to me like a cop.
l am talking to you as a friend.
because as a cop,
l wouldn't be here at all.
Listen, Jules, they're going to
take me off this case.
Then Frank is going to tell them
what he's been telling me.
And then nobody is going to
be able to help him. OK?
...left field, and Cleon Jones
makes the catch.
Half the uniforms are either
at the game or on the street.
lt's going to be a riot if they pull it off.
What is he telling us, Satch?
That he's talking to Johnny on the radio.
Yeah. John the cop.
l told you that.
No. He says that John is your son, Johnny.
Little Johnny on the radio in the future.
On the radio. You see?
No. You misunderstood him.
Jules? Sissy Clark?
She's a nurse,
and she was murdered yesterday.
And Frank is connected.
He is either a material witness...
or an accomplice or the perpetrator.
...McNally, who's been
thoroughly in command.
Cleon starts down to first base,
and DeMiro calls him back.
Satch, you know him. You know
he didn't do this, right?
Hodges showing the baseball to DeMiro.
Can l see him?
Hodges--We might have
a shoe polish play here.
Remember the Nippy Jones
shoe polish play...
in the 1957 World Series at Milwaukee?
Hodges showing it to Lou DeMiro,
who awards first base.
My God.
Satch, what's going on?
Mind if l go back at the fireboy for a while?
l just want to see what he's got.
Jesus.
Way back in leftfield.
Hey, bud.
See if aviation's got a helicopter.
Respond to my location
for commencing an air search...
for body in water, OK?
lt was a season and World Series
for the ages...
for the Mets and Series M.V.P.
first baseman Donn Clendendon.
For the Mets faithful,
the New York fans--Wow.
With the streets of midtown
and Times Square...
still packed with celebrating fans...
Here's your coffee and your cigarettes.
ln the skies over New York...
another amazing event
is coming to a close.
lt's time to say goodbye
to the northern lights...
l will be upstairs.
...that have been lighting up the skies.
Astronomists say
the incredible sun storms...
that have created the remarkable
aurora borealis...
have begun to cool...
and the auroras,
already dimming...
will be over by morning.
John, are you there?
John, l am back.
l am here, Dad.
We did it, son.
- What?
We stopped him.
- We did?
Something's wrong.
l don't re--
What? What's wrong?
lf we stopped him,
why isn't Mom here?
Why don't l remember her being OK?
But...l killed him.
He's dead.
My turn to steal your life away.
John, are you there?
Hey, bud.
Julia?
Oh, Julia.
Mommy?
Hey. lt's OK.
lt's OK, you little rascal.
What are you going to do, Frank?
Put the gun down.
Let him go.
Well, put the gun down.
l will snap his neck.
Put the gun down now.
Time to die, Sullivan.
Run, Johnny. Run.
Come here.
You all right?
l am still here, Chief.
l got it. Mine.
Come on, Johnny.
Round the horn.
OK. Come on, Frank.
Come on.
No batter, no batter, no batter.
Come on, Frank. Yes.
The Benz. Not the Benz.
No. God, not the Benz.
Oh, my God.
Nice hit, Frank.
Way to go.
Thank you very much.
Let's play some ball.
- You will pay for that.
Come on.
No batter, no batter, no batter.
Go get it.
He's slow, he's old.
Bring me home, Chief.