Got another one coming
down, Mike.
Hang on a sec.
Huh?
Hey!
Aah!
I got those...
Concert tickets you wanted.
Oh, you're kidding?
For Friday night?
Stanley, this is great.
Oh, yeah.
What time should I pick you up?
Well, see, here's the thing.
My very best girlfriend
just came into town.
She'd die to go to this,
so could we get an
extra ticket for her?
Ooh.
They're out.
They're sold out.
That means there's no more.
Oh.
I can't let her sit
home all alone.
Look, I'll tell you what.
Why don't you just
go with your friend?
Oh, Stanley,
I couldn't do that.
No. Come on.
Stanley, you are the
nicest guy.
Really, you are.
Yeah?
Charlie, isn't
Stanley the nicest guy?
The best.
Ohh.
That was the most
sickening display
I've ever seen.
I disagree.
I think I'm wearing her down.
You know what you need?
You need a little change of pace.
Tonight I'm going to
take you on a love safari,
deep into the darkest
heart of the urban jungle.
Tell me more, bwana.
The coco bongo club.
Hottest new joint in town.
Only the crème de
la crème need apply.
So how do we get in?
What, are you kidding?
Leave it to me.
Trust me.
Buddy, this is going to be
the perfect night on the town.
[Thunder]
Hold the phone.
Killer at 3:00.
Stand back...
And observe.
Excuse me.
Where can I open a new account?
New accounts, right here.
You're lucky you caught me.
Could you hold this, please?
I will hold anything you want.
Thank you.
Can you help me?
Ohh.
So...
What kind of account
do you have in mind?
Well, I'm not sure exactly.
You see, I'm just...
terrible with things like that.
That's an interesting
tie, mister...
Ipkiss.
Stanley Ipkiss.
Tina Carlyle. Pleased to meet you.
The pleasure's all mine.
May I?
May you what?
I'm such a mess.
Oh, of course.
That's what they're there for.
As I was saying about that tie,
it kind of reminds
me of one of those,
what do you call it?
Inkblot tests.
Rorschach test.
Right.
You know,
it sort of looks like, um...
A young woman riding bareback,
sort of a...
Lady godiva or something.
Of course.
What do you see,
Mr. Ipkiss?
Um...
I--I--I
don't know.
[Whistles]
[Gags]
Uh...
Bright colors.
It--it's a power tie.
It's supposed to make you feel...
Powerful.
Does it work?
Now, uh...
How--how about that account, huh?
Uh, we have, uh,
several different plans--
savings...
Checking,
savings and checking,
Cds,
savings and Cds,
checking and Cds,
savings, checking, and Cds,
T-bills.
Or we could just take
a ll your money and
throw it in a big mattress
back there.
Ha ha!
[Camera lens focusing]
Now, I have some forms
you'll have to fill out.
[Banging]
That's it, sweetheart.
Now just a little bit to the right.
Beautiful.
Will you guys keep
it down back there?
No problem.
So what do you think?
Well, it's not bad,
but them motion detectors
are a pain in the ass.
You can pull this off, right?
Hey, you talking to the doctor.
I do have one question.
Which is...
What does Niko have
to say about all this?
Nothing.
This ain't his grift, man.
Get real, man.
Everything is his grift.
He owns you, he owns this club,
he owns this whole stinking town.
Things change.
You mess with Niko,
you end up taking a dirt nap.
He's the only one who's napping.
And I'm about to give him
a serious wake-up call.
But we need some cash,
so first we take the bank,
then we take Niko,
and then, my friend,
school is out...
And this whole city
is our playground.
Ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
[Horn honks]
Uhh!
Watch where you're going!
[Honk honk]
[Opera music plays]
[Drill buzzes]
Hello?
Hang on! Hang on!
Don't get your panties
in a twist, would ya?
Hey, Burt, what the hell is this?
Oh, I don't know. Uh...
About 700 bucks, irv.
Uh, now, uh...
What can I do for you?
I'm, uh, here for the civic.
The brake drums are shot,
and you need a new transmission.
What?
All I wanted was an oil change.
Well, you're lucky you
caught these problems now
before they cause serious trouble.
Sign, uh, right here
and press down hard.
There's no price.
There will be.
I don't have a car.
I have to have a car tonight.
Irv! Yo!
Bring around...
The loaner.
The loaner?
♪ Yeah, bartender
♪ I got a lover, but
it's not what it seems ♪
♪ she poured me a drink
♪ you know what I mean
♪ don't mix it up,
give me straight ♪
[Tires screech]
[Engine backfires]
[Coughs]
Eww! Eww!
It's a classic.
[Metal jangling]
Hi.
Charlie.
Stanley.
Gals, I want you to meet
my buddy Stanley Ipkiss,
humongo in the banking business.
Ha ha ha! Not really.
What do you say we
get in this joint, huh?
Yo, Bobby.
How you doing, buddy?
It's Charlie.
Hey, Charlie, how ya doing?
How are ya?
Long time no see.
Good to see you.
O.K., then.
Come on, gals.
See y'all inside.
Ooh.
Bobby?
Uh, Charlie.
Charlie!
It's a mistake.
Hey, hey.
Whoa!
You crossed the rope.
Never cross the rope.
No, but my
friends are--
lose him.
Hey, come on now, guys.
Watch it! I'm a bleeder!
Put me down right now,
or I'm never coming back here.
Ohh!
Thanks.
Aw, jeez.
Mr. Ipkiss.
Hi.
[Tires screech]
You o.K.?
Me?
Oh...
I'm great.
Really good.
I just never felt better, really.
I--I'm
just, uh...
Catching some air out here.
Your car, sir.
That's not my car.
It matches the ticket.
All right.
I'll take it.
But I am very angry!
Do you believe this?
You drive in in a Porsche...
[Engine sputtering]
[Engine backfires]
[Engine rattles]
[Engine dies]
[Trying ignition]
Oh...Gee!
[Thud]
Ow!
Aah! [Hiss]
Aah!
Ugh!
God!
[Thunder]
Hey!
Hey, mister!
Hold on!
I know cpr.
Hey, you!
What are you doing down there?
Uh...
I'm...Just looking for...
My mask!
I got it!
[Slosh slosh slosh]
Ipkiss! Do you have any
idea what time it is?
Actually, no.
[Gasps]
My new carpet!
Well, this is coming right out
of your security deposit, Ipkiss.
You know,
Mrs. Peenman--
what?
Nothing.
Well, that's what
you are, Ipkiss--
a big nothing!
Aren't you due back
at the laboratory
to get your bolts tightened?
I should have said that.
[Slosh slosh]
[Arf arf arf]
Hey, you.
Why, hello.
You know you're not
supposed to jump up.
It's against doggie ordinance.
O.K.
[Boing]
[Wolf whistle]
[Awoo]
[Whistling]
[Honk honk]
What do you want?
You want me to throw that?
I'm very tired.
O.K. I'll throw it one time.
I ain't gonna throw it
with you attached to it.
Ow.
You ready?
Git it!
Ipkiss!
Turn down those cartoons!
All right, Mrs. Peenman!
[Woman] I say don't bother.
I kind of think that I...
So, Dr. neuman, you're saying
that everybody wears a mask?
That's correct, Wendy.
We all wear masks,
metaphorically speaking.
We suppress the ID,
our darkest desires,
and adopt a more
socially acceptable image.
The book is, of course,
the masks we wear,
by Dr. Arthur Neuman.
Thank you so much
for being with us.
[Growling]
What's the matter with you?
[Whimpering]
What is it?
What are you looking for, huh?
You like this thing?
You like it?
The masks we wear.
That's correct, Wendy.
We all wear masks...
Metaphorically speaking.
Yeah, right.
Uh!
[Moaning]
Ssssmokin'!
It's party time.
P-a-r-t...
Y?
Because I...
Gotta!
Shh.
[Giggling and ringing]
[Ring] Ha ha ha ha ha!
Hey.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
[Screeching]
Ooh hoo hoo hoo hoo!
Snooooze.
Aah!
Ahh ha ha ha ha!
Ooh hoo hoo hoo ha!
[Muffled] Uh-oh.
Look, ma, I'm road kill!
Ha ha ha!
[Honk]
[Honk honk honk]
Get out of the road!
I think he wants to communicate.
[Honk honk]
[Bah-hooooooo-yah]
Heh heh heh heh.
Hey, mister!
You got the time?
As a matter of fact, I do, cubby.
You wanna take him?
[Tick tick tick]
Look at that!
It's exactly two seconds
before I honk your nose
and pull your underwear
over your head.
[Squeak]
Oof!
Come on!
Take him! Come on!
Step right up here!
Don't be shy.
Nobody likes a bashful leatherhead!
Move it!
For my first trick...
I'm going to do
something for you, son.
We have...A giraffe!
There ya go, son. Now, get
outta here. You bother me.
Thanks.
Wow!
Now...
Sorry. Wrong pocket.
[Woman] Ha ha ha.
For you, son...
A little body English.
A French poodle.
[Pop]
Sorry, son.
The dog was rabid.
Had to put it down.
And last but not least,
my favorite!
A tommy-gun!
[Meow rooow]
This is incredible.
With these powers,
I could be...
A superhero!
I could fight crime,
protect the innocent,
work for world peace!
But first...
[Crash]
Hold on to your lug nuts!
It's time for an overhaul!
What's that?
Aah!
Ohh!
Ohh.
Ahh.
It was a dream.
Ha ha ha.
Ohh.
I gotta lay off the cartoons.
[Knock on door]
Ipkiss? Stanley Ipkiss?
Yes.
Lieutenant Kellaway.
City precinct.
Do you know anything about
the disturbance last night?
Dis...turbance?
Yeah. A prowler broke in
and attacked Mrs. Peenman.
Attacked?
You didn't hear anything?
She unloaded several
rounds of 20-odd buckshot
5 feet from your door.
Look at the floor! See that?
He put that right in my floor,
then he jumped out
the window, officer!
This is...
Impossible.
Those pajamas are impossible.
This actually happened.
Uh, see, I have, uh...
An inner ear problem.
Sometimes I can't hear anything.
That a fact?
Eh?
Here's my card.
If you remember anything
unusual about last night,
anything at all,
call me.
You betcha. Thank you.
And, uh, good luck, uh...
Crackin' the case.
Oh, my God. I'm late!
Keys. Keys.
Where are the keys?
Damn.
Milo!
Get the keys.
Get 'em. Find 'em.
Get the keys!
[Thud]
Ow! Jeez.
I am so late.
[Arf]
Good boy. Good boy!
Come on, boy.
Give them to me.
Drop it.
Easy. Watch the bump!
I want a proctologist standing by.
What?
You heard me. The
best one you can find.
I'm with the evening star.
Can you tell me what happened?
No, and you can quote me.
It looks like a mob tactic.
There it is, boys.
She broke the case.
Get these rubbernecks out of here.
Officer, please.
Can you tell us, sir...
Hey, Stan. Stan, Stan!
Where were you last night?
The girls and I were
looking all over for you.
Did you happen to look
outside... In the gutter?
You check the morning paper?
Your girlfriend got
a great review.
Ipkiss, you're 40 minutes late.
That's the same as stealing.
I'm sorry, Mr. dickey.
It'll never happen
again. I've been a...Jerk.
Well, if you weren't busy
oogling girlie pictures,
you might actually get
some work done around here.
Uh, sir, she's a prospective
client of Stanley's.
Oh, really?
Well...
The next time she comes in,
you be sure to send
her to my office.
Oh ho. You betcha.
Gee, I wish my
daddy owned a bank...
Then I could be a
rich little creep, too.
You think she'll ever
come back, Charlie?
Oh, man. Forget her.
Stanley, listen to me.
A girl like that is always
looking for the b.B.D.--
the bigger, better deal.
You don't know that.
She's an artist.
She's sensitive.
Stanley, forget her. That girl
will tear out your heart,
put it in a blender,
and hit "frapee."
You don't need her, man.
You need somebody a
little more down to earth,
somebody with some integrity,
somebody with...
Red hair...
And full pouting lips,
a white blouse, a green
jacket, and a name tag.
Boy, you really narrowed it down.
Too bad she's already taken.
Hel-lo there. May I
be of some assistance?
Stanley Ipkiss?
Oh. Hi.
I'm Peggy Brandt from
the tribune.
Oh. Hi.
Look, I canceled my subscription
because they kept
stealing my paper from--
oh, no, no.
Actually, I just want to
ask you a few questions.
Really? About what?
Ripley auto finishing.
You're a customer of
theirs, aren't you?
Me?
No.
I don't even have a car.
You know, 'cause they...
Pollute.
You don't own an '89 civic?
Oh, that car. Yeah.
Uh...Yeah.
It's all coming back to me.
Miss, uh, what is your name?
Peggy Brandt.
Wait a minute.
Peggy Brandt?
Of ask Peggy?
Yeah.
That's right.
You printed one of
my letters last year.
Remember? Nice guys finish last.
You're Mr. nice guy?
Yes!
Oh, Stanley.
Do you realize how much mail
we got about that letter?
There are hundreds
of women out there
looking for a guy just like you.
Really?
Yeah!
Do you know how hard it is
to find a decent man in this town?
Most of them think monogamy
is some kind of wood.
So, uh...
Why are you covering this story?
Because dear Peggy pays dick.
I'm starving to death.
I'm looking to become
a real reporter.
Look, Stanley, when
you were at Ripley auto,
did you see anything suspicious?
I won't make trouble for you.
I just want the truth.
God, I wish I knew the truth.
You know? I really do.
No.
Well, if you think of anything,
this is my number.
This is my, you
know, personal number.
You really think
hundreds of women
are looking for a guy like me?
Sure.
I'm one of 'em.
Bye.
[Blip blip blip blip]
[Computer's voice]
120 yards.
Hello, Dorian.
Thanks for dropping by.
Yeah, well,
next time why don't
you call, all right?
Leave the delivery boys at home.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
The cops, uh...
Tried to shut the
club down this morning.
They say you've
been using the place
to run your own small-time scams.
I hear things like that,
I start losing my concentration,
and my game...
It goes straight to hell.
You could, too.
Ah!
205 yards.
I'm fed up with you, Dorian.
But...
I'm going to
cut you a break--
one week to get out of town.
After that...
I'll use your empty little skull
to break in my new 9-iron.
♪ See you lookin'
♪ she's a work of art
♪ but nothing can save you ♪
♪ from your own heart
♪ ba da ba da do
♪ ba do ba do ba do
Mr. Ipkiss.
Hi.
You o.K.?
Your car, sir.
I am now.
♪ I'm just a ba-by
♪ nobody ever helps me
♪ somebody save me
♪ I'm just a baby
♪ when there's
business in love ♪
♪ da da da do do da...
Tina, come on.
[Whimpering]
You can't.
Ahh.
Milo.
Oh, go on.
Oh.
I don't believe it.
Stupid.
She would
never--
no way.
[Arf arf]
Hold on, sugar.
Daddy's got a sweet tooth tonight!
Ha ha ha!
Ooh!
Sssomebody stop me!
Uh-oh.
Can't make the scene if
you don't have the green.
I'd better make a little stop.
How's it going, Freeze?
Lookin' good here, my man.
O.K. You boys are on your own now.
I got to get downstairs
and make sure I'm seen.
Do it.
The doctor is about to operate.
[Drilling]
Sorry, fellas.
Waste not, want not.
Cops!
Come on, dude.
You're not on the list,
you're not in the club, all right?
[Horn plays call to post]
Whoa! Oh! Whoa!
How do?
Whoa! Ho ho ho.
Uh...
Are you on the list?
Uh, nooooo....
But I believe my friends are.
Perhaps you
know them--
Franklin, grant, and...
Jackson.
Stay back. Nobody's getting in.
And we present to you
the most beautiful
flower of the coco bongo,
miss Tina Carlyle.
[Applause]
Beautiful.
♪ Love makes me treat you
♪ the way that I do
♪ gee, baby
♪ ain't I good to you?
♪ There's nothing too good
♪ for a boy, that's so true ♪
♪ gee, baby
♪ ain't I good to you?
♪ I bought you a fur
coat for Christmas ♪
♪ a diamond ring
♪ Cadillac car
♪ and everything
♪ love makes me treat you
♪ the way that I do
♪ gee, baby
♪ ain't I good to you?
♪ Love
♪ makes me treat you
♪ the way that I do
♪ gee, baby
♪ ain't I good to you?
♪ There's nothin' too good ♪
♪ for a man, so true
♪ gee, honey
♪ ain't I good to you?
♪ I know how to make
♪ a good man happy
♪ I treat you right
♪ with lotsa love...
What the hell are you doing here?
We got trouble. You
better come upstairs.
Come on. Let's go.
♪ Gee, baby
♪ ain't I good to you?
Awoo!
Arf, arf, arf!
Woo, woo, woo!
♪ For what I gave to you
♪ gee, baby, ain't
I good to you? ♪
[Whistles]
Let's rock this joint!
Yeah! Uh-huh!
[Playing swing]
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Pachuco! Pachuco!
♪ From 4:00 to 3:00
♪ the man's gunnin' for me ♪
♪ I'm doin' winding
road tonight ♪
Hey! Hey! Hey!
♪ See them that cried
♪ the cats living
down east side? ♪
♪ may be just my
friends tonight ♪
Smokin'!
Aw, man.
What happened?
Somebody hit the joint
before we could.
Here, doctor.
Here you go, buddy. Suck on that.
Son of a bitch!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Eddie, who did this, man?
Who?
Him.
Him!
That's--
that's the guy.
That guy dancing with Tina?
He's dead meat.
Come on.
Aah!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
♪ Do it for me
♪ I'm doin' winding
road tonight ♪
Hey! Hey! Hey!
♪ See them that cried
♪ the cats living
down east side? ♪
I want this place
cleared right now!
Eeeeeee!
Hello.
Club's closed. Move it!
You think I'm joking?
Come on! Move it!
Everyone. Let's go!
Tina, get out of here.
Come on. Party's over.
Get lost!
O.K., twinkle toes.
I want to know
where my money is--
right now!
O.K.
You've got 17.5% in t-bills
amortized over the fiscal year,
8% in stock and bonds.
Carry the 9. Divide by
the gross national product.
Fortunately, funeral
bouquets are deductible.
Ice this deadbeat!
Whoo!
Shoot him!
Toro!
Hi hi hi hi hi.
Thank you very much.
Hoo. Hah.
Ooh!
Ya...Got me...Partner.
Eee...Ah...Ooh.
Ooh...Ah...Eee.
Ah...Ugh...Ahh.
Argh!
Hold me close, red.
It's gettin' dark.
[Coughing]
Tell aunty em to
let old yeller out.
[Cough cough]
Eew.
[English accent] Tell tiny Tim
I won't be coming
home this Christmas.
Tell Scarlett I do give a damn.
[Sniffling]
[Pffft]
Pardon me.
Thank you!
You love me.
You really love me!
You're not goin' anywhere.
Whoo hoo hoo hoo!
Drop it, tyrrell!
Hey, Kellaway.
Drop it!
All right.
So you got a warrant this time,
or you just stopped
by for a nightcap?
What I got is probable cause.
Couple of your boys were spotted
knocking over edge city bank.
Easy. You're giving me a woody.
One was wearing a green mask.
For once, Kellaway, you're right.
Except it wasn't one of my boys.
Maybe if you tried a little
actual police work...
Cuff him.
Hey, lieutenant.
A stiff upstairs--
one of the guys from the heist.
Better call that high-priced
lawyer of yours, tyrrell.
You and I are going downtown
for a little chat.
Get him outta here!
Ipkiss.
[Knock on door]
Ipkiss, I know you're in there.
[Knock knock knock]
Police!
Oh!
Open up.
Oh, my God!
[Knock knock knock]
Uh...
Ipkiss, I know you're in there!
[Knock knock knock]
[Growling]
[Arf arf]
Open up.
Come on. I'm getting
blisters on my fingers.
No...No!
[Grr]
No, no, no!
Stop it!
I'm coming!
O.K., I'm coming!
I'll be right there.
[Arf arf]
Let's go! Ipkiss!
Move it!
All right!
[Unlocking bolts]
Hi, lieutenant.
Listen, this isn't the
best time right now--
I just...
Won't you come in?
Where were you last night, Ipkiss?
Here...Mostly.
Is something wrong?
What do you know about
this mask character?
Mask?
Don't insult my
intelligence, Ipkiss.
He robs your bank,
then I find this in the coco bongo.
There can't be two idiots
with pajamas like these.
Milo, no!
May I see those
pajamas, Mr. Ipkiss?
Those...Pajamas?
Those--those,
uh,
those pajamas were...
Stolen.
Somebody stole your pajamas?
Yeah.
[Growling]
I mean, uh,
what is, uh,
what is this city coming to
when--when, uh, when
a man's pajama drawer
is no longer safe?
Wow, look at that guy.
Nobody's that fast at my bank.
I'll say.
Ahh.
I don't know, boss,
that's one hell of a rubber mask.
What about lab reports?
We got some fingerprints
on some of the currency,
but nothing matches tyrrell's men.
This guy beat him to the punch.
Get the bank employee files
and run down the prints
of a Stanley Ipkiss.
You figure it was an inside job?
All I need is prints to lock
this whack job up till doomsday.
50 grand.
50 grand to the man
who finds that
green-faced son of a bitch
before the cops do.
I want you to get the word out
to every street hustler, to
every lowlife in this town.
You understand?
I want him here tomorrow... Alive.
You're still here?
Come on, let's go!
What are you lookin' at?
You.
You're losing it, Dorian.
Uh-uh.
I'm not losing anything...
Except maybe some extra
baggage around here.
What does that mean?
You weren't putting
up much of a fight
when that freak show
tried to kiss you.
Did it look like
I had much of a choice?
Maybe you did...
Maybe you didn't.
Who knows, right?
I'll tell you one thing.
It's going to be payback
for anybody who crosses me.
Ipkiss!
We have a crisis here,
and you stroll in an hour late?
If I have to put up with
your slovenly behavior--
back off, monkey boy...
Before I tell daddy
you're running this place like
it's your own personal piggy bank.
Or maybe we should call the IRS?
See if we can arrange a little
vacation for you at club fed!
That'll be all, Ipkiss.
[Deep exhalation]
Genius.
That was genius.
Buddy, I have chills.
God! What side of whose
bed did you wake up on, man?
I'm not sure.
I haven't exactly
been myself lately.
Well, you don't look
real fabulous, Stan.
Really?
Do I look bad?
Ah! Not to worry.
This will put the color
back in your cheeks.
Two tickets to the charity ball
at the coco bongo club
this Saturday night.
Everybody will be there.
Want to be my date?
Ah,
Charlie, I--
wait just a minute.
Tina, what are you doing here?
I wanted to thank you, but, um...
I'm not sure I'll have much
to open an account with.
What about the club? I
thought you were doing great.
Look, it's not your problem.
I'll be o.K.
Tina, come here.
You didn't stop by
just to see me, did you?
It's o.K. Tell me.
The guy they say
robbed this place...
The mask.
I think he was at
the club last night.
Really?
They say he's pretty...
Weird-looking.
Yeah, but...
You ought to see him dance.
So did, um,
anyone find out who he is?
Why, are you interested?
Just curious, I guess.
Well...
I better be going.
Thanks for everything, Stanley.
You'd like to see him
again, wouldn't you?
I, um...
Wouldn't mind.
I know him, you know.
You do?
We're old college
buddies, him and me.
Yeah, it's funny you should mention
the way he dances because, uh...
I taught him a couple
of dance moves myself.
Do you think you could
have him meet me tonight?
I might be able to
work something out.
How about at landfill park?
O.K., at sunset?
Perfect.
Super.
Thanks, Stanley. You
really are a nice guy.
This is an interesting
piece, Mr. Ipkiss.
Looks like fourth or
fifth century Scandinavian.
Possibly a representation
of a norse night God.
Maybe loki.
Loki?
Who's loki?
The norse God of mischief.
Supposedly he caused
so much trouble
that odin banished him
from Valhalla forever.
Then he could've banished
him into that mask.
I'm talking about
mythology, Mr. Ipkiss.
This is a piece of wood.
But your book!
My book is about masks
as metaphor, Mr. Ipkiss.
A metaphor. Not to
be taken literally.
You're suffering
from mild delusion.
Ohh!
All right.
I'm going to prove it to you.
But I am not responsible
for the consequences.
Just sit back and enjoy
the ride, Mr. expert.
You don't scare me, Mr.
Ipkiss. Go right ahead.
See ya.
Coo-yaah!
Whoooo!
[Moaning]
Whoo-hoo!
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Yee-yee!
Ee-ee-ee-ee-ee!
O.K.! You said loki
was a night God.
Maybe it only works at night.
Mr. Ipkiss, I feel
I should warn you
that I don't work with
really sick people.
There are private institutions
for things like that.
However, if you like,
I can arrange for a
safe environment tonight.
No.
I've got to see Tina.
But what do I do?
I mean,
do I go as myself...
Or the mask?
If I tell you,
you promise to leave
my office right now?
Uh-huh.
All right.
Mr. Ipkiss...
Go as yourself and as the mask...
Because they are both one
and the same beautiful person.
[Police radio] Got the cross-check
on the fingerprints for you.
It's Ipkiss, all right.
I'm looking at him.
Just keep the s.W.A.T.
Team standing by.
If he's half as bad as advertised,
we'll have a full dance card.
You have the pickle relish?
Doyle, get in.
But I ordered onion rings.
Doyle!
[Sigh]
No.
Stanley.
What are you doing here?
Tina, hi.
Uh...I--I just
wanted to come by
and make sure that you
two got together all right.
That's nice.
You know, I hardly
ever stop by here.
Kind of hard to believe
it was just a garbage heap.
Yeah, it's, uh...
It's, uh, it's...
Really beautiful
right around sunset.
The methane emissions really
pick up the colors.
All those...
Pinks and Greens.
Uhh...
My friend'll be along
any minute. I better go.
Stanley, wait.
Stanley?
Stanley!
[Whoomp sssss]
[Gasp]
Hello, chèrie.
We meet again.
Is it fate?
Is it meant to be?
Is it written in the stars
that we are destined to fraternize?
I'd like to think so!
Ha ha ha!
Kiss me, my dear,
and I will reveal my croissant.
I will spread your paté.
I will dip my ladle
in your vichyssoise!
Aw!
[Very high voice] She is so coy.
[Deep voice] I love it!
Eh-eh-eh-eh.
Our love
is like a red, red rose,
and I am a little thorny.
Je t'adore.
Shut the window, I don't care!
Ah ha ha ha ha!
This is Kellaway.
I need backup. Now.
Cigarette?
No?
Now,
like Napoleon...
I will divide and conquer.
[Guns cock]
Ipkiss, police!
Merde!
Freeze!
Put your hands up.
[Muffled] But you
told me to freeze.
All right, all right. Unfreeze.
You're under arrest.
No! It wasn't me.
It was the one-armed man.
All right, I confess.
I did it, you hear? And
I'm glad, glad, I tell ya!
What are they gonna
do to me, sarge?
What are they gonna do?
Sorry, son. That's
not my department.
Search him.
Ow!
Where's a camcorder
when you need one?
[Snort snort]
Looks like it's
gonna be a long night.
My wife's gonna kill me.
What is it, Murray?
Cops got your pal
Ipkiss at landfill park.
I'll cover it. I need this story.
You can go home to Claire.
I don't know,
Peggy. Ramsey said--
I'll take care of Ramsey.
Thanks a million. I owe you one.
Really big sunglasses.
[A-ooga squeak]
Bike horn.
Small-mouth bass.
Wow! Rolling pin.
[Snap]
Ah-ah-ah!
Gaaa!
Mousetrap.
Rubber chicken.
Little to the left.
That's it. Ohh.
Funny eyeball glasses.
I've never seen those
before in my life.
Bazooka.
I have a permit for that.
Picture of Kellaway's wife.
What?
Uh-oh.
Margaret!
You son of a bitch!
Jeez, I figured you
had a sense of humor.
After all...
You married her!
Aah!
That's got to
hurt. Eh-eh-eh.
Get him!
Doyle!
Aah!
It's all over, Ipkiss!
Put your hands over your head,
or we'll open fire.
Ehhhh.
Hit it.
[Rumba plays]
♪ They call me Cuba Pete ♪
♪ I'm the king
of a rumba beat ♪
♪ when I play the maracas ♪
♪ I go chic-chicky-boom,
chic-chicky-boom ♪
♪ yes, sir, I'm Cuban Pete ♪
♪ I'm the crazy
man in the street ♪
♪ when I start to
dance, everything goes ♪
♪ chic-chicky-boom,
chic-chicky-boom ♪
♪ the señoritas, they
singin' and they swing ♪
♪ with their rumberos ♪
♪ it's very nice
♪ so full of spice
♪ and when they dancin'
they bring a happy ring ♪
♪ to their vaqueros ♪
♪ singin' that song
♪ all the day long
hoo!
♪ Ooh, if you like the beat ♪
♪ take a lesson
from Cuban Pete ♪
♪ and dance to
♪ chic-chicky-boom,
chic-chicky-boom ♪
♪ chic-chicky-boom
♪ he's a really modest guy ♪
♪ although he's
the hottest guy ♪
♪ in Havana
♪ sí, señorita, I know ♪
♪ that you will like
a chicky-boom-chic ♪
♪ it's very nice
♪ so full of spice
♪ when I place my
hand on your hip ♪
♪ and if you will just
give me your hand ♪
♪ then we shall try
♪ just you and I
ai-yi-yi-yi!
Olé!
He's not bad.
Shut up and help me down.
♪ And I'll teach you to
♪ chic-chicky-boom,
chic-chicky-boom ♪
♪ chic-chicky-boom
brrrr!
[Rhythm changes to conga]
Hey! Brrrr! Aha!
Ai-yi-yi!
Hey!
[Scatting]
You start dancing,
I'll blow your brains out.
Give me that thing.
Diddy-daddy-wow!
See ya.
There he is! Let's get him!
Snap out of it!
This dance is over!
Eh-eh-eh.
Aah!
[Kiss]
Ahh!
He's down the alley! Follow me!
Come on! Grab your gun!
Aaaaahhh!
[Panting]
Stanley!
[Honk honk]
Stanley, get in!
[Gasp]
There he is!
Halt!
Or I'll shoot!
[Gunfire]
Shoot! Shoot!
Seat belts.
I missed him.
Come on!
We all missed him.
I saw it.
I saw everything.
What's happening to you, Stanley?
It's crazy.
[Sigh]
I'm losing control.
When I put that mask on,
I can do anything,
be anything.
That's wrecking my mind.
My life is wrecked.
Wrecked.
Wrecked!
Look, I don't know what's
happening to you, Stanley,
but I do know this.
That letter that
you sent my column?
That was from a guy
with more guts...
And more heart...
Than any of the creeps
that I've met in this city.
Whatever that mask is,
you don't need it.
You...
Stanley Ipkiss...
Are already all
you'll ever need to be.
Gosh, peg.
Do you really mean that?
Actually...
No.
What?
What took you so long?
I've been vamping
for 20 minutes.
Is this him?
You got the 50 thou?
Give her the money.
Right.
When he puts on the mask,
he turns into that
green thingamajig.
Peggy.
What are you doing?
Sorry, Stanley. You
really are a great guy.
I just can't lose my condo.
You know how hard it
is to find an apartment.
You said you wouldn't
hurt him.
I lied.
Stanley!
Hey. Hey!
Hey!
Ohh! Uhh! Uhh!
Uhh! Whaa!
Tell me,
how does this mask work?
I don't know.
You just...
Put it on.
Boss...
You better be careful, huh?
Aah!
[Shuddering sigh]
[Deep bass voice] What a rush!
Whoa, boss.
You o.K.?
Better than ever, you idiots.
What do we do with Ipkiss?
The police are
looking for the mask.
So we'll give them the mask.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Aah! Uh!
The money better be here, Ipkiss,
or you can Ipkiss your ass goodbye.
[Arf]
Hey, Orlando.
[Grrrr]
[Whimpering]
[Grrr]
[Muffled cry]
[Engine starts]
Go!
[Tires screech]
I still can't believe it.
Hardened cops dancing in the street
and broadcast all
over the 11:00 news.
S.W.A.T. Team got
an offer for Vegas.
I'm history. The captain will
have my badge for breakfast,
with a little pension on top.
Come on, lieutenant.
It's not all your fault.
Something will turn up.
Sure. Stanley Ipkiss will
fall right into my lap.
[Brakes squeal]
Hey!
Uhh!
[Grunting and groaning]
Get him off of me!
Aah!
Ipkiss!
Wait!
I can explain everything.
Oh, yeah. You can
explain everything?
Explain this.
Umm...
Get him up. Let's go.
We got a cell for you, pal.
[Cellblock door slams]
[Arf]
[Arf arf]
Milo.
[Arf]
[Whimpering]
You better forget about me, buddy.
Find yourself a new place to live.
Looks like I'm going to be
in here for a long, long time.
[Whimpering]
Hey, you with the face.
You got a visitor.
Tina.
Hello, Stanley.
What are you doing here?
Is it true?
You're the mask.
Yeah, but don't tell anybody.
If I get a good lawyer
and strike up a deal,
I can be out of here
in about 10,000 years.
You're taking a chance
coming here.
Your boyfriend might
be a little upset.
He's going to the
charity ball tonight.
He's going to do
something terrible.
Like
what--
the lambada?
Stanley, this is serious.
There's got to be
a way to stop him.
How does it work?
I don't know.
It-it's like, uh...
It's like it brings your
innermost desires to life.
If deep down inside, you're...
A little repressed and
a hopeless romantic,
you become some sort of
a love-crazy wild man.
And if you're somebody
like Dorian?
Then we're all in big trouble.
And if I were you, I'd
get out of town fast.
Thanks.
For what?
Lots of things.
For sharing a sunset with me,
for being the only guy
who treated me like a person
and not some sort of party favor.
For being any kind of romantic,
even a hopeless one.
You're welcome.
You know that night at the club?
I knew I'd found someone special.
The mask.
No.
It was the guy inside the mask,
who was you all along.
You...
Stanley...
Ip...
Kiss.
O.K., lady, time's up!
Could I have just one more minute?
I've got to disappear
for a while now, Stanley.
I don't know where I'm going,
but I'll let you
know as soon as I can.
Aah!
Somebody help me!
Oh. Oh, no.
No.
Guard!
There's a woman being
chased through the alleyway!
Come on! She needs help.
Yeah, yeah, sure. Keep it down.
Come on!
Serve and protect, man!
Milo.
Milo, good boy. Come on.
Jump up. Can you jump up?
[Whimpering]
Remember how I taught you
not to jump up on people?
Forget that. Come on.
Get up here.
That's it.
You can do it.
Come on!
Come on.
Milo.
Put some effort into it!
Baby, there you are.
I was beginning to
get worried about you.
Nice talk with the cops?
I just went to see
what Ipkiss told them.
That's right, you and Stanley.
You two are getting awfully close.
Maybe you helped him
out with the bank job.
That's ridiculous.
Oh, is it?
Look what I found in her car.
You planning a little
trip without me, baby?
No.
No?
Boys, I want you...
To pick her out
something pretty to wear.
We're going to a party tonight,
and we're going to have one
hell of a time, aren't we?
Yeah.
Yes.
Get out of my sight.
Jump up.
Get up. Come on.
[Arr]
Come on, Milo.
Jump, please.
Do it for daddy.
[Arf]
That's it.
Oh!
I can't believe you did that.
Oh, good boy.
Good boy.
Good boy. O.K...
See that man over there?
He's got keys.
Yeah.
Go get those keys.
Go get 'em.
Get the keys. Go get 'em.
That's it.
Yeah.
O.K., get the keys.
Oh!
No, not...
Not the cheese, the keys.
Put the cheese down.
And get the keys.
Go on.
Over there. Over there.
[Snoring]
Shh.
Yeah!
Oh.
Come on.
Come here.
Good boy.
That's a good boy.
No. Give it. Give it.
Give me the keys.
[Grr]
Come on. Come on.
Drop it.
It's sundown.
It's almost time.
Oh...
I wouldn't do that, darling.
Wouldn't want to start the
celebration early, would you?
[Snoring]
Oh!
[Arf]
Milo.
Aah! Aah!
Hold it!
I'm warning you, I'm...
Seriously stressed out here.
Easy, Ipkiss.
Come on.
Don't be an idiot.
You're in the middle
of a police station.
There's no way you're
walking out of here like this.
You know, you're right.
You're absolutely right.
What the hell are you doing?
You're going to take
me out as your prisoner.
Put it on.
Put it on!
Ow.
Come on.
I'm really very sorry about this.
Milo.
Got the wrong guy, I tell you.
It's a bum rap. I got my rights.
Hey, lieutenant. Where
you taking Ipkiss?
Ixnay. He's otgay an ungay. Ow!
Oh, I get it. Pig Latin, right?
Eesay ouyay aterlay.
Come on!
Why don't you just sit
back and relax, o.K.?
I've got to change for the party.
[Music plays]
Need a pack of cigarettes.
Which brand?
Doesn't matter. I don't smoke,
but for you, I would
shoot the surgeon general.
May we have a word with you?
I always have time
for the press and my
loyal constituents.
Aah! Aah!
[Horn honks]
Let me out of these cuffs.
You're driving like a maniac.
We're already late for the ball.
Alice and the white rabbit
will be really disappointed.
Now you're being cynical.
Who the hell are you?
I'm just an ex-employee
who's come for his back pay...
Or should I say payback?
Dorian?
Uhh!
Kill him.
Come on.
Aah!
Ha ha ha.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I will be your host
for the remainder of
the evening.
[Whimpers]
Get your dog away from me.
[Spits]
I'm sorry. He seems
to be attracted to you.
Where is everybody?
Something's not kosher here.
Exactly!
Watch it!
Sorry. I'm going to
have to lock you in.
Use the radio.
What?
You know, call for
backup or something.
Milo...
This could be dangerous.
You stay here and be
a good boy.
Daddy's going to have
to go kick some ass.
[Grr]
[Whimpers]
He's a dead man.
Down! Get down!
Move it!
Line them over here!
Easy. I got the point.
[Whistles]
[Whap]
Aah! Aah!
Blow it.
Bastard!
Aah!
What's the matter,
darling?
This is your big
production number,
and you know it's important
to go out with a big bang.
Charlie.
What are you doing here?
Look, take this gun.
Start sneaking people
out the back.
Step back.
Don't you know who
you're talking to?
A dead man if you
don't step back.
[Woman] Don't you have
respect for law and order?
It's all set, Dorian.
Excellent.
This party's over...
In 10 minutes.
This is the moment of truth,
when a man shows what
he's really made of.
Crap.
Drop it, Ipkiss.
Uhh.
Smart dog.
Hey, boss, look who
decided to crash the party.
Hi, Dorian.
How's it going?
Bring him up here!
Dorian! Dorian,
wait! No!
There's no time for last requests.
But all I wanted was a kiss.
A kiss?
Just one last kiss.
I can't shut this off.
There's always time...
For one last kiss.
Oh!
From the real Dorian,
the one I used to love.
Nobody ever kissed me
like Dorian tyrrell.
This place is going to
blow in a couple of minutes!
Just wait!
I have decided...
To give her one last thrill.
[Ticking]
Get it!
Aah!
[Crash]
Run, Milo!
I got
him--oh!
Stanley, hurry!
Don't worry, Tina.
It's all over now.
Stanley!
Gotcha.
Aah!
I'm going to take you apart.
I hope you can enjoy the
victory with one friggin' eye!
Aah!
No!
God!
[Grr]
Good doggy.
Shh. Good doggy.
I'm winning.
Stanley!
Ha ha ha ha.
[Tina] Stanley!
Uhh!
Yes!
Aah!
Milo!
Oh, my God.
This is going to be a new breed.
Easy, boy.
Good boy.
[Arf]
Did you miss me?
I guess not!
Now, you have to ask
yourself one question,
"do I feel lucky?"
Well...
Do ya...
punks?
Eh-eh-eh!
Stanley!
Ahh.
[Boom]
[Belches]
[Italian accent]
That's a spicy meatball.
How do?
[Arf]
This guy's incorrigible.
Aah!
You were good, kid, real good,
but as long as I'm around,
you'll always be second
best, see?
Police! Hands up!
Officers, arrest those men.
I always wanted to say that.
Come on.
Give me that gun.
They stole all my jewelry.
Take me down to headquarters.
Stop that man!
Ipkiss!
I've got you now, Ipkiss.
Watch it, chunky.
Mayor
Tilton--
what the hell's wrong with you?
That man is the mask.
No, Dorian tyrrell was the mask.
This young man here
just saved our lives.
With a little help
from his friends.
You're a real hero.
Doyle!
Well, it's nothing...
Any American with balls of steel
wouldn't do for his community.
Milo, come on!
Hey, wait.
That dog.
You see that--
leave the dog alone.
I want to see you in my office
first thing tomorrow morning.
Yes, your honor.
That doesn't sound good at all.
No, it doesn't sound good.
What would sound good to you?
Breakfast.
Shut up!
[Music plays]
You sure you know what
you're doing, buddy?
I'm sure.
Then do what you got to do.
Sure you're not going
to miss this guy?
When he's gone, all
that's left is me.
Milo!
Smokin'!
♪ Know
♪ don't you wanna know?
♪ Don't you wanna know?
♪ I know you wanna know
♪ who's that man?
♪ Know
♪ a-don't you wanna know?
♪ Don't you wanna know?
♪ Who's that man?
♪ He's got a different little style
♪ than all the men today
♪ he does his
thing with a swing ♪
♪ and everything you see him do
♪ is done a different way ♪
♪ you never ever
seen him before ♪
♪ he's not your ordinary
slick uptown-type lover ♪
♪ don't think twice, 'cause
you'll never find another ♪
♪ because the man
behind the mask ♪
♪ you never ever
seen him before ♪
♪ never never seen him before ♪
♪ know
♪ who's that man?
♪ Don't you wanna know?
♪ I know you wanna know, yeah ♪
♪ who's that man?
♪ Know
♪ don't you wanna know?
Don't you wanna know? ♪
♪ know
♪ who's that man?
♪ He's got the flavor
♪ to do his thing
♪ he's got something
everybody wish they had ♪
♪ and something tells me you
don't want to make him mad ♪
♪ no, you don't, no, you
don't, no, you don't ♪
♪ he's not your ordinary
slick uptown-type lover ♪
♪ don't think twice, 'cause
you'll never find another ♪
♪ because the man
behind the mask ♪
♪ you never ever
seen him before ♪
♪ you never never
♪ know
♪ don't you wanna know?
♪ I know you want to know ♪
♪ know
♪ who's that man?
♪ Know
♪ don't you wanna know?
Don't you wanna know? ♪
♪ don't you wanna know? ♪
♪ know
♪ who's that man?
♪ Who's that man?
♪ Skip-bip-bip-
doo-doo ♪
♪
skip-doo-doo
♪ who's that man?
♪ Know
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ who's that man?
♪ Skip-doo,
dip-doo ♪
♪ somebody was
spreadin' rumors ♪
♪ about better days a-comin' ♪
♪ fly was a-hummin'
♪ as if I knew
♪ one in the same
♪ but I just
whispered your name ♪
♪ somebody was
saying somethin' ♪
♪ about there being
an end to tyranny ♪
♪ but when they asked me
♪ what would I do
♪ if that day came
♪ I only whispered your name ♪
♪ every wimp got
their own opinion ♪
♪ and protects
their own dominion ♪
♪ no doubt, for
them, it's true ♪
♪ but I tell them
what I really believe ♪
♪ my only worry is
protecting you, yeah ♪
♪ I just whisper
♪ your name
♪ anybody in the town
want to bounce around? ♪
♪ bounce around
♪ just come with me,
and we'll do it, do it ♪
♪ we'll do it
♪ if you really want to
do it up caddie style ♪
♪ bounce around
♪ just come with me,
and we'll do it, do it ♪
♪ we'll do it
♪ I know a club
♪ in the town
♪ that's going on
Thursday night at 10:00 ♪
♪ but 12:00
♪ is not too late
♪ I own the place, so
bring your friends ♪
♪ the night for you
will never change ♪
♪ we'll do it till
the break of dawn ♪
♪ you bounce around
♪ in the town
♪ anywhere
♪ I just want to love you ♪
♪ anybody in the town
want to bounce around? ♪
♪ bounce around
♪ just come with
me, and we'll do it ♪
♪ and we'll do it
♪ if you really want to
do it up caddie style ♪
♪ bounce around
♪ just come with
me, and we'll do it ♪
♪ and we'll do it together ♪
♪ anybody in the town
want to bounce around? ♪
♪ bounce around
♪ just come with
me, and we'll do it ♪
♪ and we'll do it together ♪
♪ if you really want to
do it up caddie style ♪
♪ bounce around
♪ just come with
me, and we'll do it ♪
♪ and we'll do it
together, yeah ♪
♪ oh, yeah
♪ all right
♪ send me searching for you ♪
♪ oh, yeah
♪ all right
♪ California style
♪ anybody in the town
want to bounce around? ♪
♪ bounce around
♪ just come with
me, and we'll do it ♪
♪ ohh-ohh
♪ if you really want to
do it up caddie style ♪
♪ bounce around
♪ just come with
me, and we'll do it ♪
♪ let's do it, do it
♪ anybody in the town
want to bounce around? ♪
♪ bounce around
♪♪ ya-ha-ha-ha-ha ♪