Check. Head count.
Head count. Two. Three.
Four. Five.
Six.
Demo set.
Let's move.
Clear.
Low Boy, this is Black Cat.
ETA Romeo, L-Z-one-niner.
We are hot. Copy.
Come on. Get out there!
Go, go!
Come on.
Get in!
Cover! I'm on the roof!
Go!
This is Low Boy.
Package is wrapped.
Ladies and gentlemen...
three weeks ago,
Russian and American special forces...
apprehended the self-proclaimed leader
of Kazakhstan...
General Ivan Radek.
The forces of Radek were directed
toward the suppression of democracy.
His nuclear arsenal
could have brought the world...
into a new cold war.
But thanks to the support of one
of the world's greatest leaders...
Radek is now in prison.
Today we are honoring this brave man.
Ladies and gentlemen,
my friend...
the president of the
United States of America.
The dead remember our indifference.
The dead remember our silence.
I came here tonight
to be congratulated.
But today when I visited
the Red Cross camps...
overwhelmed by the flood of refugees...
fleeing from the horror
of Kazakhstan...
I realized I don't deserve
to be congratulated, none of us do.
- What's he doing?
- That's not the speech.
The truth is...
we acted too late.
Only when our own national security
was threatened did we act.
Radek's regime murdered over 200,000
men, women and children...
and we watched it on TV.
We let it happen.
People were being slaughtered...
for over a year.
We issued economic sanctions and hid
behind the rhetoric of diplomacy.
How dare we?
The dead remember.
Real peace...
is not just the absence of conflict,
it's the presence of justice.
Tonight I come to you with a pledge
to change America's policy.
Never again...
will I allow
our political self-interest...
to deter us from doing what we know
to be morally right.
Atrocity and terror
are not political weapons.
And to those who would use them...
your day is over.
We will never negotiate.
We will no longer tolerate
and we will no longer be afraid.
It's your turn to be afraid.
The Russian was a nice touch.
Tell my mother.
She wanted me to study French.
- Do you know what you committed us to?
- I know exactly what I committed us to.
Gentlemen,
welcome to "Air Force One. "
Please present your equipment
for inspection.
We were just inspected at the gate.
This plane carries the president
of the United States.
I understand. I'm terribly sorry.
Please place your thumb
on the I.D. pad.
Access cleared.
Hello. I'm Melanie Mitchell,
deputy press secretary.
- I'll be taking you in from here.
- Oh, Miss Mitchell.
It is so nice to finally meet you
in person.
The president and I were delighted
we could accommodate your news crew.
So, if you boys are all cleared?
The president's on a very tight schedule
so this is how it works.
During the flight,
two members of your crew...
will be allowed outside the press area
for filming.
You'll get exactly 10 minutes
with the president, 20 with the crew.
Gary, the president is ready
to take Congress on.
He's not gonna kiss their ass
for each vote.
Let them vote us down
and stand on their record.
Yeah, I'm with him now.
I'll call you from the plane.
- What did they say about the speech?
- Your speech is leading the news.
They're calling it
the "Be Afraid" speech.
Good.
With all due respect,
next time you want to make...
a major policy departure,
you might want to discuss it...
with your national security advisor
first.
- We did discuss it, Jack.
- We discussed it...
in private, which is where I thought
it would remain.
Now it's public.
Now it's policy.
Get behind it.
The allies are going to be very upset
they weren't consulted about this.
It might come back and bite us
in the ass in November.
It's the right thing to do.
You know it.
There goes the neighborhood.
If you'd like,
we have time for a quick tour.
- We'd be delighted.
- Good.
Andrei, Boris.
Follow me.
Ahead of this staff cabin
is Secret Service. Right here.
Never try to go past them without
an escort or you'll be very sorry.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Thanks for the warning.
Here we have
our in-flight offices.
A lot of the plane's features
are classified.
But I can tell you
it's bullet-resistant...
and it's even protected against
the pulse of a nuclear blast.
I'm not sure that's very comforting.
Upstairs is the cockpit along with the
most advanced communications center...
on or above the face of the earth.
We could run the whole country
from here.
Or even a war if we had to.
Just last week, the president called
the shuttle astronauts from there.
The president's arriving.
They should take their seats.
Right away.
I'll get out of here and let you all
get some sleep.
- Mr. President, welcome aboard.
- Hey, Danny. How are you?
Mr. President!
Change in plan, Danny.
Let's go to Barbados.
Anything you want.
You're the president.
Boy, I wish.
- Mr. President.
- Mr. Gibbs, where's my bunch?
Ballet ran late.
They'll be here in five minutes.
- Lewis, you tape the game?
- It was a real squeaker, sir.
Don't brief me on it.
I wanted to watch it, for Christ's sake.
We'll be underway
in about 30 minutes, sir.
Mr. President.
Could you put the game on now?
Yeah, Jack?
The Iraqis have mobilized
two armored brigades toward...
Just got it. Give me 15 minutes.
Get the guys together.
"Repel them.
Make them relinquish the ball. "
- Did you hear about Notre Dame?
- Don't. Don't tell me the score.
- Great game.
- Mr. President.
We need to strategize,
smooth some things out politically.
- What was that?
- It's not so important.
- Damage control. What if...
- Give me a minute alone.
What if a "high-ranking
White House official"...
Just give me a few moments alone.
A "high-ranking official" were
to qualify what you said last night?
Drop it. Do yourself a favor.
It's policy.
Drop it.
- Or find another ride home. Yeah?
- The Russian news crew's with us.
I told them you'd give them a sound bite
about life in the White House.
There is no life in the White House.
You said it.
The president needs some time alone.
14-13 Michigan!
All right, Mr. President!
That wasn't you napping
during the performance, was it, Tom?
No, ma'am. It was very enjoyable.
Alice, you can finish it on the plane.
Let's not keep your father waiting.
Try and smile, sweetheart. Okay?
- Alice, one picture, please!
- Thank you very much.
Great, something from Tom.
Shh. Daddy's asleep.
How was the ballet?
It was great!
You trying to kill me?
Wait it really good? Did you enjoy it?
Did you love it? Men in tights?
Did you hear my speech?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- You're gonna get yourself reelected.
- That's what I keep telling them.
This is the aircraft commander.
We'll take to the runway in a moment.
- Are you guys comfortable?
- Yes, very.
- I brought you V.I.P. press kits.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
Pass interference.
That's cheating.
- Only if they get caught.
- Dad!
The way of the world, kiddo.
Why didn't you take me with you
when you went to the refugee camp today?
For one thing,
it's not 100 percent secure.
You've got your whole life to live.
You don't need to see that stuff.
Come on, Dad. It's not like
I don't see it on the news.
It's different on the news.
All I'm saying is I'm ready for things
you don't think I'm ready for.
Maybe I'm not ready.
I'm 12 years old, Dad!
In the caveman days...
I'd be having children of my own.
That's what we call progress. You're
missing the best part of the game.
God!
We're so looking forward to seeing you.
- She is so anxious to grow up.
- I know. She's...
Yes, the both of us.
Okay. Bye, bye.
Well, she couldn't stay
your little girl forever, Jim.
I was hoping it would last
till she was 14 or 15.
Or 50.
They hated your speech, didn't they?
They're afraid we won't have the guts
to back it up.
And, then, if we do,
it'll be political suicide.
Remember our first campaign?
- In the House?
- Yeah.
- Downstate, driving around with...
- Who was that kid, our volunteer?
- Henry.
- Henry with the convertible.
- With the broken top.
- And the snow coming in.
We were the only three people
who thought you could win that.
You didn't give a damn. You knew
what needed to be done and you did it.
And you spoke from your heart.
That's what I heard tonight.
Well, it felt good.
I'll bet it did.
Sorry to interrupt.
Everybody's assembled, sir.
United States "Air Force One. "
It is an honor to clear you
for immediate takeoff on runway 2-5.
"Air Force One" cleared for takeoff.
Thank you for your hospitality, Moscow.
In Moscow tonight,
President Marshall defended...
the military action
against the Radek regime...
an act the administration had
been calling a one-time intervention.
But in a rare display of emotion...
the president alluded to a change
in U.S. foreign policy when he stated...
that America will no longer tolerate
any terrorist government.
Meanwhile in Kazakhstan, Radek's ouster
stalled the neo-communist revolution.
These are two of Saddam Hussein's
Republican Guard brigades...
that have been moved north.
He knows we're watching,
knows we'll retaliate.
Why the hell is he sending tanks
to the border?
Could be a response to your speech,
Mr. President.
- Maybe he's got a son-in-law up there.
- Very funny.
I think there's one or two
he hasn't shot yet.
What does State have to say?
The Iraqi ambassador is claiming
it's just an exercise.
Let's not waste more time.
Send the "Nimitz" back in.
- Gibbs.
- Guys.
- Sleeping on the job?
- No, sir.
Hey, guys...
these are the advance team reports
from the Miami field agent.
- Take a look at them.
- Thank you.
Smoke.
There's smoke!
Steward, there's smoke in the cabin.
Everybody move to the back of the plane.
Now! Please!
Smoke! Notify the cockpit!
Mr. President, stay back.
Everybody down!
Code red! We have a code red!
I repeat. Shots fired on board.
Code red acknowledged.
Lock that door now.
Flight control, this is "Air Force One"
declaring emergency.
Cover us!
Stay back.
Move up!
I'll cover you.
Go! Go!
- What's going on?
- Shots fired, sir.
- What about my family?
- We're handling it, sir.
Boy Scout coming out!
Cover!
- Give us cover!
- Daddy?
Alice, get back!
Alice, get down!
- Take him around here.
- Get down.
This is "Air Force One. "
We are code red.
Shots fired on board.
Request emergency assistance.
ETA 15 minutes.
Acknowledged. We are scrambling
our fighters. Emergency equipment...
will be standing by.
Get him to the escape pod!
Boy Scout is headed to the vault.
The football!
Get him around here.
Get him down to the pod!
Don't move!
Get the president!
- They're on us.
- Where's my family?
- Get in the pod, sir. Get in!
- What about my family?
"Air Force One," landing runway 0-9.
I repeat, runway 0-9.
Roger. Turning to heading 1-8-5.
Descending to 5,000 feet.
Hurry, he's in the escape pod.
Ramstein, this is "Air Force One. "
Emergency pod has been deployed.
I repeat.
- The emergency pod has been deployed.
- Ramstein tower, acknowledge.
We are picking up the homing beacon
and deploying search and rescue.
- Is the locking ready to look at?
- Just about, sir.
- Has General Northwood arrived?
- Yes, he has.
- Give me an update.
- Madam Vice President, this way.
- We'll avoid the press.
- Is the president secure?
Not yet. The recovery team
will have him very soon.
"Air Force One"...
this is Halo Flight Lead,:
you are under escort.
All airspace has been cleared.
Alert force has been mobilized.
- Is everyone here?
- We're working on it.
How did this happen?
How did they get "Air Force One"?
Gentlemen. Mr. Secretary.
Ramstein tower, we are at ten mile...
Final coming in red hot.
Roger, "Air Force One. " Wind is
0- niner-0 at 1-2. You are clear to land.
They're landing.
Get down! Now!
Open the door!
Open!
No matter what happens, we land
this aircraft. Is that understood?
Come on. Flaps 30.
Flaps 30.
If we land, we're finished.
- No!
- Get the fuck in the air!
Now!
Take this plane up!
Up! Up!
- Get us back in the air now!
- Artie!
Take it up!
Get this plane back in the air now
or you die.
Get up now!
No! Jesus!
Contact those F-15s.
I want them to keep "Air Force One"
in visual contact.
- What are our airborne scenarios?
- There are no airborne scenarios.
Then we'd better start generating them.
They better be good and better work.
How long can they stay up there
with the fuel they have?
- That's a question of airspeed, wind.
- Altitude.
We need an "Air Force One" pilot. Any
educated guesses where they might go?
- Iraq, Libya, Algeria.
- Those are guesses, but not educated.
Notify our allies.
We'll need secure airspace.
- Can we keep that under wraps?
- We'll do our best.
Try and relax, Kathryn.
I'm in charge here.
I don't know.
It seems to me they're in charge.
We're heading home.
Let's get him.
- Don't hurt me.
- Go.
Go.
The president.
The president is no longer on board.
He made it to the pod and escaped.
Moscow police found six members
of a Russian TV news crew murdered.
The same crew that was cleared
to fly on "Air Force One. "
Tell me it's not that easy.
No. You would have to generate
fake I.D., photos.
- Fingerprints.
- Could be with help from Moscow.
How would they get weapons on board?
There's no way to get weapons on board
"Air Force One. " It's impossible.
There are enough weapons on board to
take Panama, but who has access to them?
You think someone on the plane
helped them?
What if somebody did
and they're still on the plane?
Who do they trust up there?
Who do we trust?
Madam Vice President,
Mr. Secretary.
All compromised nuclear launch codes
have been cancelled.
New codes are active.
Ramstein, the president's escape pod
has been located.
We're honing in at 2-8-5 degrees.
There it is.
Ramstein, we have a strong signal.
ETA, two minutes.
Where is the wife and daughter?
Where is my husband?
He had fled.
The coward chose to save himself.
But one can always
strike a bargain.
You listen to me.
I don't know who you are
or what you want...
but you will never get it.
He will not negotiate.
Really?
His wife. His daughter.
A man could not live with himself.
And it would be such bad politics.
I think he'll negotiate.
The escape pod is visually acquired.
Location of Ramstein is 2-8-4 degrees.
Twelve miles out.
All the weapons have been collected.
Nevsky, check the plane again.
You have the first watch.
I'll check downstairs.
Ready.
It's "Air Force One. "
They want to talk to the vice president.
Hello. Can you hear me?
This is the vice president
of the United States.
To whom am I speaking?
This is the person who controls
"Air Force One. "
The world's most secure aircraft.
What is it that you want?
We'll get to that.
- I want to speak to the First Lady.
- No.
- No. Why?
- I need to know they're safe.
The president is safe.
But then you must know that.
He ran from here like a whipped dog.
I'm sure you can't wait for him
to get back to making the decisions...
so you can stop sweating
through that silk blouse of yours.
What is the condition
of the people on board?
Some are dead.
What are your intentions?
What arrogance to think
you could ever understand my intentions.
I want to understand
what it is that you want.
What do I want?
When Mother Russia becomes
one great nation again...
when the capitalists are dragged
from the Kremlin...
and shot in the street...
when our enemies run and hide in fear
at the mention of our name...
and America begs our forgiveness...
on that great day of deliverance...
you will know what I want.
We can give you a forum
for your grievances.
We can contact the Russian government.
But you must understand
that it will take some time.
Really?
When you talk to the president...
you might remind him that I am holding
his wife, his daughter...
his chief of staff,
his national security advisor...
his classified papers
and his baseball glove.
If he wants them back, he will prevail
upon the puppet regime in Moscow...
to release General Radek.
Fifty for one.
It's a good deal.
How's your blouse?
What assurances do I have
that you'll keep your word?
I'll wait for confirmation that
General Radek has been released.
Until then...
I will execute a hostage
every half an hour.
You have my word.
You must understand that we...
Hello?
They're off!
Damn it!
Nobody does this...
to the United States.
The president will get back his glove
and play catch with this guy's balls.
We can't do anything in half an hour.
We need more time.
He's a zealot. Tough to negotiate with.
All you can do is wear them down.
Mr. Secretary!
We found the escape pod.
It's empty.
So where's the president?
I think we have to acknowledge
the possibility...
that the president
may be dead.
Why wouldn't they tell us?
Diversion.
Try to buy some time.
It could have happened in a cross fire,
and they're afraid we'll retaliate.
Damn right, we'll retaliate.
We'll release Radek into the atmosphere.
It doesn't add up. That terrorist knew
we'd recover the pod in short order.
He expected that we'd be talking
to Marshall.
Let's not bury him yet.
He could still be alive in that plane.
Let's not forget this president
is a Medal of Honor winner.
In Vietnam, he flew more helicopter
missions than any man in my command.
He knows how to fight.
Then he's taking a terrible chance
with his life.
The element of surprise
is a formidable advantage in combat.
If he's up there,
he's the best chance that we have.
That pod was designed
for a reason, General.
He has no right to take chances
with his life.
Everything is all right.
What does the psych profile say?
How far will he go?
He's a Radek loyalist. That tells us
all we need to know, doesn't it?
He'll see this thing through
to the last hostage or his own death.
Release this bastard
and Central Asia will go up in flames!
I'm aware of that.
Bring back the old Soviet empire
under a flag of genocide?
Radek with a nuclear arsenal?
I hate to say this,
but 50 people...
is a small price to pay
to stop that from happening.
Even if one of them is the president?
The presidency is bigger than any man.
Didn't they teach you that at Yale?
Can't we release him today
and pick up the pieces tomorrow?
We caught him before,
we'll catch him again.
If Petrov releases Radek,
his government will fall.
I promise you that.
Then who's gonna stand up to Radek?
You go to catch him again,
you'll find him in Moscow.
With respect, Mr. Secretary, we don't
need more dramatics, we need options.
- It's not an option.
- We need a decision.
It's not her decision.
This is a military situation.
I'm the secretary of defense.
Check your regs. In the absence
of the president, the buck stops here.
Get the attorney general
with a copy of the Constitution.
We have... Oh, my God!
Nineteen minutes.
I'm going to consult
with President Petrov.
Madam Vice President, I'm sorry.
I cannot release him.
We would train...
all our military might
against this one target.
- He wouldn't stay at large for long.
- Maybe so.
But millions of lives
are hanging in the balance.
I am trying to save a nation!
As am I.
No nation can survive the loss,
nor soon replace, a great leader.
Let us be pragmatic.
Fifty lives means nothing...
in the grand scheme.
Let me be equally pragmatic.
Our president took a great risk
to come to your aid...
against strong opposition
in both parties and among our allies.
It would be politically impossible
to do so again.
If it meant saving his life,
I would gladly do it.
But I would have to know for sure.
And you cannot tell me he's alive,
can you?
No, Mr. President, I cannot.
Then there is nothing I can do.
I am truly sorry. Good-bye.
Okay, Walter,
you and your generals get to work.
He was in Afghanistan with me
for five years.
Find out who killed him
or you lie down next to him.
Okay, they can't keep the plane
in the air indefinitely.
There are only four possible
landing sites in Kazakhstan...
that are still controlled
by Radek's forces.
We have to go in and take all of them.
Can we do it?
I'd rather take my chances in the air.
I just looked at the airborne scenarios.
They're no good.
- Can we do this?
- In the time we have? Messy.
Three more minutes
before they execute the first hostage.
You'll have to buy us more time.
All right.
It's time.
Transfer the phone
to the conference room.
You both, come here.
Now!
They will transfer the call here.
So...
let's just wait.
Excuse me.
Sir, if you will permit me,
I am the national security advisor.
I'm the man the president
would be listening to.
I believe you are negotiating right now
with the vice president.
In our system, the vice president
is like the queen of England.
She can't even get airline tickets
without talking...
to somebody like me; therefore,
let me speak to the White House.
I promise you, I'm the one person
who can make this all work out.
Has he been released?
I've contacted the Russian government.
We've set things in motion.
But at this point,
we have to be realistic.
It's going to take more time.
More time?
Your national security advisor
has just been executed.
He's a very good negotiator.
He bought you another half hour.
Mrs. Marshall.
Alice.
If you please, come with me.
That's the first time
you ever seen a man killed, huh?
Leave her alone.
You think I'm a monster?
That I would kill this man?
Somebody's son?
Somebody's father?
I am somebody's son, too.
I have three small children.
Does that surprise you?
- Tell her to answer.
- Leave her alone!
Shut up!
Why did you kill him?
Because I believe.
And when I shoot this man,
I know in that instant...
how deep was my belief.
That I would turn my back
on God Himself...
for Mother Russia.
My doubts, my fears.
My own private morality.
It dissolve in this moment...
for this love.
You know, your father,
he has also killed.
- Is he a bad man?
- That's not true.
Why?
Because he does it in a tuxedo
with a telephone call and a smart bomb?
You are a monster.
And my father is a great man.
You're nothing like my father.
What's the goddamn number?
- What city please?
- Washington D.C., the White House.
- Just a moment. Here's the number.
- Can you connect me to that number?
- There's a connect fee of one dollar.
- Fine.
White House switchboard.
How may I direct your call?
All right, listen.
Listen carefully.
This is an emergency call from
"Air Force One. " This is the president.
Connect me to the vice president.
Who did you say is calling?
- This is the president!
- Right, and I'm the First Lady.
Don't cut me off.
This is an emergency.
The president doesn't call this
particular number, so whoever you are...
Trace the call.
Follow your standard security procedure.
Trace the goddamn call!
Okay, sir. You want to make
a federal case out of this, fine by me!
Hello. Anyone there?
Don't move.
- I traced the call, sir.
- Give me the gun.
- Are you there?
- Slowly.
Oh, my God!
I'll put you right through,
Mr. President.
The switchboard has a call from someone
claiming to be the president.
She traced it back to
the White House satellite account.
The caller's gone,
but the line is still active.
Put it through.
Listen to me.
You know who I am.
I'm the president of the United States.
- Yes!
- Quiet!
Don't think that means
I don't shoot you.
Put your hands behind your head
and move.
This is your lucky day.
What more can my people do?
Tell the F-15s to fire at the plane?
Even if they tried, we're equipped
with tactical countermeasures.
- He's talking to us.
- What do you mean?
I just want you to feel secure.
That way no one will get hurt.
The computer will fly circles
around any missile they fire at us.
- And no hit, just a shock wave.
- He's telling us what to do.
Believe me, all that would happen
is that we'd get knocked off our feet.
- That's all!
- Shut up!
My God! Is he saying
what I think he's saying?
- If we're going to act, we must act now.
- It's too risky.
The president is up there
with a gun to his head.
He's asking us to do that
to "Air Force One"?
He's not asking.
Your commander in chief has issued
a direct order. Do it!
Are you sure that's what
you want me to do?
You heard me. Let's pray it works
the way it's supposed to.
Boys, give me room.
I've been ordered to fire
on "Air Force One. "
I'm in position.
Missiles are armed.
The target is acquired.
I have a good lock.
God, I hope this works.
Fox Three.
What's going on?
The Americans fired at us.
I have no control.
The computer is flying.
Are they crazy?
This is Marshall.
- Anyone there?
- We're here, Mr. President.
Where's my family?
Are they safe?
The terrorists claim they're
holding them. We can't confirm.
Who are they?
What do they want?
They're Russian ultranationalist
radicals. They want General Radek...
...released from prison.
- Radek?
- What are our tactical options?
- We're working on that, Mr. President
- But the bastards have us in a corner.
- There is no rescue attempt?
I ruled out a midair rescue. We can
do nothing while the plane's in the air.
We gotta get this plane on the ground.
Take me off the speakerphone.
- Where's Bennett?
- Mr. President.
We cannot release Radek.
They're gonna shoot a hostage
every half hour until we do.
I don't want a plane
full of dead people.
Jim, they shot Jack Doherty.
Oh Christ!
We can't give in to their demands.
It won't end there.
If you die in the plane,
does it end there?
Kathryn, we've got a job to do...
whatever the cost.
- Mr. President, I-
- Kathryn...
...if you give a mouse a cookie-
He'll want a glass of milk.
We gotta get this plane
on the ground.
- Has Bazylev returned?
- No.
Get the plane on the ground.
This man down there evades us.
My patience is running out.
I thought I'd ask you
to come and join us.
It is starting to feel
a little empty up here.
Sit down. Please.
Come.
Tell me your name again...
for the record.
Melanie.
Melanie Mitchell.
You travel often...
with the President?
Yes.
So you know everyone on the plane?
I bet they like you, huh?
You're a nice person, yes?
I guess so.
You are trembling.
Why are you afraid?
Because I don't wanna die.
Tell me...
what am I doing at this moment?
You're pointing a gun at me.
Thank you, Melanie.
This is to the secret service agent
in the baggage deck.
I will count to ten.
And if you do not surrender,
this nice woman will die.
One.
- Please don't.
- Two.
- Don't do this!
- Three.
- Let me talk to him!
- Four.
- I beg you, please.
- Five.
Let me talk to the agent.
- Six.
- He might listen to me.
Seven.
- I beg you, don't do this.
- Eight.
- Don't do this, please!
- Nine!
Oh, God.
Let's think about that one
for a moment.
And then we'll start again.
Next time...
I'll choose someone
more important.
I know what you are thinking,
First Lady.
You want me dead.
It may come to that.
In a war, people die.
This isn't war!
You just murdered
an unarmed woman.
You, who murdered 100,000 Iraqis
to save a nickel on a gallon of gas...
are going to lecture me
about the rules of war?
Don't!
Mr. President,
how can I help you?
Chief, you can help me
dump some fuel.
Who's down there in the baggage deck?
- It's a secret service agent. Who?
- We have no idea.
Melanie was shot because one of your men
wouldn't show himself.
- I want to know who he is.
- We'd like to know ourselves.
Sir, it's someone
smart enough to know...
if you're hunting with one bullet,
you wait for a clean shot.
What are you saying?
Whoever that is down there,
he may be our only hope.
Our only hope is that Washington
complies with this bastard.
Because any minute now
another one of us is dead.
And you know what?
I'm afraid it might be me.
- Sir, do you see the maintenance panel?
- I see it.
Pop it open. There should be
a red switch. Toggle it up.
Hang on.
We got some indicator lights here.
To dump the fuel, you have to close
the circuit for the pump.
There's no switch,
so you'll have to cross the wires.
- Open the fuel control door.
- Hang on.
There should be five of them.
- Do you see them, sir?
- I see them. Yeah.
Jesus. There's a lot of goddamn wires.
All right, wait a second.
We got five.
Green, yellow, red, white and blue.
Let me double-check.
Come on. For Christ's sake, hurry up.
Get the wrong wire, you'll cut
the engine feeds. The plane will crash.
Then we don't want to get
the wrong wire, do we?
Cut the green wire.
Cut.
- Then, cross the... With the...
- With the what?
Hello? Cross it with the what?
Say again.
Cross the green wire with the...
For Christ's sake!
Wait, green...
yellow...
red, white and blue.
I'm counting on you,
Sirs, it looks like "Air Force One"
is losing fuel.
We're losing fuel.
Somebody is pumping it out of avionics.
I'm going downstairs.
Take Sergei.
If it isn't us coming out, shoot.
A magazine, quickly.
Are you okay?
Sergei? Kolchak?
What's happening?
He's dead. Give us a hand.
Madam Vice President, the time has come
for you to demonstrate your good faith.
I've been reading through
your press kit.
I understand "Air Force One"
is able to refuel in midair.
We need fuel.
And we need it now.
I'm sure we can come
to some sort of arrangement.
If you'll land the plane,
we'll trade fuel for hostages.
This is bullshit!
It's simple physics. Without fuel,
the plane crashes. Everybody dies.
We're trying to do everything
that we can.
Tell me what I want to hear, or I will
execute a member of the senior staff...
and continue killing one hostage
every minute...
until the plane crash
or refueling plane arrive!
What do you say?
Fuel's on its way.
Thank you.
They'll refuel us.
Ready.
Everything all right?
Yes.
Move.
- Jim, what are you doing here?
- I never left.
Watch the door.
Where's my family?
Another part of the plane.
We haven't seen them.
We got weapons now.
We should try to retake the plane.
Not while they've got Grace and Alice.
I can't take that chance.
What about trying to disable the plane
and force them to land?
I tried. I dumped some fuel.
Now they're gonna refuel us in midair.
A refueling tanker?
Jesus! Sir?
- There may be a way to get people off.
- What do you mean?
We have emergency parachutes
in the tail cone, but we're too high.
If we could get a message
to the refueling tanker...
get him to drop to 15,000 feet,
we could jump.
They've disabled the phones.
They control the radios.
- Mr. President? Sir? The fax machines.
- The phone lines are out.
No. Voice lines and faxes are on
two different systems of encryption.
If you disable one,
it'd be easy to overlook the other.
If this works, you get to be
postmaster general. Come with me.
- Get these people ready.
- Yes. Remember.
15,000 feet and 200 knots.
Otherwise it's suicide.
You'll need this.
Good luck, people.
- Where are we sending it?
- Situation Room.
It makes me so proud
that you stuck with us.
- Thanks.
- Whatever happens.
Yes!
Madam Vice President,
the attorney general is here.
- Thank you for coming, Andrew.
- Good that you're here.
You want my interpretation of what the
Constitution says about the situation?
Yes. Andrew,
my understanding is...
that if the president is out of contact
in a military situation...
the secretary of defense
is in charge as second in command.
- Yes, of course.
- Good. Then that settles it.
It doesn't settle it at all.
The president is not merely out
of contact. He is also under duress.
His family is held hostage,
possibly himself a hostage.
It creates an incapacity to discharge
the office under the 25th amendment.
Surely just as if he'd had a stroke.
I think the president would dispute
that any incapacity exists.
It exists if a majority of the cabinet,
including yourself, says it exists.
The president may be alive,
but he may not be the president.
Madam Vice President?
I think you need to see this.
This is CNN breaking news.
We interrupt programming to bring you
this breaking news bulletin.
CNN has received
unconfirmed reports...
that "Air Force One" has crashed.
- Oh, my God! How did they get that?
- I don't know.
The aircraft was en route from Moscow
when it began its Mayday hail.
I repeat.
We have unconfirmed reports...
Call the press room.
We have to issue a statement.
that the president's plane
has crashed in Eastern Europe.
- Has "Air Force One" crashed?
- That is a rumor.
- Where'd the story come from?
- I don't know where it came from.
Listen.
I cannot confirm anything...
at this point.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have a statement.
The president's plane,
"Air Force One," has been hijacked.
Please.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please let me finish.
For security reasons,
I cannot divulge...
the identity of the hijackers
or who was on board the plane.
But I'm here to assure
the American people...
that we are doing everything we can
to resolve the situation.
For the safety of all the people
on the plane...
I cannot tell you any more than I have,
and I'm sure you understand that.
Is James Marshall still the president?
I'm coordinating with
the National Security Council...
pending the president's return.
And, yes, James Marshall
is still the president.
At this time...
At this time,
I would like to ask all Americans...
to pray for the safety of everyone
on board "Air Force One. "
Thank you.
The president.
Where is the president?
Everything all right down there?
Yes.
Folks, listen up.
This is your main rip cord.
As soon as you clear the plane,
give it a yank.
If your chute doesn't open,
this is your reserve chute.
Pull it down. Clear?
"Air Force One," do you read?
Yes, we read. Go ahead.
"Air Force One,"
this is "Extender 1-0."
- We have been instructed to refuel you.
- Go ahead.
Drop to 15,000 feet
and slow to 200 knots.
Acknowledged. Two hundred.
- They got it!
- They got the fax.
Sir, your chute.
- Please, sir.
- I'm not leaving without my family.
Okay, "Air Force One,"
you need to open your receptacle door.
Pull the yellow lever
on the upper control panel.
Done.
Go ahead and close distance
nice and easy.
Almost there.
- Where are your chutes?
- We stay with the president, sir.
Thank you.
All right, that's close enough.
Here we go!
Go! Go!
Go! Come on!
Go check. Do it!
Go! You, come on!
The hostages are gone!
We got...
so far 25 chutes.
- I can't hold her.
- What are you doing?
Break away! Break away!
Sir, take my hand!
Everybody, break now!
- Don't move!
- Let me save him!
He's the president,
for God's sake!
Go get him!
Grab my hand!
Major!
I got you.
We have the president.
We've lost the tanker?
What else?
- They're counting 32 survivors.
- That means they still have hostages.
- What about the first family?
- No word yet.
Losing hostages will make
the terrorists more desperate.
Madam Vice President,
we've got "Air Force One" on the line.
This is Vice President Bennett.
We're listening.
I now hold hostage...
the president of the United States
of America.
Soon we shall enter
the sovereign airspace of Kazakhstan.
You will cease your military escort
at the border.
If you violate our airspace...
I will execute a member
of the first family.
Tell our fighters to back off.
Get me Ops.
You said a presidential incapacity
could be declared by a cabinet majority.
- Would you sign it?
- Under the circumstances.
See who else would.
Move! Come on, move!
Fast! Move! Quick! Right here.
- It'll be all right.
- I know.
You've been very busy downstairs.
Haven't you?
Killing my men.
You don't wanna do that.
I'm what you came for.
Don't forget that.
Then I kill them.
Or just one.
You pick.
That's what you do in the White House.
You play God.
Go ahead.
Which one lives?
You're not here for this.
You want something.
- What is it?
- Radek.
- How can I do that? I can't.
- Then you die, the three of you.
I'll do anything to save my family.
Don't ask something I can't give!
The most powerful man on the earth.
Suddenly, there are things you can't do.
This is very curious.
Stop with your fucking lies!
- Petrov will never give up Radek.
- Petrov is a dog.
He does what you tell him.
Tell him to do this.
Petrov used me.
I just wanted to stop the bloodshed.
He wanted a personal victory.
Petrov hates Radek.
Of course he hates Radek.
Radek is everything he is not.
A great man, a strong man.
Are you saying...
he would refuse you?
You'd be playing right into his hands.
Are you an idiot?
You'd make him into a hero.
The man who stopped the terrorists.
Or better yet,
the man who stopped me.
You talk as if you have nothing
to do with this.
This is all your doing.
This infection you call freedom.
Without meaning, without purpose.
You have given my country...
to gangsters and prostitutes.
You have taken everything from us.
There is nothing left.
Call him.
No!
Sit!
- No.
- I have no choice.
- You have the choice.
- Leave her alone. It's between us.
You lose a child,
it hollows you out.
We're soldiers.
You take my life.
Have you no honor?
- I'll count to five.
- No!
- It's gonna be all right, honey.
- One.
- It's gonna be all right.
- Two.
I'll do it.
Yes.
You just leave my family alone.
Leave 'em alone.
Sir, the president of the United States.
Mr. President!
We just got an intercept.
The president called Petrov
and asked him to release Radek.
- He can't do that!
- He must have no choice.
We have a choice.
I have the signatures of the cabinet
attesting to the president's incapacity.
- Sign it and you can overrule him.
- No. I won't do that.
The United States does not negotiate
with terrorists.
It's been our principle
for 25 years.
You can't give in to them now.
It'll be open season on
the United States. Many more will die.
Jim isn't making this decision as
president, but as a husband and father.
History will judge you
by what you do right now.
For God's sake, sign it.
You are released.
I can now confirm that General Radek
is in the process of being released.
I repeat. General Radek
is now being released.
Yes, yes.
General Radek has been released.
It is confirmed.
They are releasing the general.
Now what?
Now we return to our homeland...
where Radek will decide
how best to use you...
now that we know you are willing...
to negotiate.
Our nation needs so many things.
- You said you were gonna release us.
- Forgive me. I lied.
Listen.
- Sir, are you hit?
- Stay with the major, honey.
- Alice, get in the cockpit.
- Lie down.
- Let her go!
- Not until Radek is safely away.
Call it off.
Don't give up Radek.
If anything happens to the general,
your wife will die!
Comrades.
Our forces have arrived
for the general.
They'll pick him up any minute.
You hear that?
It's almost over, Mr. President.
Drop the gun!
You made one mistake when
you killed my pilot, Mr. President.
No one left to fly the plane.
And no parachute.
Whatever happens...
you lose and I win.
Get off my plane!
- You all right?
- They're leading the general to the courtyard.
Go.
Go! Call Petrov!
Stop! Don't move.
They killed him.
Mr. President.
He almost got away.
Did you hear me? Radek is dead.
Yes! It's the president.
We have retaken the plane!
- How's he doing?
- Not good, sir.
- I don't suppose you know how to fly.
- No, sir.
- Come along. I'll need a copilot.
- Yes, sir.
How long since you've flown, sir?
Twenty-five years.
Little planes. Never jets.
Nothing like this.
- Anybody there?
- Yes, we're here, sir.
You got somebody
that can help me fly this?
Sir, this is Colonel Jackson. We need
to get you out of hostile territory.
- Good idea, Bob.
- Look above the central video screen.
There's a series of L.E.D. numbers.
One of them should read 1-1-0.
- Got it.
- That's your course heading.
Just below, there's a knob
surrounded by hash marks.
Turn that knob counterclockwise
to 290.
- We're turning, Bob.
- Good.
- This will take you out of Kazakhstan.
- We're gonna be okay.
Now, we can't land this plane on autopilot,
so we'll need to go over a few things.
Where's the nearest safe landing site?
Incirlik, Turkey.
- General Northwood.
- Madam?
What's that?
Madam Vice President,
that red dot represents MiGs.
On course to intercept "Air Force One".
Christ! They took off from Aktubinsk.
The base commander there
is loyal to Radek.
General, send our fighters
into Kazakhstan.
Order them to use any and all means
to protect the president.
When you're on final approach,
keep the throttles mid-range.
- Mr. President, can you hear me?
- Yes, Kathryn.
We're tracking six MiGs closing
on your position. I'm sending in...
our F-15s to protect you.
- Shit!
- Did she say MiGs?
Yes, she said MiGs.
Get in that seat and put a seat belt on.
We're having trouble.
These MiGs get closer,
I'm gonna have to maneuver this thing.
How do I get it off autopilot?
Push the button on the yoke
by your left thumb.
I'll try a little right turn.
Keep your moves smooth and steady.
It's all flying.
Just step on the ball.
That's right.
Just like riding a bike.
Halo Flight, we are cleared to commit,
bearing 0-9-0.
Jettison tanks and push it up.
These MiGs, how far away are they?
Never mind.
- One coming. Countermeasures activated.
- Left turn.
Jesus Christ!
- We need some help.
- U.S. fighters, this is "Air Force One. "
We are under attack.
Where are you?
This is Halo Flight closing
on your position. E. T.A. two minutes.
We may not be here!
We're hit!
Christ. We're on fire.
We've got an engine on fire.
- Number four engine is on fire.
- Pull the fire handle overhead.
I got it.
- We're rolling right.
- Left rudder. You have to compensate.
- Do I pull back on number one engine?
- Negative. You'll slow down.
- Trim it out.
- How do I do that?
- Knob. Aft pedestal.
- Jesus Christ!
We got a red light.
Looks like we're losing fuel.
Halo Flight.
Everybody lock a bandit.
Stand by for max range.
And Fox Three!
Kill one!
Kill two! Four more bandits
bearing 0-9-0. Halo Flight engage!
Ha, ha! Good guys are here.
- Bug out west. We'll cover you.
- You got it.
- Sir, pull up! You got one on your tail.
- Get him off my tail!
Missile away.
- Break left and climb!
- Shit! Sir, we've lost countermeasures.
This is "Halo 2." They've lost
countermeasures. I'm going in.
Two's down! "Halo 2"is down!
"Air Force One,"
are you still with us?
Yes! We're still here.
Not so fast, you son of a bitch!
The last three MiGs
are bugging out, sir.
- We're clear!
- Yes!
- Bob, are you still there?
- Yes, sir.
Got a little problem here.
My rudder is sluggish.
Let me look.
Oh, man!
Sir, you're torn up pretty bad.
Do you have any elevator control?
It's sluggish, too.
And we're still losing fuel.
We got a problem up here.
Sirs, "Air Force One" is badly hit.
With the damage,
there's no way they can land.
I'm sorry, sir.
- Thanks for your help.
- I'll stay on your wing, sir.
Take it straight and steady
until we figure out what to do.
Sir.
You did great.
They can't control the plane. Engines
are failing and they're losing fuel.
There must be something
we can do to help them.
- Is that our airstrip strike team?
- Yeah. Why?
I just had a wild idea.
Time is critical.
Start turning north.
- You'll get more details en route.
- Yes, sir.
Change of orders acknowledged.
Try to hold your heading, sir.
They'll rejoin in about 25 minutes.
All right.
- We know it's risky.
- Understood.
But we are all out of options.
Yeah, baby?
It'll be okay.
Everything's gonna work.
Concerned Americans have gathered
at the White House...
to await word on the president
and his family.
But CNN has learned
that "Air Force One"...
is severely crippled
and virtually unlandable.
Sources report that the first family
is still trapped on board.
And a daring midair rescue operation
is said to be underway.
"Air Force One," this is "Liberty 2-4"
approaching on your left side.
- Do you read?
- "Air Force One. " Loud and clear.
Gibbs, they're here.
Get the door.
- We'll need 10,000 feet and 200 knots.
- We've got to get her slowed down.
"Air Force One" and "Liberty 2-4,"
this is "AWACS Blue Star. "
We have you in radar contact.
"Liberty 2-4,"
they're almost out of fuel.
Roger.
"Air Force One," keep the wings level.
If the engines fail, sacrifice altitude
to maintain airspeed.
Ready!
"Liberty 2-4," ramp leader.
First man is on his way.
Back up. Easy.
"Air Force One," come left, six.
- How's my speed?
- It's good. See if you can hold it.
A little more left, sir.
Three, two, stop.
Take my arm! Pull me in!
Come on! Come on!
- Unhook me.
- I got it.
Good.
"Liberty," locked in.
Where's the president?
Up in the cockpit.
- We lost another engine.
- "Liberty," we lost another engine.
"Liberty 2-4." Acknowledged.
Sir, time to go.
- Who's gonna fly the plane?
- I'll take care of that, sir. Got it.
Go!
Ramp to pilot.
Second P.J.'s on the way.
- Mr. President, this way!
- My family first.
- Sir, I have orders to take you off.
- Them first.
"Blue Star," the third parajumper
is boarding "Air Force One. "
- Standing by for recovery.
- Roger. Moving into receiver position.
- Dad?
- You'll be all right, honey.
- Promise?
- Promise.
Close your eyes.
You can do it.
Just hold on tight.
It's okay. Don't worry.
She's okay.
- Hang on!
- Ramp to pilot. We got her!
I'm right behind you.
Come on there!
Hang on. Good.
- You're next, sir.
- Him next. He's wounded.
- You go.
- Come on, Shep. Come on, pal.
We've lost another engine.
You're sinking too fast. We only
have time for one more retrieval.
We're passing 3,000 feet.
Impact in less than two minutes.
Get the president out of there!
Right here.
Easy there.
He's on.
- Get your arms ready. It's time to go.
- What about the other team?
There's no time.
I can only take one more.
No! We're all going!
That's impossible, sir.
I have to take you.
It's time to get you off this plane.
Go, sir.
Go!
Please go!
It was you?
- Give me the strap!
- I trusted you with my life.
So will the next president.
Now, give it to me.
We have to release the cable.
We're descending from 1200 feet.
I'm getting off this plane!
Seven hundred!
Five hundred!
We have to pull up!
"Blue Star. "
"Air Force One" is down.
I repeat.
"Liberty 2-4,"
do you have the president?
Right. You can do it.
- "Liberty," do you have the president?
- Stand by.
Hang on!
We got him!
"Liberty 2-4"is changing call signs.
"Liberty 2-4"is now...
"Air Force One"!
Mr. President, welcome aboard, sir.