From the silence
From the night
Comes a distant
Lullaby
Soul
Surrendering your soul
The heart in you not whole
For love
Walked out
Cast into the dark
Branded with a mark
Of shame
Of Cain
[Man Narrating]
If I could just go back.
If I could rub everything out,
starting with myself.
Starting with borrowing
a jacket.
Oh, such fleeting
paradise
Such innocent
delight
To love
Be loved
A lullaby
Then silence
- [ Woman ] Frances, that was lovely.
- I'm so glad. Thank you.
[ Man ]
Congratulations.
Marvelous.
Most enjoyable.
Herbert Greenleaf.
My wife, Emily.
Thank you.
Tom Ripley.
- How do you do ?
- You were at Princeton.
Most likely you'll know our son,
Dick. Dickie Greenleaf.
[Emily] I couldn't help
noticing your jacket.
Yes.
Class of'56.
How is Dickie ?
[Frances]
We've enjoyed meeting you.
I do hope that you'll
come out and see us.
- Thank you. That's very kind.
- Both of you.
- Herbert ?
- Yes, yes. I very much hope so.
Of course, Dickie's idea
of music is jazz.
- Oh, dear.
- He has a saxophone.
To my ear,
jazz is just noise.
Just an insolent noise.
- Very nice to meet you.
- And you.
- Sir.
- We'll see you at the shipyard.
- I hope to.
- Good.
I have to run !
I'm very late !
- Ah, you were great !
- You were great.
Darling couple,
aren't they ?
Yes, they are.
Exceptional young man.
- Thanks a lot for the jacket.
- Thanks for filling in for me.
Take care of that wrist.
Bye, Fran.
Believe me.
Buy I.B.M. now, before it splits.
You'll make yourself
a fortune.
You think so ?
[ Chattering, indistinct ]
[Piano]
Sorry.
[Mr. Greenleaf] Youĺve probably
heard Dickie's been living in Italy.
Mongibello.
South of Naples.
No kind of place
at all.
- Good morning, sir.
- Frank.
Marge,
his young lady,
is supposedly writing
some kind of book.
God only knows
what he does.
By all accounts, they spend the whole
time on the beach or in a sailboat.
That's my son's talent--
spending his allowance.
Could you ever conceive
of going to Italy, Tom ?
Persuade my son
to come home ?
I'd pay you...
a thousand dollars.
Well, I have always wanted
to go to Europe, sir, but--
Good. Now you can go
for a reason.
[Man Vocalizing]
[Jazz ]
Count Basie.
Duke Ellington ?
I don't know.
Dizzy Gillespie.
My funny Valentine
My funny Valentine.
- [Man, Woman Arguing.: Faint]
-Sweet, funny Valentine
I don't even know
if this is a man or a woman.
-[Continues]
- [Crashing]
[Arguing Continues]
Charlie Parker ?
Charlie Parker.
I know it. It's Bird.
Yes !
-[Ends]
- Ugh.
- Here. I'll take it.
- Thanks.
That thousand bucks
should come in handy.
- Yes, sir.
- I'll get that.
- Thank you.
- Sir. You're gonna have a great trip.
Mr. Greenleaf is personal
friends with the Cunard people.
[Opera.: German]
I can tell you, the Greenleaf name
opens a lot of doors.
[ Horn Sounding ]
[Man Speaking Italian
Over P.A. ]
- [Ripley] Do you speak English ?
- [Man] What you name, please ?
- Ripley.
- Follow me. No problem.
- Here, Signor Ripley.
- Okay.
Uh, there.
That one.
- This one.
- Wait, is that all ? Count them.
Attenzione.
Just one suitcase, Signor Ripley ?
- Si.
- Attenzione.
[ Man Speaking Italian ]
[ Italian ]
- What's your secret ?
- Excuse me ?
No, itĺs just that--
You are American, aren't you ?
I have so much luggage,
and you're so, um, streamlined.
It's, you know,
humiliating.
[ Italian ]
I'm Meredith,
by the way.
- Hello, I'm Dickie.
- Meredith Randall.
- Um, Dickie Greenleaf.
- Hello.
You're not
the shipping Greenleafs.
Oh, trying not to be.
Trying to jump ship.
So, uh, did they put
your cases in the wrong pile ?
Itĺs just that, uh,
you were in the "R" stand.
I thought
I saw you there.
My father wants me
back in New York.
He builds boats.
I'd rather sail them.
So I travel
under my mother's name.
- Which is--
- Emily.
I'm just kidding.
You know,
the funny thing is,
I'm not Randall either.
I'm Logue.
- As in--
- As in the textile Logues.
Trying to
shrug off the dress.
- I travel under my mother's name too.
- Randall.
Right.
- So, Rome, Rome, Rome.
- Oh.
- We're partners in disguise. Bye.
- Bye.
[ Shouting in Italian ]
[ Driver Singing in Italian ]
[ Chattering in Italian ]
[ Italian ]
[Bus Motor Starts]
- [Bus Drives Away]
- [Women Chattering]
[Ripley Speaking
Italian Slowly]
ôThe fiancÚe has
a face. ô
[Resumes Speaking Italian]
[ Italian Continues ]
Bird.
ôThis is my face. ô
[ Italian ]
[People Chattering in Italian]
[Woman] So I guess you didn't
look at my new chapter.
I will, Marge.
I promise.
Itĺs just been too hot.
If I make dinner at my place tonight,
maybe you could look at it then.
Dickie Greenleaf?
- Who's that ?
- It's Tom. Tom Ripley.
Tom Ripley ?
- We were at Princeton together.
- Okay.
Did we know each other ?
Hello.
Well, I knew you, so...
I suppose
you must have known me.
Princeton's like a fog.
America's like a fog.
This is Marge Sherwood.
Tom-- Sorry, what is it ?
- Ripley.
- How do you do ?
How do you do, Marge ?
- What are you doing in Mongi ?
- Nothing.
Nothing much.
Just passing through.
- Passing through ?
- Yeah.
You're so white.
Did you ever see a guy
so white, Marge ?
Gray, actually.
Itĺs just an undercoat.
- Say again ?
- You know, a primer.
That's funny.
Margie likes that
'cause she's so white too.
Yes, I do,
and you're not funny.
You should come and have lunch
with us before you go.
- Yes, Dickie ?
- Sure, anytime.
Well,
coincidence.
I don't remember him.
That's so funny.
Silvana ! Hey !
I've been looking all over for you.
Whereĺve you been hiding ?
Today you're looking for me. Where've
you been the rest of the week ?
You're always working.
Come on. Get on.
With the American girl ?
- Hold on to me.
- I hate you.
- Huh ?
- I hate you!
[Marge]
Did you suddenly forget where I lived?
I know. I'm late.
I'm a swine.
- It's 4:00.
- I just woke up.
- Ohh.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- You just woke up.
- Fausto and I took the boat out.
We were fishing, and then it was dawn,
and we caught absolutely nothing.
Mmm, yes, well,
we ate everything without you.
- We ?
- Yes.
- Tom Ripley's here.
- Who ?
- Tom. Hello.
- Hi.
-Hello.
-How are you? Thought you'd disappeared.
- We were gonna send out a search party.
- No.
- No, still here.
- Tom was telling me about his journey.
[Giggling] Made me laugh so hard
I almost got a nosebleed.
- Is that good ?
- Shut up.
I'm sorry.
I'm despicable.
But I love you.
- Do you love me ? Do you love me ?
- I'm intruding.
Can you mix
a martini ?
- Sure.
- [ Sighs ] I'll do it.
- Ohh.
- I make a fabulous martini.
[ Laughing ]
Everybody should have
one talent. What's yours ?
Forging signatures,
telling lies, impersonating
practically anybody.
That's three. Nobody should have
more than one talent.
Okay,
do an impression.
- Now ?
- Yeah.
[ As Mr. Greenleaf]
The only talent my son has...
is for cashing
his allowance.
- What ?
- Oh, I like to sail.
Believe me,
I love to sail.
- Instead, I make boats.
- Stop !
- Other people sail them.
- It's too much !
You're making all the hairs
on my neck stand up.
Oh, yes. Jazz.
Oh, jazz. Let's face it.
Itĺs just, uh--
Itĺs just insolent noise.
I feel like he's here.
- Horrible, like the old bastard's here.
- Good.
That's brilliant.
Brilliant !
How do you know him ?
Oh, I met him in New York.
Marge !
Marge, this is scary.
You've got to hear this.
Meet my father,
Herbert Richard Greenleaf l.
Pleasure to meet you.
Dickie's made a fine catch.
- Uncanny !
- I know Emily thinks so.
- I don't get it.
- It's uncanny.
Could you ever conceive
of going to Italy, Tom,
and, uh, bringing him back ?
- What ?
- I'd pay you.
If you would go
to Italy,
persuade my son to come home,
I'd pay you a thousand dollars.
[Dickie]
Iĺm never going back.
To actually hire somebody
to come all the way here...
to drag me back home--
Got to be a little
insane, doesn't he ?
- Ciao, Fausto.
- [ Italian ]
- This is Tom.
- Ciao, Tom.
[ Italian ]
- I'm never going back.
- No, I think--
Your mother, her illness,
I think that's--
It's got nothing to do
with my mother.
She's had leukem--
This is what makes me boil about him.
He wants me back.
- It's got nothing to do with my mother.
- Look, I don't know--
Go back.
Go back to New York.
Or call him, if you can find
a telephone that works,
and tell him wild horses wouldn't
drag me back to him or his shipyard.
- Hi, Tom.
- Hi.
Marge, Tom's saying good-bye.
Oh, I'll come down.
So, uh, did you
speak to my father ?
Oh, you were right...
about the telephones.
- I told you.
- There are no lines.
- There's some problem.
- That's Italy.
Tom. You're off ?
What are your plans ?
Oh, back, I suppose,
as slow as I can. Oh !
This bag !
Hey.
You like jazz.
I love jazz.
This is the best.
Baker, Rollins.
Marge says she likes jazz,
but she thinks Glenn Millerĺs jazz.
- I never said that !
- [Tom] Bird.
Thatĺs jazz.
Bird ? Ask me
the name of my sailboat.
I don't know. What's the name
of your sailboat ?
Look ! Look !
Bird !
[Marge]
Which is ridiculous. Boats are female.
Everyone knows you can't
call a boat after a man.
- He's not a man. He's a god.
- Okay, we're going to Naples.
There's a club--
It's not a club, it's a cellar.
-It's vile.
-Yes, it's vile. You don't have to come.
It's great. It's-- It's great.
You're gonna love it.
How are you ?
-[Ends]
- [People Applauding]
Oh !
[ Italian ]
That'd be cool.
Bring him up.
[ Italian ]
Tom Ripley !
Come on !
Get on up here !
- Yeah !
-  [ Italian ]
I'll tell you when
to join the chorus.
Come on.
Okay.
Together !
[ Italian ]
[Dickie] I bumped into
an old friend from Princeton,
- a fellow called Tom Ripley.
- [Keyboard Clacking]
He says he's going to haunt me
until I agree...
to go back to New York...
with him.
Afternoon.
What time is it ?
- Oh, God.
- ôGo back to New York with him. ô
- Here--
- You always type your letters ?
- That should be two T's.
- I can't write, and I can't spell.
It's the privilege
of a first-class education.
Your room's
upstairs at the back.
I think Ermalinda
made up the bed. Ermalinda !
[ Both Speaking Italian ]
- This is so good of you.
- Don't say it again.
Now that you're a double agent
and we're going to string my dad along,
what if we were to buy
a car with your expense money ?
- Okay.
- Great.
- Hello, Tom.
- Hello.
Marge, Marge,
what do you think ?
Little Ciquencento
with my dad's money ?
Oh, please, Dickie.
You can't even drive a car.
- [Tom] You can't even drive.
- What we need urgently is an icebox.
What do you think ? Agree with me,
and I'll be your friend for life.
- I absolutely agree with Marge.
- Hmm.
Icebox. Icebox.
[Bell Tolling]
[Marge]
So, what, is he gonna move in with you ?
It'll just be for a little while.
He can be-- He makes me laugh.
- Okay, darling.
- Promise you'd say ?
- No, I like him.
- Marge, you like everybody.
Don't like you.
[Chuckles]
Then I'll go to your place
and you can move in with Tom.
[ Imitating Marge ]
I like him.
[ Imitating Dickie ]
Marge, you like everybody.
[ Imitating Marge ]
No, I like him.
[ Imitating Dickie ]
Marge, you like everybody.
[Dickie] Now you'll find out why Miss
Sherwood always shows up for breakfast.
It's not love.
It's my coffee machine.
[Marge] Ever since Ermalinda
showed him how to make his own espresso,
he feels like quite
the grownup.
-I bought the coffee machine.
-[Marge] Oh, darling, is that for me ?
This is for Tom,
because he didn't complain.
[Tom]
That ring is superb.
Oh, Tom, I love you.
See ?
Ooh ! I had to promise,
capital "P," never to take it off.
-Otherwise, I'd give it to you.
-Isn't it great ? I found it in Naples.
I had to bargain for it
for about two weeks.
I hope it wasn't cheap,
Marge.
- Oh, it was.
- [ Chuckles ]
I have to get a birthday present for
Frances, so perhaps you could help me.
- Who's Frances ?
- My fiancÚe.
Engaged ?
You're a dark horse, Ripley.
- Who is she ?
- Your parents met her.
Oh, God.
Oh, I can just imagine.
"If only Dickie
would settle down.
Doesn't every parent
deserve a grandchild ?"
Oh, God.
Never. Never.
I swear on your ring, Marge,
I'm never going back.
- [ Tom ] Say when to pull.
- [ Dickie ] Pull now. Pull.
It's not pulling.
I'm doing it wrong.
- Better now, huh ?
- Okay, okay, okay.
We'll make a sailor
of you yet.
You're doing really well.
- All right. Bar's open.
- Yes, please.
- Hey, can we sail to Venice ?
- Sure. I love Venice.
"See Venice and die."
Isn't that right ? Or is it Rome ?
- Is it Rome ?
- I have to see Venice.
You do something and die, don't you ?
Okay. Venice is on the list.
And Rome.
Do you ski ?
Ah, no, no.
Don't tell me.
You're a lost cause.
That's the next thing to deal with.
Christmas, weĺre planning
a skiing trip to Cortina.
- Excellent skiing. Excellent. Marge.
- Yes ?
Unbelievable.
Tom can't ski either.
- We'll have to teach him that too.
- Thank you.
Such low class, Marge.
Does this guy know anything ?
Good thing we're not
getting married soon.
We'd have to invite Tom
on our honeymoon.
[Marge] Oh, I hated New York.
That whole Park Avenue crowd.
So I fled to Paris
to work on my book.
And I was always going
to this cafe in Monmartre...
with Jean-Jaques.
And Dickie would play
"My Funny Valentine."
It was only later that I found out
he only knows about six songs.
Anyway, I looked forward
to seeing him, I suppose.
[ Speaking Italian ]
[Men Chattering in Italian]
Hey, hey, Signor Greenleaf !
You're not at my place by 7.:00,
Tom and I are running off together.
- Okay, fine.
- [Man] Oh, Dickie !
[ Indistinct ]
Oh, hold on.
Hold on.
Silvana, Silvana
You make me smile
I need
to talk to you.
[Continues]
- [ Dickie ] You're breaking my ribs !
- What ?
You're breaking my ribs !
But don't
Change a hair for me
Not if you care
For me
Stay, little Valentine
Stay
Each day
Is Valentine's Day
Ohh !
[ Kisses ]
I could fuck this icebox,
I love it so much.
So, what did you actually
do in New York ?
Played piano in a few places.
I told you.
Well, that's one job.
You told me a lot of jobs.
Few places.
That's a few jobs.
The mysterious Mr. Ripley.
Marge and I spend
hours speculating.
Anyway, I don't even want
to think about New York.
Are you ready ?
- Cold beer. Thank you, Dad.
- Okay.
Copy out from here.
- You bring this with you to Europe ?
- You gonna write something ?
I love the fact that you brought
Shakespeare with you but no clothes.
Ermalinda says you wash out the same
shirt every night. Is that true ?
No. I have more
than one shirt.
She can do that for you.
Anyway, just wear
some of my stuff.
Wear anything you want.
Most of it's ancient.
Now your signature.
Not Dickie.
Your signature.
Without the glasses,
you're not even ugly.
I don't need them
because I never read.
- How do I look ?
- Like Clark Kent.
- Now Superman.
- Superman.
- Okay.
- I know.
It's like a kid's. See this, the ôSö
and the ôTö ? Fine, vulnerable.
That's pain.
That's secret pain.
Well, that must be a very deep secret,
'cause I don't know about it.
Hmm. There's nothing more
naked than your handwriting.
See how nothing's
quite touching the line ?
- That's vanity.
- Well, we certainly know that's true.
[ Dickie ]
Do you have any brothers ?
No.
No brothers,
no sisters.
Me neither.
Nor does Marge.
All only children.
What does that mean ?
Means we've never
shared a bath.
And I'm cold.
Can I get in ?
No.
I didn't mean
with you in it.
Okay.
Get in. I'm like
a prune anyway.
It is me.
It's an old picture.
Every time ! "Is it you ?
It doesn't look like you."
God !
Letters-- Greenleaf
and for Ripley.
Ooh. Fran. "I miss you.
When are you coming home ?
Stop telling me what
an incredible time you're having.
- How much you love Dickie.
- Whoo !
And Marge
and Mongibello."
And this one, I think,
is from your father.
[Dickie Vocalizing: Jazz]
- Let me see it. What does he say ?
- He's getting impatient.
He wants me to reassure him that you're
going to be home by Thanksgiving.
You've got to get
a new jacket. Really.
You must be sick
of wearing the same clothes.
I can't. I can't keep spending
your father's money.
I love how
responsible you are.
My dad should make you
chief accountant or something.
Or when I take over,
which is never, I will.
Okay. When you take over,
which is never, I'll accept.
Let me buy you a jacket. When we
get to Rome, there's a great place--
- Battistoni.
[ Italian ]
Roma, we're taking Tom
to Roma
Weĺre going to a-Roma
[ Chattering in Italian ]
Buongiorno.
Nice sweater.
Where do we get
a carrozza for the Forum ?
- Can we just hire any of them ?
- Relax.
Relax !
Itĺs just there's so much
to do in a single day.
The most important question is where to
eat. I hope Freddie made a reservation.
Freddie ?
Freddie.
Freddie Miles.
Freddie's organizing
the Cortina skiing trip.
Oh.
Oh, here he is.
[ Tires Screech ]
- Frederico !
- Comestai ?
- [ Italian ]
Oh, God, don't you want to fuck
every woman you see just once ?
- Only once ?
- Absolutely. Once. Ciao.
- Tom Ripley, Freddie Miles.
- Tom.
I mean, hey, if I'm late,
think what her husband's saying.
- You look gorgeous.
- As always.
So, mangiare.
Si. I got us a table
outside at Fabrizio's. Tommy.
[Dickie]
Outstanding. I tell you,
- I'm so cabin-crazy with Mongi.
- I know. I was there.
[Jazz]
Look, Tom, we got to go to a club
and meet some friends of Freddieĺs.
The best thing is, if you want
to be a tourist, grab a cab now,
and I'll meet you
at the railway station.
What club ?
Freddie's arranged it
with some of the skiing crowd.
Come if you want, but I thought
you wanted to go sightseeing.
I do, and then maybe get the jacket
and what have you.
Dick !
You gotta hear this.
Listen, just take
one of mine when we get back.
Don't worry about it.
Come on !
Ciao.
Have fun, okay ?
[Knocking]
You said to make sure you didn't
miss the train. Leaves at 8:00.
[ Snickers ]
Have a good time.
See ya, Tommy.
[ Whistles ]
[Whistle Blows]
If I meant
anything to her
I'd be brave, and hereĺs
the song I'd bring to her
I'd sing to her
May I be the only one
To say I
Really fell in love
the day I
First set eyes on you
-  May I
- What are you doing ?
Oh. I was just
amusing myself.
- Sorry.
- I wish you'd get out of my clothes.
- Do you have my shoes on too ?
- You said I could pick out a jacket--
Did you get undressed
in your own room ?
Thought you missed
the train.
Freddie drove me back
in his car.
- Is Freddie here ?
- He's downstairs.
I was just fooling around.
Don't say anything.
Sorry.
[Freddie]
God. A corduroy jacket in Italy.
- [Marge] Good morning, Tom.
- Morning.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Come join us.
Hey. I want this job
of yours, Tommy.
I was just saying,
you live in Italy,
you stay at Dickie's house,
you eat Dickie's food,
you wear his clothes,
and his father picks up the tab.
[Chuckles]
If you get bored,
you let me know,
'cause I'll do it.
- I'll do it.
- [Dickie] To the mainland!
You really should go in.
It's marvelous.
I'm fine.
[ Dickie Shouting ]
Are you okay ?
Sure.
The thing with Dickie--
It's like the sun shines
on you, and it's glorious.
And then he forgets you
and it's very, very cold.
So I'm learning.
When you have his attention, you feel
you're the only person in the world.
That's why
everybody loves him.
It's always the same. Whenever
someone new comes into his life--
Freddie, Fausto,
Peter Smith-Kingsley.
He's wonderful.
Have you met him ?
Especially you.
And thatĺs just the boys.
[ Dickie,
Freddie Shouting ]
Come get him !
Tell me, why is it
that when men play,
they always play
at killing each other ?
[Dickie] He's drowning me!
He's drowning me!
- I'm sorry about Cortina, by the way.
- What about Cortina ?
Didn't--
Didn't-Didn't Dick say ?
[Sighs] He spoke to Freddie,
and-and apparently...
it's not going
to work out.
It's because
everyone else can ski,
and it affects
where you stay, and--
[ Dickie ]
Come on, Freddie.
At least stick around for
the Festival of the Madonna.
- The whole town comes out--
- I donĺt think so.
I have my own, uh, Madonna back in Rome.
Why donĺt you come back with me ?
A lot of ladies.
Ooh.
[ Chuckles ]
- Oh, God.
- You want to take over ?
Yeah, sure.
Just point her at Capri.
Avoid the rocks.
Where are you going ?
Marge maintenance.
Aye-aye.
[Marge, Dickie Murmuring]
[ Marge ]
Don't.
[ Scoffs ]
- [ Marge ] Dickie--
- [ Dickie Moaning ]
Tommy.
How's the peeping ?
Tommy,
how's the peeping ?
Tommy, Tommy,
Tommy, Tommy, Tommy.
[Chanting, indistinct]
[People Applauding]
[Chanting Continues]
[ Screaming in Italian ]
[ People Shouting ]
Is someone getting
an ambulance ?
- Is someone getting an ambulance ?
- [ Wailing ]
[People Chanting]
[Chanting Continues]
[ Shouting, indistinct ]
What's the fight about ?
That's her fiancÚ, isn't it ?
- I don't know. Why are you asking me ?
- Are they blaming him ?
How can it take an hour
to find an ambulance ?
She was already dead, darling,
wasn't she ? So I suppose--
I don't know why people say
this country is civilized.
- Dickie !
- It isn't. It's fucking primitive.
I'll go see
what's the matter.
I'll go.
[Saxophone]
[Tom]
I know why youĺre upset.
I know about
Silvana, Dickie.
you and Silvana.
What about us ?
You don't have
to clean up ! Really !
- Like what ?
- Forget it.
She was pregnant.
Did you know that ?
Silvana was pregnant.
Do you know what that means
in a place like this ?
I'm prepared
to take the blame.
- What are you talking about ?
- You've been so good to me.
You're the brother I never had.
I'm the brother you never had.
I would do anything
for you, Dickie.
She came to me for help.
She needed money.
I didn't help her.
Now sheĺs drowned herself,
and it's my fault.
I'm not going
to say anything--
to Marge, to the police
or anybody.
It's a secret
between us, Dickie.
And I'll keep it.
[Tom Reading] ôDear Tom.
in view of the fact Dickie shows...
no more signs of coming home than
before you went--ö blah, blah, blah--
Um--
"I hope that the trip has
afforded you some pleasure...
despite the failure
of its main objective.
You no longer should consider yourself
obligated to us in any way."
Can't blame him.
You could hardly expect this
to go on forever, Tom.
Well, you can write again.
- Especially now we're brothers.
- I can't.
How can l,
in all decency.
You said it yourself.
Itĺs my dad's money you're spending.
We've had a great run
though, haven't we ?
Well, we'll still go to Venice.
We could stick to that plan.
I don't think so, Tom.
You canĺt pay
your own way, can you ?
Itĺs time we all moved on.
I'm sick of Mongi.
Especially now, with everything--
I really want to move
to the north.
I need to check out
San Remo next week.
Find somewhere new
to keep the boat.
It would be great, though,
if you came with me to San Remo.
There's a great jazz festival.
We could say good-bye in style.
What do you think ?
Our last trip !
Sure.
[Speaking Italian]
Why do you do
that thing with your neck ?
What thing ?
On trains, you always
do that thing.
Spooky.
Spook-- k-k--
k-k-- k-k--
[ Imitating
Jazz Percussion ]
Spooky.
[Cymbals]
[Jazz ]
Oh !
Didn't I tell you
San Remo was crazy ?
This is more like it !
Come on !
[ Ends ]
Grazie.
To Mongibello
and the happiest days of my life.
To Mongi.
You're cheerful tonight.
I'm suddenly quite happy
to be going back.
Did I know you
at Princeton, Tom ?
I don't think I did,
did I ?
- Why are you asking all of a sudden ?
- No reason.
Because you're leaving, I guess.
I don't think you were there.
- Why ?
- I mean it as a compliment.
You've got
such great taste.
Most of the thugs at Princeton
had tasted everything and had no taste.
I used to say,
"the cream of America: rich and thick."
Freddie's
the perfect example.
Then I'll take it
as a compliment.
I knew it !
I knew it.
Marge and I had a bet.
Do you even like jazz,
or was that
for my benefit ?
- I've gotten to like it.
- Oh, yes !
Iĺve gotten to like everything
about the way you live.
It's one big love affair.
If you knew my life
back home in New York--
I'm thinkin'
of givin' up the sax.
What do you think
about the drums ?
- What ?
- So cool.
I'm gonna rent a boat tomorrow,
take a look around.
This is how I found
my place in Mongi.
Took a boat out...
around the bay,
first thing I liked,
I got it.
- Whoa !
- Come on, Dickie. Donĺt go crazy.
- Dickie. Slow down !
- [ Laughing ] Hold on.
Wait a minute !
It's gonna tip ! Oh, God !
Stop it ! Somebody !
Somebody ! Stop it !
[ Shouting ]
Oh, I love it here !
I love it here !
I'm gonna move here !
Beautiful.
[ Imitating Cymbal
Percussion ]
I want to tell you
my plan.
- So tell me.
- Well, I thought...
I'd come back in the new year
under my own steam.
- Really ? To Italy ?
- Of course.
And I figured,
just for argument's sake,
say I got a place.
Or say we split
the rent on a house,
I could get a job,
or, better still,
if I got a place in Rome,
and then when we're there,
we could be there, and when we're here,
we could be here.
- I don't think so.
- Particularly with the Marge problem.
You just blame me.
- Marge and I are getting married.
- How ?
- Yesterday, you were ogling girls.
Today you're getting married ?
That's absurd.
- I love Marge.
- You love me. You're not marrying me.
- Tom, I don't love you.
- No, I don't mean that as a threat.
To be honest, I'm-Iĺm a little
relieved you're going.
I think we've seen enough
of each other for a while.
- What ?
- You can be a leech !
You know that !
And... itĺs boring.
You can be quite boring.
The funny thing is,
I'm not pretending...
to be somebody else,
and you are.
-Boring.
-Iĺve been absolutely honest with you...
about my feelings.
- Boring.
- But you-- First of all,
I know there's something.
That evening, when we played chess,
for instance, it was obvious.
- What evening ?
- It's too dangerous for you to take on.
Oh, no, no.
We're brothers.
Hey. And then you do this sordid thing
with Marge-- fucking her...
on the boat, while we
all have to listen,
which was
excruciating.
And you follow your cock around like a--
And now you're getting married.
No, Iĺm bewildered.
Forgive me.
You're lying to Marge and then
you're getting married to her.
You're knocking up Sylvana, ruining
everybody-- You want to play the sax.
You want to play the drums. Which is it,
Dickie ? What are you actually--
Who are you ? Huh ?
Some third-class mooch ? Who are you ?
Who are you to say
anything to me ?
Who are you
to tell me anything ?
Actually, I really, really do
not want to be on this boat with you.
- I can't move without you moving.
- Shut up. Shut up.
It gives me the creeps.
You give me the creeps.
- You shut up.
- I can't move without "Dickie, Dickie,"
Like a little girl
all the time.
Shut up !
Oh, God, Dickie.
- God's sake.
- Oh-- Oh God !
Okay. Okay.
We have to get you-- Okay--
[ Screams ]
I'm gonna kill you !
Kill you !
[ Screaming ]
You're dead !
Stop ! Stop !
Please ! Please !
- [ Screaming ]
- Stop it ! Stop !
- Dickie, let go !
- Iĺll kill you!
Stop ! Stop !
Stop !
[ Panting ]
Hi. Can I have
my key, please ?
Of course.
You must be very cold.
Uh, Signor Greenleaf, yes ?
No. I'm--
[Keyboard Clacking]
- Hello, Marge.
- [ Screams ]
Tom !
[ Chuckles ]
You startled me !
- Sorry. How are you ?
- You're back!
- Your book going well ?
- Yes.
I'm on a good streak,
thank you.
I was just...
Looking at you. So quiet.
[ Chuckles ]
Where's Dickie ?
I think he's planning on staying
in Rome for a few days.
Rome ? Ahh.
Did he say why ?
I don't understand Dickie.
Your guess is as good as mine.
What does that mean ?
Oh, one day I'm invited skiing,
the next day I'm not.
One day, we're one family,
then the next day he wants to be alone.
You tell me.
Is that what he said ?
He wants to be alone ?
He was thinking of you.
He asked me to deliver this.
Thank you.
[ Chuckles ]
He knows
I love this.
- But why it couldn't have waited. I--
- Errand number one.:
deliver Marge's perfume.
Errand number two:
pack some clothes
and his precious saxophone.
How long is he staying for ?
Search me.
I guess we're abandoned.
Goddamn it !
[ Tom ]
Are you okay?
There was a letter from Dickie
in with my perfume.
You realize it's more
than just a few days.
He's thinking of moving to Rome.
[ Sniffles ]
The thing is,
the night before
he left, we--
we talked about
moving together...
somewhere north,
and I suppose I...
put some pressure on him
about getting married.
I just--
[ Sobs ]
I just might have
scared him off.
There's a side to him...
when our heads
are on the pillow...
I know no one else sees
that's so tender.
I think I should come with you
to Rome and confront him.
He hates
being confronted.
I think youĺre right.
Grazie.
Checking in.
- Signor Ripley ?
- It's me.
Signor Greenleaf.
Of course.
Welcome back.
Thank you.
[ Woman ] Pronto ?
Yes, I'd like to telephone
the Hotel Goldoni.
- Si, signor.
- I want to speak to Thomas Ripley.
- Ripley ? Subito.
- Yes. Grazie.
- [Phone Buzzes]
- Pronto.
Signor Greenleaf,
Signor Ripley's not there.
- He's not there ?
- No, signor.
Well, I would like
to leave a message.
- He's not there ? I'll leave a message.
- No, signor.
- Got your call.
- Dinner tonight...
- sounds fine.
- Ripley. Ripley.
- Ripley.
- Dickie Greenleaf.
- [ Woman ] Dickie Greenleaf.
- Yes. Greenleaf.
- Greenleaf.
At the Grand.
[Tom] And Iĺd like to have
this wallet embossed.
I don't know
the word in Italian.
Embossed. Of course,
Signor Greenleaf.
Thank you.
Dickie !
It's--
- Oh, my gosh.
- Meredith.
- Ciao !
- Ciao. Come in. Come in.
But you're going skiing
with those Yankees, aren't you ?
- What ?
- At Christmas. To Cortina.
- With Freddie Miles.
- How did you know that ?
Oh ! Everybody
knows Freddie Miles.
Is Freddie in Rome ?
- Now ?
- Yeah.
Oh, I don't think so.
But l-- But I've met him,
of course, and we've chatted.
And I know about you...
and Marge in Mongi.
What an unreliable
rat you are.
Well, Freddie said
you were a rat.
And I thought
to myself,
"Ah, now I know why
he travels under 'R."'
I've left Marge,
Meredith.
And Mongi.
- So the rat's here in Rome.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, don't be sorry, no.
I've never been happier.
I-- I feel like
I've been handed a new life.
The truth is that if youĺve had money
your entire life,
either you despise it,
which we do-- agreed ?
You're only truly comfortable
around other people...
who have it
and despise it.
I know.
I've never admitted that
to anyone.
[ Chattering in Italian ]
[Meredith] Because my friend
Mr. Greenleaf, Signor Greenleaf and I,
are on a little spending spree.
- [Man] I see.
- We're behaving very badly.
Oh, I love Italian money. So dark.
Doesn't make you feel guilty.
- Gr-r-razie.
- Thank you.
I don't want too many large bills.
No one will change them.
Tutto bene,
Signor Greenleaf.
[ Counting in Italian ]
[Italian]
- I really like this too.
- I think I'm having that too.
[ Italian ]
- Tomorrow.
- [ Italian ]
- Arrivederci.
- Arrivederci. Oops !
- Ciao.
I know you're a jazz fiend,
but do you absolutely hate the opera ?
I've--
I've...
been trying to give
my tickets away.
It's tomorrow. But if
you were prepared to be dragged--
You could drag me.
[ Opera: Italian ]
[Shot Fires]
[Body Thuds]
[Audience Applauding]
Feodor Chaliapin.
It's the whole Russian baritone.
Thank you so much
for inviting me tonight.
Can you bear it ?
We hear you are a friend of Freddie's.
He has "I hate opera"
tattooed on his chest.
There's room for a whole
libretto on Freddie's chest.
I'm sure
we've met before.
I was sure we'd met before.
Weren't you, Ted ?
Dick is Herbert
Greenleaf's boy.
- I know.
- Yes, I think we have.
One minute you people are children,
and the next you're getting tattooed.
- Cheers.
Cheers.
- Excuse me.
- Prego.
Oh !
Excuse me.
- Hello.
- Tom !
- Marge !
How are you ?
What are you doing in Rome ?
- Is he here ? Are you with Dickie ?
- No. Um, no.
Um, hello.
Um, I'm Tom Ripley.
Peter Smith-Kingsley. I've heard
all about you from Marge and Dickie.
- Ditto.
- No-No glasses.
So, where are you hiding him ?
He's impossible, isn't he ?
Is he really not here ?
Marge, you know Dickie has
"I hate opera" tattooed on his chest.
- I thought you were going to Venice.
- Yes, what happened with that ?
I heard you were
desperate to come.
I was rather looking forward
to rowing you around.
- [Bell Ringing]
- I am. I really am.
I've been traveling, and I just can't
seem to get that far north.
Well, you should hurry,
before we sink.
Look, let me give you
the telephone number.
There. Oh, look.
There's Meredith.
Meredith. What's her name,
Marge ? The textile people.
Um, come on. Some of us
spent Christmas at her house.
I don't know her.
He hasn't called.
He's hardly written.
Just these cryptic
notes, you know ?
- You donĺt just dump people.
- [Bell Rings]
Look, will we see you later,
or are you with people ?
- Uh, I can't later.
- Well, how about tomorrow ?
Yes, uh,
maybe in the morning ?
Do you know Cafe Dinelli
at the Piazza di Spagna ?
- I know the Piazza. What time ?
- 1 0:30 ?
- We'll be there.
- Okay.
So I'll see you
in the morning, Marge ?
10.:30 ?
Very nice to meet you.
[Peter]
And you.
Come on.
Let's go back in.
I don't understand why
Tom's still in Rome.
- [ Whispering ] Let's go.
- I thought you were enjoying yourself.
Let's take a carrozza
and look at the moon.
Are you crazy ?
It's freezing out there.
Come on. I need to talk to you.
Just the two of us.
[Meredith]
Okay.
[ Meredith ]
Don't worry, please.
Don't worry.
You're such a pal
to understand. I--
It's like Marge is here
right now. I look at you,
and I see her face.
And I can't-- No matter
what I'm feeling towards you--
No. I absolutely...
understand. Of c--
Otherwise, you'd be
fighting me off.
Beating you away.
But will you meet me
tomorrow ?
Just to say good-bye properly,
you know, in the daylight,
so it's not just this.
Of course. Meredith, I'm sorry.
Of course I'll meet you.
You should always
save pain for daylight.
Why don't we have coffee
in the morning at Dinelli's ?
Uh, by the Spanish Steps.
Exactly. 1 0:30 ?
- 1 0:1 5.
- Okay.
Okay.
[Bell Tolling]
[Tolling Continues]
[ Italian ]
[ Chattering, indistinct ]
- [ Peter ] Grazie.
- Peter ?
Hello.
It's Meredith Logue.
[Peter] Of course it is.
Meredith, hello. Sorry.
- I was half asleep. How are you ?
- How are you ?
This is Marge Sherwood.
Meredith Logue.
How do you do ?
Do join us, wonĺt you ?
Weĺre just waiting for a friend.
I-- I won't, actually.
I think there's--
- Did we see you at the opera last night ?
- Uh--
Are you waiting for Dickie ?
Dickie ? Do you-- Do you--
Do you know Dickie ?
You were at the opera.
Oh, that explains-- Yes, I was there.
I was there with Dickie.
[ Exhales ]
I knew it.
I told you.
Marge, I don't know you,
so I've got no right to--
Dickie loves you.
He's-- Well--
I think youĺll find
he's on his way home to you.
[ Sighs ] Well, how-how-how
would you know that ?
He... told me everything.
No, I was supposed to meet him
1 5 minutes ago, so, uh,
I'm gonna go now,
I think.
God, unless he meant us
to meet.
Thatĺd be a little cruel,
wouldn't it ?
No, no, we're
meeting another friend.
- Tom Ripley.
- Do you know Tom Ripley ?
No, no. I've heard about him,
of course, but I didn't meet him, no.
- [Italian]
- Not for me. No, grazie.
Hope I didn't
complicate matters.
God, nothing, nothing...
untoward happened.
No, there is nothing to prevent you
from welcoming him back,
from marrying him.
Good-bye.
I'm happy to put a face to a name.
Good-bye, Peter.
Please, don't get up.
[ Marge ] Now I don't know what to
think. Do you think he's coming back ?
Sorry. Sorry.
Had to renew my papers.
Never one stamp when they
can make you line up for three.
- Have you been waiting long ?
- Not at all.
- Morning, Tom.
- Hi. Sorry.
You okay ? You look like
youĺve seen a ghost.
Dickie was at the opera
last night.
I don't believe that. Uh--
Wild horses couldn't drag Dickie--
[ Laughs ] Well, he was there
with someone, you know,
so I suppose she must
have dragged him.
It's not fair.
I think I'm going back to Mongi.
I think Dickie's coming home.
Really ? l-- Well,
thatĺs just swell.
No, you know, you're
way ahead of me. Great.
That was rather moving
when I heard-- I'm sorry.
Meredith is the American girl
I saw at the opera last night.
- Sheĺs been seeing something of Dickie.
- Oh, my God.
But the point is,
Dickie-- and we all know this.
Dickie loves Marge.
And he misses her.
I feel guilty.
Marge doesn't understand this,
but whenever Dickie does
something, I feel guilty.
[ Chuckles ]
As if that makes sense.
[ Italian ]
[Choir Singing
in Italian]
[Ends]
[Knocking At Door]
- [Knocking]
- [Piano: Stops]
[Freddie]
Dickie.
- [Knocking]
- Dickie, come on. It's me.
It's Freddie.
Let me in.
Dickie.
Hello, Freddie.
It's Tom.
Um, where's Dickie ?
How are you ?
I'm good. Uh, yes, thank you.
He's gone. He went to dinner.
- He's at Otello's. You know Otello's ?
- No, no, no.
I-l don't think he's
at dinner at 6:30 P.M.
If you said he was still at lunch,
maybe I'd believe you.
You know ? [ Laughs ]
Incredible.
I mean, the guy just, you know,
disappeared off the face of the earth.
I guess.
The landlady,
as far as I could tell--
The landlady said
he was here right now.
Search the place.
I-l just don't-- I don't know why you'd
imagine that Dickie would hide from you.
Because he's been
hiding from me.
- What happened at Christmas ?
- What about Christmas ?
He was supposed to come skiing.
I didn't get a cable...
or a call or a little note
or a--
- [ Grunts ]
- Frankly, a fart.
Well, he's been very involved
with his music.
Um, I think his theory... is...
that you have to go into a cocoon,
uh, before you can be a butterfly.
Which is horseshit.
[ Mutters ]
You hear him play this thing ?
Well, he can't.
How did you find him ?
It's such an out-of-the-way apartment.
Can I fixyou a drink ?
No, thanks.
At the American Express.
[ Strikes Random Keys ]
Some kid.
[ Strikes Keys ]
Are you living here ?
No, no. I'm staying here
for a few days.
- But--
- [Strikes Keys]
It's a new piano.
Probably shouldn't--
[ Striking Keys ]
- Probably shouldn't--
- [Strikes Keys]
Did this place come furnished ?
It doesn't
look like Dickie's, uh--
It's really horrible,
isn't it ?
It's so, uh, bourgeois.
Oh, that's a, uh--
You should-- Watch that.
Excuse--
Excuse me.
In fact, the only thing that looks
like Dickie... is you.
- Hardly.
- Hmm.
Have you done something
to your hair ?
Is there something
you'd like to say, Freddie ?
- What ?
- You have something you'd like to say ?
I think I'm saying it.
Somethingĺs going on.
Either he's converted
to Christianity,
or there's something else.
Well, I would suggest you
ask Dickie that yourself.
Otello's is on della Croce
just off the Corso.
Is it on della Croce
just off the Corso ?
Sure. You're
a quick study, arenĺt you ?
Last time you didn't know
you ass from your elbow.
Now you're giving me directions.
Thatĺs not fair. You probably
do know your ass from your elbow.
I'll see you.
[Door Opens, Closes]
[ Italian ]
[Freddie]
No Dickie Greenleaf. Thomas Ripley.
Si.
[Italian]
Ciao, Dickie.
Dickie doesn't
play the piano.
[Freddie]
Tommy.
Tommy!
[Freddie Groaning]
[Tom Grunting]
[Man And Woman Chattering]
Oh ! [ Laughs ]
You're making me laugh.
No. Youĺre just so drunk.
Oh. Youĺre just--
What can you do, eh ?
You should see my other friends.
- What canyon do ?
- [ Italian ]
Yes.
Such a pig.
- [ Laughs ]
- [ Italian ]
[ Imitating Freddie ] Hey, if I'm drunk,
think what her husband's saying.
- La polizia.
- Dickie Greenleaf?
- Yes.
- Inspector Roverini.
- Can we come in ?
- Please.
It's a terrible shock,
huh ?
W-What time did Signor Miles
leave yesterday ?
Oh, um, I can't be certain
exactly. I--
8:00, 9:00.
[ Italian ]
We'd both taken on, uh,
far too many drinks.
But it was dark. It was certainly dark
when l-- when I walked him to his car.
So he drove away,
and, uh, you did what ?
- I went to bed.
- [ Italian ]
Freddie's a big man, but I'm in trouble
after a couple of drinks.
I've been suffering all--
Who found him ?
[ Italian ]
You understand, I must ask you...
to stay in Rome,
Signor Greenleaf.
Yes, if it's gonna help,
certainly.
So, the doctor, he has to make
the, um--
- [ Italian ]
- Postmortem.
- Yeah, exactly.
But, you know,
his first conclusion...
was that Signor Miles was killed
not later than 7:00 yesterday evening.
Well, he certainly wasn't dead
when he drove away in his car.
No.
[ Chattering ]
[ Italian ]
It's okay.
- Okay ?
- Si, si.
- Did he kill Freddie ?
- Marge. When did you get here ?
Tell me the truth.
Did he kill Freddie ?
I'd swear he didn't.
Of course he didn't.
I tried again.
Waiting here, watching for him.
Instead, it's you.
Whenever I look for Dickie, I find you.
What happened to your face ?
Dickie--
Dickie did it.
- Dickie ?
- My face. There was an argument.
I-- I said some things
I shouldn't have said and l--
About you. About the appalling way
he's treating you, all of us.
And the next thing I know,
he's launched himself at me.
- Are you getting on ?
- What ?
Get on.
I'll take you to him.
[ Italian ]
[ Engine Stops ]
- Where does he live ?
- We passed it a few blocks back.
It's where the police were.
The Palazzo Gioia.
Look, they don't even know I'm in Rome,
and I'm not gonna incriminate Dickie.
Well, perhaps
I shouldn't go either.
No. Well, go if you want to, but just
don't talk to the police about my face.
If they know he hit me and his temper,
then he could've hit Freddie.
I'll catch up
with you later.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Italian ]
Signor Greenleaf !
It's Signor Greenleaf !
Presto, presto !
[ Shouting in Italian ]
Open the door !
Open up !
- [ Italian ]
- I live here !
Mr. Greenleaf !
Can we go up ?
Do you mind ?
Of course.
What happened to your face ?
My scooter. I fell off
getting chased by photographers.
The telephone, the press,
I've been-- I'm feeling hounded.
Do you think you could
not give out my address ?
Never. We've had many requests,
and we say no, even to your fiancÚe.
I really don't want
to see anybody.
- Even your fiancÚe ?
- Even her.
[Man Speaking Italian]
- What about Thomas Ripley ?
- What about Tom Ripley ?
You and Signor Ripley went to San Remo.
Is that right ?
Yes, we-- We went to San Remo.
That was months ago.
November, I thought.
Was it ?
- Did you speak to Tom ?
- November 7 is my information.
I donĺt remember
the exact date.
- When did you last see Signor Ripley ?
- A few days ago.
- Does he stay with you here ?
- No.
No.
Here is a pattern.
Two days ago,
Freddie Miles is dead,
hmm ?
He leaves your apartment,
and he's murdered.
Yesterday, a little boat
is found in San Remo full of rocks.
And the owner tells the police
it was stolen on November 7.
We look at hotel records...
and we see...
Dickie Greenleaf
is staying in San Remo.
And then our boatman remembers
two Americans taking a boat.
That is not a pattern.
That's a coincidence.
There must be 50 hotels
in San Remo.
There were probably a hundred people
renting a boat that day.
Thirty-one people.
Thirty-one, yeah.
[ Italian ]
- Marge Sherwood.
- That is Miss Sherwood now.
Let her in.
What's the difference ? Let her in.
No ! Actually--
Actually, no.
I would-- I would
really appreciate it...
if you would ask Miss Sherwood
to come back later.
[ Italian ]
Thank you.
May I ask you--
Why would you speak to your friend
and not your fiancÚe ?
Well, l--
I think I just said.
Um, Mr. Ripley was
handling some business for me.
Nor does Mr. Ripley
want to marry me...
and ask me every single day
if I'll marry him and when.
Do you keep a photograph
of Signor Ripley ?
I'm not in the habit of carrying
around photographs of my male friends.
Now I think I've upset you.
Sorry. My English,
perhaps, is coarse.
It is a little coarse,
yes.
I'm sorry.
But you-- No one has seen
Signor Ripley since San Remo.
- I have.
- You have, yes.
And so has Miss Sherwood.
Ask her. And, um,
if I can remember the name
of the hotel he was staying at--
Um, the Goldoni.
Tom was staying at the Goldoni.
Goldoni. The Goldoni.
Good, good, but--
Yes, you are right.
You are right.
A coincidence.
[Siren Wailing, Distant]
[ Sighing ] I look forward
to our next meeting.
Hmm ? When I will be
more careful with my English.
[Roverini] Ah. I have a witness
who thinks they saw two men...
getting into Mr. Miles' car.
And she wants to identify you
in a confronto.
Lineup. Tomorrow, then ?
Uh, tomorrow.
[ Chuckles ]
- Buon giorno, Miss Sherwood.
- Buon giorno.
He's in, but I really don't think
he wants to meet anybody.
[Knocking]
Dick ?
Dickie ?
I know you can hear me.
[ Sighing ]
I was gonna say that I would count to
three, and if you didn't open the door--
But I won't count anymore.
On you.
I won't count on you
anymore.
Whatever it is you've done
or haven't done,
you've broken my heart.
That's one thing
I know you're guilty of.
And I don't know why.
[ Sobbing ]
I don't know why.
I just don't know why.
[Footsteps Receding]
[Typewriter Keys Clattering]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Tom's Voice]
My dear Tom.
Iĺm getting out of this.
Freddie's death. Silvana.
Iĺve thought about going to the police,
but I canĺt do it.
I canĺt face it.
I canĺt face anything anymore.
I wish I could give you
the life I took for granted.
[Typewriter Bell Dings,
Clattering Continues]
You've always understood
whatĺs at the heart of me, Tom.
Marge never could.
I suppose that's why
Iĺm writing this to you,
the brother I never had.
The only true friend
I ever had.
in all kinds of ways,
you're much more like the son
my father wanted.
I realize you can
change the people,
change the scenery,
but you can't change
your own rotten self.
Now I can't think what to do
or where to go.
Iĺm haunted by everything
Iĺve done and canĺt undo.
Iĺm sorry.
Iĺve made a mess of being
Dickie Greenleaf, haven't I ?
Tom !
I'll see you over there !
[Bell Tolling]
I'm so sorry to put you
through this, Peter.
I just can't face going to the police
by myself when my Italian's so rotten.
Don't be so daft.
It's fine.
I'm delighted you finally
made it to Venice.
I'm delighted, contrary to rumor,
that you're still in one piece.
- What rumor ?
- Oh, you know.
That Dickie murdered you
and is traveling under your passport.
I know. It's ridiculous.
[Man Shouting in Italian]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[Phone Ringing]
Welcome to Venice.
God, this place reeks, doesn't it ?
Can you smell it ?
Anyway, I've got to
the bottom of the delay, finally.
We're waiting
for someone from Rome.
What do you mean ?
They've sent for someone from Rome ?
- Well, yes. That's good, isn't it ?
- No, I thought...
that didn't happen in Italy,
that each region is separate.
I was sure that--
I've read that--
You've read the papers.
You know what a big deal it's been.
- American tourist murdered.
- Actually, can we not do this now ?
- The stench really is--
- [Man Speaking Italian]
[ Italian ]
[ Continues in Italian ]
He's taken over the case, 'cause they're
annoyed that the previous chap...
let Dickie disappear
when he was, um,
the only suspect
in Freddieĺs murder.
[ Italian ]
In Rome,
about three weeks ago.
I knew that one.
Um--
[ Italian ]
Are you a homosexual ?
Interesting non sequitur.
No.
- No.
- Oh.
By the way, um, officially
there are no Italian homosexuals.
Makes Michelangelo and
Leonardo very inconvenient.
Eh ?
Tell him...
I have a fiancÚe.
And Dickie has a fiancÚe.
And that Freddie Miles
probably had a string of them.
[ Italian ]
Mamma mia.
- [Inspector Laughing]
- [ Chuckling ]
- What did he say ?
- He says "so many fiancÚes."
[ Italian ]
Heĺs asking... if you
killed Freddie Miles...
and then killed Dickie Greenleaf.
No ! No, I did not kill Freddie Miles
and then kill Dickie Greenleaf.
Is he accusing me ?
Ask him if he's accusingme.
The way it works here,
it's better to be less volatile.
- But itĺs absurd!
- [ Italian ]
[ Italian ]
They found this
in Dickie's place in Rome.
- You opened this ?
- Of course.
It's a suicide note.
You asked me all these questions and you
already read this suicide note ?
I don't believe that letter.
Do you ?
Dickie's letter.
Do you believe it ?
I don't know
what to believe.
Can you imagine, though, if he did
kill Freddie, what that must be like ?
Just to wake up every morning.
I mean, how can you ?
Just wake up and be a person ?
Drink your coffee.
Well, whatever you do,
however terrible, however hurtful,
it all makes sense,
doesn't it, in your head.
You never meet anybody
who thinks they're a bad person.
No, I know, but you're still tormented.
You must be. You've killed someone.
Don't you just take the past
and put it in a room in the basement,
and lock the door
and never go in there ?
- That's what I do.
- God, yes.
But, of course, in my case,
it's probably a whole building.
-  [ Piano: Stops ]
- And then you meet someone special,
and all you want to do
is toss them the key.
Say "Open up. Step inside."
But you can't...
- [Resumes]
- because it's dark...
and there are demons.
And if anybody saw
how ugly it is--
Now that's the music talking.
It's harder to be bleak if youĺre
playing "Knees Up, Mother Brown."
I keep wanting to do that.
Fling...
the door open.
[Resumes]
Just let the light in,
clean everything out.
If I could take a giant eraser
and rub out everything,
starting with myself--
The thing is, Peter, if--
- Hmm ?
- If--
If--
No key, huh ?
[Boy Singing in Latin]
[ Continues ]
- Marge.
- Peter.
- So good to see you.
- Hello, Marge.
Tom.
- I see you found Peter.
- I think we sort of found each other.
- Where's Dickie's father ?
- He's not coming till the morning.
Evidently his stomach. I don't think
the food here is agreeing with him.
Oh, I was looking forward
to seeing him.
Dickie hasn't killed himself.
I'm sure of that.
There's a private detective
on the case now.
A Mr. MacCarron
Dickie's father's employed.
- That's a terrific idea.
- He's American.
He's already discovered
that Dickie cashed checks for $1 ,000...
the day before
he disappeared.
[ Man ]
Signora.
Is that what you do
before you jump into the Tiber ?
I donĺt think so.
- Is this you ?
- No, it's Tom's.
Splendid, eh ?
Golly.
Who's paying for this ?
Peter found it for me.
I can afford it because
it's damp and... falling down.
- Tom's transformed it.
- This is spectacular.
That's why
Tom wanted you to stay.
It's better than trying
to squeeze into my room.
And I know
how you hate hotels.
A hotel would have been fine.
We'll have to tell Mr. Greenleaf
how far his dollar stretched.
- [ Chuckles ]
- What's funny ?
I was just thinking about when
Tom first came to Mongibello.
- And look at you now.
- Look at me what ?
To the manor born.
[Bell Tolling]
[Tom]
Mr. Greenleaf?
[Continues]
Tom. How are you ?
You look well.
- Thank you, sir. I am well.
- Far cry from New York.
- Yes, it is.
- Marge.
Good morning.
Unusual weather.
- Very.
- And you, sir. Any better ?
Pretty good.
Sticking with hot water.
- Where's Mr. MacCarron ?
- San Remo.
The police are amateurs.
Well, my boy, it's come
to a pretty pass, hasn't it ?
What is the detective
hoping to find in San Remo ?
Heĺs being thorough.
Iĺm learning about my son, Tom.
Now he's missing,
I'm learning a great deal about him,
and I hope that you can
fill in some more blanks for me.
Marge has been good enough
to do that about Mongibello.
I'll try my best, sir. Obviously,
I'll do anything to help Dickie.
-[Continues]
- Good. This theory,
the letter
he left for you.
The police think that's
a clear indication...
he was planning on doing something,
uh, to himself.
I just don't believe that.
You don't want to, dear.
I'd like
to talk to Tom alone.
Perhaps this afternoon.
Would you mind?
Marge, what a man may say
to his sweetheart...
and what he'll admit
to another fellow--
Such as ?
[Continues]
[ Clears Throat ]
What a waste of lives and opportunities.
I'd pay that fellow a hundred dollars
right now to shut up !
No, Marge doesn't
know the half of it.
And his passport photo.
Did you hear ? To scratch out
his own face like that ?
Can you imagine ?
Frame of mind
you'd have to be in ?
"I've thought about going to the police,
but I can't face it.
I can't face
anything anymore."
I feel guilty. I feel
like I pushed him away.
I feel like I spoke
and he heard you.
Well,
[ Clears Throat ]
if we all pushed him away,
what about him pushing us away ?
You've been a great friend
to my son.
Everything is
someone else's fault.
We all want to sow
wild oats,
but somebody's got to--
got to--
What is the word ?
You know, the moment
someone confronts him,
he lashes out.
He always has.
You know, people always say
that you can't choose your parents,
but you can't choose
your children.
- [Knocking]
- [Freddie's Voice] Dickie.
[Dickie's Voice] You can be a leech.
You can be quite boring.
- [Tom's Voice] Stop it !
- [Dickie's Voice] It's boring.
- [Knocking]
- [ Voices Overlapping, indistinct]
[Tom Screaming]
Stop, stop, stop !
- Stop, stop, stop !
- [Freddie's Voice] Tommy, Tommy.
[Dickie's Voice]
Like a little girl.
- Like a little girl.
- [Knocking]
[Knocking]
- Coming.
- Sorry. I was asleep.
- Finally.
- I must have fallen asleep.
- Did Dickie's dad go ?
You look ghastly, Tom.
Did you have a nightmare ?
- He's having an early night.
- Oh, poor man.
You know, we were banging
on that door forever.
[Marge]
Uh-oh.
- I think I've broken a strap.
- Not guilty.
- I'll fix some drinks.
- [ Marge Giggling ]
Ah !
You walk in Venice.
Are you okay ?
I'm fine.
- Did you want me to stick around ?
- No, it's okay.
I could come back.
Your key.
- [Knocking At Door]
- [Marge] Tom ?
Marge, I'm in the bath.
I won't be long.
Tom, I have to speak to you.
Itĺs urgent.
Coming.
- I found Dickie's rings.
- What ?
You have Dickie's rings.
I can explain.
Dickie promised me he would
never take off this ring.
Let me put some clothes on
and we'll talk about this.
- I have to tell Mr. Greenleaf.
- Marge, you're being hysterical.
He promised me, "I swear, I will never
take off this ring until we get--"
- Shut up !
- [ Gasping ]
I'm wet, Marge.
I've lost my towel.
And Iĺd really like
to put some clothes on.
Go and pour us both a drink.
Pour us a drink.
Marge ?
Where are you going ?
I wasn't snooping.
I just--
I was looking for a needle
and thread to mend my bra.
That scent you're wearing.
I bought that
for you.
The thing about Dickie--
So many things.
That day when he was late
coming back from Rome,
I tried to tell you this.
He was with another girl.
I'm not talking about Meredith, either.
Another girl
that we met in a bar.
He couldn't be faithful
for five minutes.
So when he makes a promise,
it doesn't mean what it means
when you make a promise...
or I make a promise.
He has so many realities, Dickie,
and he believes them all.
He lies. He lies.
And that's his-- Half the time
he doesn't even realize he's doing it.
And today,
I really started wondering whether
he may have killed Freddie.
He would get so crazy
if anybody would contradict him.
Well, you know that.
You know that.
And thatĺs the irony, Marge.
I loved you.
You may as well know, Marge.
I donĺt know, maybe it's
grotesque of me to say this now,
so just... write it on apiece
of paper or something...
and put it in your purse
for a rainy day.
"Tom loves me. Tom loves me."
- Why do you have Dickie's rings ?
- I told you.
- He gave them to me.
- Why ? When ?
I feel as if you haven't been listening
to anything Iĺve been saying to you.
I don't believe you.
- It's all true.
- I don't believe...
a single word you've said.
[ Gasping, Shuddering ]
You're shivering, Marge.
Look at you.
Marge, can I hold you ?
Will you let me hold you ?
- [ Screaming ]
- Marge ?
- Peter ! Thank God you're here.
- Whatĺs going on ?
Get me out of here.
Get me out of here. Please!
- [Peter] Tom, are you okay ?
- [Marge Sobbing]
You try.
You try talking to her.
- [Peter] Tom ?
- I give up.
Tell me whatĺs going on.
Tom !
- [Tom] What did I ever do to her?
- Listen--
Have her tell you one thing
that Iĺve ever done to her.
You can't be angry
with her.
She's confused, and she needs
someone to blame.
So she blames you.
I'll go back home
and talk to her.
As for you,
either get a safety razor
or grow a beard.
[Knocking]
- Is Mr. Greenleaf here ?
- Mr. Ripley ?
- Yes.
- I'm Alvin MacCarron.
[Marge] I donĺt know,
I donĺt know. I just know it.
[Mr. Greenleaf] Marge, there's female
intuition and then there are facts.
- Tom.
- Sir.
Marge, you should have waited.
I didn't--
Didn't Peter say Iĺd
come by and pick you up ?
Marge has been telling us
about the rings.
Yes, I feel ridiculous
I didn't mention them yesterday.
I clean forgot.
Ridiculous.
Perhaps you didn't mention them because
there's only one conclusion to be drawn.
Iĺm going to take Marge for a walk.
Tom, Mr. MacCarron needs to talk to you.
There's no need. We could go
to the bar. There's no need.
No, no.
I think you should
stay here.
[Door Opening, Closing]
I could probably
see my room from here.
I can see my house.
When you see where you live from a
distance, it's like a dream, isn't it ?
I don't care for B.S.
I don't care to hear it.
I don't care to speak it.
- Okay.
- Did you know that at Princeton...
Dickie Greenleaf
half-killed a boy ?
At a party over some girl.
Kicked the kid several times
in the head, put him in the hospital.
Boy had a wire fixed in his jaw,
lost some hearing.
Why do you think Dickie's father
sent him to Europe in the first place ?
The Rome police didn't think
to ask Mr. Greenleaf.
Nor did they think to check
on whether a Thomas Ripley...
had ever been a student
at Princeton University.
Oh, I turned up
a Tom Ripley...
who had been a piano tuner
in the music department.
You see, in America,
we are taught to check a fact
before it becomes a fact.
We're taught to nose around.
When a girl drowns herself,
find out if
that girl is pregnant.
Find out if Dickie
had an embarrassment there.
Mr. Greenleaf appreciates your loyalty.
He really does.
Marge--
She has a hundred theories.
There are a few things
that she doesn't know.
We hope she never knows.
I hope she never knows.
Three different people...
saw Dickie
get into Freddie's car.
One man,
who will not testify...
because he was jumping somebody
else's wife at the time,
saw Dickie removing license plates
from a red sports car.
The police know about this man because
he happens to be a policeman.
I found these in the basement
of Dickie's apartment.
They belong to Freddie's car.
Mr. Greenleaf has asked me...
to lose these in the canal
this evening.
[Bell Tolling]
Mr. Greenleaf feels that
there was a silent promise...
in Dickie's letter to you
which he intends to honor.
He also intends to transfer
a good portion...
of Dickie's income from his trust
into your name.
He does not intend...
to give the Italians any
information about Dickie's past.
He's rather hoping that...
you will feel the same.
- Thank you so much, Tom.
- Sir.
Good-bye.
Marge, I feel I never should have said
those things to you the other evening.
I was pretty flustered,
and the rings-- And you looked so--
I don't know.
But I hope that note goes
in your purse to New York...
for a rainy day.
- What are you gonna do now, Tom ?
- I don't know.
Peter has a concert in Athens
next month,
so he asked me to come along
and help out.
He says good-bye.
By the way, he was
in rehearsal so he couldn't--
Why do I think there's
never been a Ripley rainy day ?
What ?
I know it was you.
I know it was you !
- Marge, Marge. Please !
- I know you killed Dickie !
- Marge !
- I know ! No !
[ Sobbing ]
I know it was you !
Marge.
Marge, please.
It's not Tom.
Really.
[Tom And Peter]
We are called gondoleri
But thatĺs a vagary
Itĺs quite honorary
The trade that we ply
Ask me what I want to change
about this moment.
I don't know. What do you want
to change about this moment ?
Nothing.
[ Peter ]
I'm freezing. Coming down ?
Later. I want
to catch the sunset.
- You're mad. [ Chuckling ]
- I am.
[Meredith]
Dickie ?
Dickie !
[ Italian ]
Oh, my God.
Hello, Meredith.
I was looking at you.
Your clothes.
I wouldn't have known you.
Well, you spotted me,
so you get the reward.
- What ?
-Just kidding.
- Are you alone ?
- Oh.
Hardly.
Couldn't be less alone.
- Aunt Joan.
- And "co."
A lot of "co."
Oh, God.
You know, seeing you again, l--
I've thought about you...
so much.
And I've thought about you.
Yeah, well, when I've thought about you,
I was mostly hating you.
Where have you been hiding ?
I haven't been hiding.
I've been in police custody.
They've been trying to
flush out Freddie's killer.
- You're kidding.
- They're giving me this vacation,
which is why
the getup.
Which is why
you haven't heard from me.
You know, the whole world
thinks you killed Freddie.
- Oh ! It's terrible.
- I know.
Listen, I can't
talk now. Um, later ?
Later ? Later ?
So--
[ Laughs ]
Are you traveling
under "R" ?
[ Laughs ]
You know what ? I am.
[ Laughing ]
Dickie, are you with Peter
Smith-Kingsley ? I bet you are.
My aunt
thought she saw him.
Peter Smith-Kingsley ?
No, l--
I haven't seen him
in months.
No, I'm alone.
[Knocking At Door]
Hi.
- How was it ?
- It was good.
But I'll tell you something.
I want us to stay in here
for the rest of the trip.
[ Chuckles ]
Was that Meredith ?
Was who Meredith ?
Meredith Logue. You were kissing
someone. It looked like Meredith.
I came out to find you.
Oh, hardly kissing.
- Kissing off.
- It didn't look that way.
You know ?
From a distance ?
I lied... to her.
She thought she'd seen you.
Why lie ?
[ Chuckling ] Dickie and Peter
together. Thatĺs just too good gossip.
Or Tom and Peter, even.
That would be
even better gossip.
Really ? Why ?
[Sighing]
I-l, um-- [ Sighing ]
I'm completely lost.
I know.
I'm sorry, Peter.
I'm lost.
I'm gonna be stuck
in the basement, aren't I ?
Aren't I ?
That's my--
Terrible...
and alone...
and dark.
[ Chuckles ]
And I've lied...
about who I am...
and where I am.
Now no one'll ever find me.
[ Chuckling ]
What do you mean,
lied about who you are ?
I always thought
it'd be better...
to be a fake somebody...
than a real nobody.
What are you talking about ?
You're not a nobody.
That's the last thing
you are.
Peter.
[Sighing]
Tell me some good things
about Tom Ripley.
No, don't get up.
Don't get up. Don't get up.
Just--
Just tell me some nice things...
about Tom Ripley.
[ Chuckling ]
"Good things
about Tom Ripley."
That could take me
some time.
Tom is talented.
Tom is tender.
Tom is beautiful.
[ Crying And Chuckling ]
You're such a liar.
Tom is--
Tom is a mystery.
[Peter's Voice]
Tom is not a nobody.
Tom has secrets
he doesn't want to tell me,
and I wish he would.
Tom has nightmares.
Thatĺs not a good thing.
Tom has someone to love him.
That is a good thing.
Mmm. [Chuckling]
Tom is crushing me.
[Whispering]
- [Tom Sobbing]
- Tom. Tom, you're crush--
- [Peter Coughing, Gagging]
- [Tom Sobbing] Oh, God!
Oh, God!
- [Gagging Continues]
- Oh, God!
[Sobbing Continues]
Oh, God! Peter.
You don't know
What love is
Until you know the meaning
of the blues
Till you love the love
You had to lose
You don't know
What love is
You don't know how lips hurt
Until youĺve kissed
And had to pay the cost
Until youĺve
flipped your heart
And found you've lost
You don't know what love is
You know
Howa lost heart feels
The very thought
of reminiscing
And how those lips
With a taste for tears
Soon lose their taste
For kissing
You don't know
How hearts burn
A love that cannot live
But never dies
Until youĺve reached dawn
With sleepless eyes
You don't know
What love is
And donĺt know
You don't know
What love is