- Sync by: -
- AlexKay	-
What kind of pies
do you have?
Well, we got um...
Apple, pecan, cherry, key lime.
And which do you recommend?
Well, key lime's great, but...
it's an acquired...
acquired taste.
Well l ain't had
key lime pie in ten years.
When you had it did you like it?
No, but that don't mean much.
l was a completely
different person back then.
Let's give that key lime pie
a day in court...
And a big ol' glass
of nonfat milk, if you please.
Should l make that two pieces?
No, no, Rosie.
My name's not Rosie.
It's Mabel!
Whatever.
"It must have hurt your pride"
"To have to stand
beneath my window"
"With your bugle and your drum"
"And me, I'm up there waitin'
"For the miracle"
"For the miracle to come"
"l don't believe you'd like it"
"You wouldn't like it here"
"There ain't no entertainment"
"And the judgments are severe"
Goddamn, this son-of-a-bitch
is runnin' hot!
Y'all go on inside.
I'm gonna check it out.
All right, I'll get a
cold one for ya.
Good God almighty,
what the hell is that?
That?
A bitch out of hell, son.
Take a run at her, kiddo.
- Miller, Mabel.
- Right, comin' up.
Hey, Mabel.
"The way you love me
got to suit my style"
"Or little baby,
l will say goodbye"
That's some sweet
piece of meat, ain't it?
Her name's...
...Mallory.
Mallory, whatever.
Who gives a shit?
l call it pussy!
Hell's bells,
don't stop now, darlin'...
I'm just gettin' started!
Hey, l think
she's sweet on you.
Are you flirtin' with me?
Beep, beep.
You want a piece of it, darling?!
Your move, fucker!
Go!
Yeah!
This stupid...
Shit...
...list!
Shit!
You son-of-a-bitch...
It's not polite to point.
Just because my woman's
mopping up the floor...
...with your buddy,
is no reason to join in.
How sexy am l now?
Huh...flirty boy?!
How sexy am l now?!
Damn!
"You made my shit list!"
Why're they always
fuckin' with me?
Honey!
Come on, he's dead.
l just wanna dance.
Fucker!
No!
There's no escaping here!
Who's the lucky one?
Eenie, meenie...
minie, moe...
Catch a redneck
by his toe.
lf he hollers
let him go!
Eanie, meanie, minie, moe...
My mama told me...
...to pick the best one,
...and you are it!
Woo!
When people ask you
who done this,
you tell 'em
Mickey and Mallory Knox did it.
All right?
Say it!
Mickey and Mallory Knox did it.
Mickey and Mallory Knox.
l love you, Mickey.
l love you, Mallory!
Narrator:
Stars are coming out.
Look up in the brassy sky...
and there they are
like loony pocket change.
You bet on something you wish
you had 10,000 to bet on,
something where the odds are good.
Betting all those stars
won't mean shit...
l saw 'em getting out of the car,
...going into a door.
One of the cops looks at me,
and l say, "No!"
The whole world's
comin' to an end, Mal.
That's the angels, Mickey.
They're comin' down for us
from heaven.
And l see you ridin'
a big red horse.
And you're drivin' the horses,
whippin' 'em.
And they're spittin' and frothin'
all at the mouth.
And they're comin' right at us.
And l see the future.
There's no death,
'cause you and l,
we're angels.
That is poetry.
l love you, Mal.
l know you do, baby.
l've loved you
since the day we met.
Hi, Dad,
how was work?
What work?
I'm unemployed.
Where the
have you been, huh?
Well, you look nice, Mallory.
Yuck, you look like
Thanks, Mom.
Well, I'm gonna go now.
I'll be back at midnight, okay?
What're you wearing,
a broomstick and a trash bag?
Why don't you put
some meat on you?
A few pounds lighter,
you'll be Miss Ethiopia.
Where the hell
do you think you're goin'?
I'm going to the
John Lee Hooker concert with Donna.
l told you that yesterday.
First off, you don't tell me anything!
You ask my permission.
Second, you're not going out
in that whorehouse dress.
You'll end up peddlin' your ass,
you stupid bitch.
And third,
you're not going out at all.
You didn't mow the yard.
That piece of shit lawn mower
is fucked!
That's how you talk
in front of your mother?!
You stupid bitch!
You watch your language
or I'll kick the shit out of you...
like l do her.
So if your ass is in this house...
...it's my ass.
So you move it upstairs
and take a shower.
And you make sure
it's a good shower,
'cause I'm comin' up after
to see how clean you are.
Mommy!
Don't you think you were
a little hard on her, Ed?
I'll show her a little tenderness...
after l eat.
When l get up there
she won't see my face for an hour.
Darling, l think you should
speak nicely in front of Kevin.
Don't think.
You're a idiot!
What am l, the bad guy?
Did l ask you to
my friends?
And don't tell me
what to do!
lf it wasn't for me,
you'd still be slingin' hash
...in that shithouse
and fuckin' your boss!
Oh, that must be Donna!
I'll tell her the bad news.
Don't let your
macaroni get cold, Ed.
- Yes?
- Delivery for Ed Wilson.
What on earth is it?
It's beef, lady
50 pounds of beef.
Well you wait right here.
l have to have a word with my husband.
Who're you?
Mickey. Who're you?
I'm Mallory.
You oughta change
your name to beautiful.
You a big...
meat eater, Mallory?
l could be.
You always dress like that,
or you just...
...waitin' for me?
Why would l be dressed like this
for somebody l don't know?
Maybe something inside
told you to.
You know, like fate.
You believe in fate, Mallory?
Maybe.
You don't look too happy.
Wanna go for a ride?
Talk about it?
Now, Ed, you promised your doctor,
no more meat.
l eat what l want, so what?
This food here,
you pray after you eat.
It's just that l don't want you
to clog up your arteries
...and just keel over at the table.
Now don't cry!
It turns me off!
l haven't cried in 15 years
and you still haven't touched me.
Yeah, how 'bout him?
You were drunk and thought
you were in Mallory's room!
That's why we have Kevin.
What?!
You mean Mallory's my mom?!
I'm sending the meat back, Ed.
And l don't care
what you do to me!
You know what I'll do to you...
- Ed, look!
- What does it say?
"Out with the meat man.
Back before dawn. Love, Mallory."
Oh, that stupid bitch.
Ed, they stole your car.
My car?
Oh, that meat man cocksucker!
l broke her in
and he grabbed her.
I'll fix his ass too.
Call the cops! Come on!
Everything l see,
l see you, Mal.
l know, baby,
I'm goin' crazy too.
Even ugliness looks beautiful...
...'cause of you.
Even though I'm in here,
l visit you every night.
Listen, Mickey...
...my daddy,
he's gonna move us away...
so that you
can't never find me.
And I'm scared.
He can't keep me away from you.
He said if you ever show up...
...he's gonna kill you.
Kill me?
When's this supposed to happen?
Can l help you?!
He won't leave me alone.
He keeps fuckin' touchin' me,
and l can't take it.
l have to go.
'Cause if he finds out I'm gone,
he's gonna beat me.
l just wanted to tell you
l love you and l miss you...
...and don't forget about me.
- You won't forget about me?
- l won't forget about you.
It's cool.
No matter where he takes you...
...Timbuktu,
it don't matter.
'Cause we're fate.
You know?
Nobody can stop fate.
Nobody can.
One of these nights soon...
...I'm gonna be comin' for you.
Gotta go.
l love you.
Tornado! Tornado!
Move!, move!, move!, move!
All right you guys,
get on the goddamn bus! Now!
Get on the fuckin' bus!
Hey?!...
Stop or I'll shoot!
...break his arms.
There's no action here.
What am l watchin', two fuckin' fags?!
Kill him!
Kill the fuckin' indian!
Where the fuck
do you think you're going?
- I'm going out!
- You ain't going nowhere!
Hey Dick...Mickey's back.
Well, just the prick
l wanna see.
All right, fuck face!
Now I'm gonna take your eye out
and show it to you.
You been fuckin'
the wrong woman!
You stupid bitch!
You stupid fuckin' bitch!
"You will shut up!
You will eat your food!"
"You will listen to me!
Are you clean?!"
"Are you sloppy and wet?!"
"You stupid bitch!"
He's dead! He's dead!
Now where's the old bag?
He's dead. He's dead!
Hi, Mom.
You never did nothin'.
Wait!
You're free, Kevin.
Wherever we go,
or whatever happens, Mickey...
when l look up at the stars...
I'll know you're
lookin' up at the same ones.
Same ones, baby.
You make every day
feel like kindergarten.
All right!
l think we should get
a whole bunch of stuff,
because l need
a whole new wardrobe,
'cause I'm a new woman now, huh?
A- All right,
All right, honey.
I'm a new woman!
She's a new woman!
Past is behind us, Mal.
It's time to grow up.
We got the road to hell
in front of us.
- Mal?
- Yes?
Will you marry me?
Of course I'll marry you.
I've been waitin' for you
to say that for so long.
Well, where are we
gonna get married?
Right here, Mal.
This is our church.
l got the perfect thing.
Give me your hand.
That's not what l had in mind.
Fuck you!
Ow!
Okay, put 'em together.
It's very romantic, baby.
We'll be livin'
in all the oceans now.
God...
before you and this river...
...and this mountain,
and everything we don't know about.
Mickey, do you take Mallory
to be your lawful wedded wife,
...to have and hold
and treat right until you die?
l do.
Oh, baby.
Mallory, do you take Mickey
to be your...
l ain't gonna murder anybody
on our wedding day.
Fuck you!
God!
l do.
For all eternity
until you and l die,
...and die and die again...
...'til death do us part.
Yes!
By the power vested in me,
as God of my world...
l pronounce us husband and wife.
After that, there was no stopping
Mickey and Mallory.
They tore up the countryside with
a vengeance right out of the bible.
Tonight, I'm standing on
Highway 666.
Running through towns like
Cortez, Shiprock, Sheep Springs...
...and ending in Gallup, New Mexico.
To some, a beautiful stretch
of the American landscape...
...but to Mickey and Mallory Knox,
who are still at large,
it is a candy lane
of murder and mayhem.
Patrolman Gerald Nash...
was just the first
of 12 peace officers...
that Mickey and Mallory murdered during
their reign of terror. A DRAMATIZATION
Gerald and his partner...
Dale Wrigley,
were parked at this donut shop,
Alfie's Donuts, when...
This 1970 Dodge Challenger
pulled up across the street
from the donut shop.
Gerald, only three weeks
out of the academy,
come walkin' out with coffee...
...and my bear claw.
Hey you.
Driver asked him a question.
How the hell
do you get to Farmington?
Looked like he was
giving street directions.
Head on out on 324.
Take it over to 66
and Farmington's up about 65 miles.
Quick ride.
You folks goin' there?
When he finished
they waved him thanks...
then up come that shotgun.
You cop killin' cocksuckers!
Wayne: In the ensuing chase
a tragic murder occurred.
American bronze medalist
marathon bicyclist...
Brian Smith...
Mallory: l always wanted to
take a shot at one of 'em.
They're not so easy to hit.
We raped and pillaged
the first show.
We changed the order so
it wouldn't be so obvious.
It needs a new intro
in my opinion.
Who is this guy?
You can't cannibalize yourself
all the time.
- Repetition works, Davey.
- You're gonna wind up with shit.
Do you think those nitwits
out there in zombie land
...remember anything?
This is junk food for the brains.
It's filler, fodder.
Whatever.
Look, just build
it to the interview, okay?
Keep saying that word,
"Live Interview with Wayne Gale!"
Anticipation, Davey,
that's what it's all about.
What do you think of
Mickey and Mallory, huh?
They're hot.
Totally hot.
l love Mickey and Mallory.
They're so cool.
Mickey and Mallory are the best
thing to happen to mass murder
...since Manson.
But way cooler.
Take all the great figures
from the states:
- Elvis; Jack Kerouac;
- James Dean;
- They are supercool.
- Mickey, c'est l'homme!
Jim Morrison; Jack Nicholson;
- add a bloody pail of nitrate
and you got Mickey and Mallory.
I'm not saying l believe
in mass murder or that shit,
- Don't get us wrong.
- We respect human life and all.
But, if l was a mass murderer,
I'd be Mickey and Mallory.
"I'm back in baby's arms"
"l miss those lovin' arms"
l haven't seen a cop
for ten minutes.
Is there such a thing
as a cop-less town?
That would be paradise,
wouldn't it? Shangri La.
- You wanna get us a hostage?
- No.
What about her?
You from here?
Too heavy? Too fat?
What's the matter?
Do you think I'm still sexy?
Oh, man, we might have to
find us a motel here soon.
Soon as l see one
that looks nice
I'm gonna put my little
honey bunny bride down on the bed,
tie her up.
"Now I'm back where l belong"
"And in my baby's arms
I'm gonna stay"
TV: Offering a present
in the form of a flower.
Wanna go out and
get something to eat?
No...we'll stay in.
We got plenty of action here.
You know what I've been
thinking about, baby?
Course l know.
You been thinkin' bout...
rollin' around in that big
sunflower patch outside of Tulsa.
How'd you know?
...and you been thinkin' about
cuttin' your hair short.
And you been thinkin' about us,
settlin' down on a boat,
in the middle of a big lake
...with a dog and a jukebox
and a 26' Sony Trinitron.
Baby, l love it
when you can read my mind.
l bet l know
what you been thinkin' about.
Yeah, l been thinkin' about...
why they're makin'
all these stupid fuckin' movies.
Doesn't anybody
out there in Hollywood
believe in kissin' anymore? Hm?
Love you baby.
l love your knee.
l love your thigh.
Love your stomach.
l love your finger.
"There ain't no entertainment"
- Where is it?!
- Goddamn it, Mickey!
l just took it off so l wouldn't
snag my hair when l washed it.
Okay, baby, look.
Even if that ring pulls out
every hair on your head,
...it stays on.
lf it tears out my eyeballs,
it never comes off.
Every great thing we do
starts with these.
All right.
Since you put it that way.
TV: The impulse for sexual
reproduction is strong and unique.
"l know you really love me"
"But you see my hands"
Why are you lookin' at her?
"l know it must have hurt you"
"It must have hurt your pride"
I'm goin' for a ride.
Uh...baby, hold on.
l thought we could just
throw her into the mix.
Shut up!
Quit being so fucking cute!
You can be cute
all by yourself, little Mickey!
You're so fuckin' pretty!
You go fuck her!
Maybe l just will!
We gonna have some fun?!
No!
Fill her up.
- Can l look at that car?
- Go ahead.
That'll be, uh...
17 bucks, lady.
That's a nice 'Vette.
Wait a second.
Don't l know you?
l don't think so.
Do you want to touch me?
Yeah.
Tell me you want me.
l want you.
Tell me I'm beautiful.
Boy, you are beautiful.
Am l beautiful?
You're so fucking beautiful
l can't stand it.
Am l sexy?
Yes, you're sexy.
Go down.
Holy shit.
You're Mallory Knox, ain't ya?
That's the worst fucking head
l ever got in my life!
Next time, don't be
so fuckin' eager!
It's called, "Scagnetti"
on Scagnetti."
It's probably at your local bookstore.
- Why don't you go buy it?
- I WILL.
An author too, huh?
My wife could never wear these.
Now, that is a perfect ass.
It's nice.
There's her arm...
her head.
Dry saliva drops here.
See 'em?
That's my type of girl.
l like her.
Let's see what we
got here, Scooter.
Give it up.
Mallory Knox,
meet Jack Scagnetti.
Exactly, where do you
expect us to be goin'?
Where exactly are we
supposed to be?
What town is it that's out here?
Oh, fuck,
it's the fuckin' cheese.
Quit lookin' in the rear view.
Sit back.
Put the lighter on the floor.
Where's the bag?
Mal...would you relax?
Make a left up here.
l think there's a town.
All l see is desert.
Mickey:
That's right, Cochise...
go eat some more fried bread.
Give me some 'shrooms, Mal?
Mine ain't kickin' in yet.
Mickey: Turn left?
To what, stupid bitch?
Mallory:
"Aw, you stupid bitch."
"You stupid bitch?"
"You stupid bitch!"
Mickey, that's what
my father used to call me.
Thought you'd be
more creative than that.
You're losin' it, Mickey!
You're losin' it!
Snakes and birds!
Ain't nothin' out here.
I'd go down on a lawman
for a gallon of gas.
Let me tell you something.
This is the 1990's, all right?
In this day and age,
a man has to have choices.
A man has to have
a little bit of variety.
What're you talkin' about,
"variety"?
Hostages? You wanna fuck
some other women now?
Is that what you're talkin' about?
Why'd you pick me up?
Why'd you take me out of my house
and kill my parents with me?
Ain't you committed to me?
Where are we fuckin' goin'?
Just relax, all right?
It's me, your lover, not some demon,
not your father, all right?
Relax.
No, you're not my fuckin' lover.
You're not my fuckin'-
You been lovin' me?
You been fuckin' lovin' me, huh?
You've been lovin' me
real fuckin' true!
Hey...listen,
we got tobacco,
lots of tobacco, if...
You got any gas we can buy?
Mallory:
l don't think he speaks English.
Push comes to shove,
we can snatch that donkey
and ride on outta here.
Come on in.
- Oh!
- Oh, my God!
That a friendly snake?
That's a rattlesnake.
My name is Mal-lo-ry.
This is Mick-ey.
How...
you doin'...?
We're not from here.
It's kinda like "The Twilight Zone"
or something.
Is that your wife?
Oh.
Man:
Washington...
Mallory:
Oh, he died?
That was your baby, huh?
Feel the demons here, Mal?
l think we're the demons.
Mickey's dad:
Who you out there fuckin'?
- Your father.
- Bitch!
l said, shut up!
Come here, you peckerhead.
Mickey:
Don't...don't hit me!
Mom...?
l hate you,
you little asshole!
This is so bad!
- What did you do, Mickey?
- l didn't mean it!
Bad, bad, bad...!
Bad, bad!
Okay...get it together, now.
Come on-!
Mickey:
Come on, Mal!
Mal...?
Let's go!
Come on!
Why?
Why did you do that?
It was an accident.
This whole fuckin' thing is crazy.
There are no accidents, Mickey.
I'm human, Mal,
and l made a mistake,
- and you gotta understand...
- You are sick!
You killed life!
He fed us!
He took us in there!
Mal, that is a harsh indictment.
Mal...whoa-!
Hold it, hold it!
Leave me alone!
I'm going!
No, Mal! Hang on!
Mallory:
l got bit!
- Hold on, Mal!
- Oh, shit!
- Go on, Mal!
- l think there's more!
l know, hang on, hang on!
Stay right there, Mal!
There's more!
Hop on, Mal.
Oh-!
Know something?
Badasses don't die, Mal.
It's okay...
Just dreamin' and shit.
It's just a dream, Mal.
My name's Pinky.
Oh, yeah,
l remember, now.
My brother gave me this name
when l was six or so.
He said, "Well, you're about as big
as my little pinky."
l really don't like
these cheap motels.
Give me the creeps.
Say, are you a real cop?
I'm a real cop.
You're not gonna hurt me,
are you?
l never hurt anybody
in my whole life.
I'm the law, okay?
I'm your protector.
Come on over here.
Come here.
Take off them shoes.
You're real pretty.
Step up on the bed.
That's nice.
Move around.
Take off your bra.
Mmm...that's nice.
Come here. Come on down here
and gimme a kiss.
Give big Jack a kiss.
- You like me?
- Yes.
Pinky...
you ever been strangled?
Hey, just kidding with you.
Come on,
I'm just kidding with you.
Come here.
Give me a kiss.
I'm just kiddin'.
Come here.
I'm just kiddin', okay?
AAAAAHHHH!
Fuckin' bitch!
Mickey!
I'm coming to get you.
I'm not gonna make it.
l feel so cold.
You're gonna make it, Mal.
Get mad.
Just go get the stuff...
go get the stuff then.
All right.
TV:
Once they were average citizens.
Living drab
nothing-ever-happens lives.
But then these sweethearts
began a cross country murder spree
which has lasted
only three terrifying weeks,
but has left 48
known bodies in its wake,
including Mallory's own...
...mum and dad.
Oh, shit.
TV: All needlessly...
- Excuse me.
Aloha.
Uh...chief?
Rattlesnake took a chunk
out of us a ways back...
and me and my wife
are pretty sick.
Could be dying,
you never can tell about these things.
So, how's about you
ungluing your ass from that boob tube.
and getting us
some snake juice...pronto.
Found it yet?
TV:
They stormed in with shotguns...
and after liberating the establishment
of all the firearms they could carry,
and various personal
idiosyncratic knickknacks...
they killed every customer
in the place without hesitation.
"Come on...money!
Faster! Faster!"
But they always leave
one clerk alive...
...to tell the tale
of Mickey...and Mallory.
I'll be damned.
Mal?!
Mal!
Mal, cops!
Hurry! I'll meet you
out front with the car.
Go get the car!
I'll get the snake-bite juice!
No, please!
Well, that was sweet.
Snake juice.
We don't carry it.
Hospital.
Yahembey?
This shit keep you hard?
I'm the only clerk left.
- You're forgettin' something.
- W-What's that?
lf l don't kill you...
what is there to talk about?
- Fuckin' squid.
- No!
Mal?!
l forgive you, baby.
All right, get off of him!
Mal!
Fuck you!
What a stupid bitch!
Shut the fuck up!
Kill 'em all!,
kill 'em all!
Hey you bonehead sissy,
this is Jack Scagnetti, Knox!
Now you put that gun down!
Fuck you, Scagnetti!
Now!
I'll cut her tits off!
Go ahead, Scagnetti!
I'll get her some silicon implants.
l swear to God,
I'll cut her fuckin' tits off,
right here...
...right now!
Go ahead!
You ain't got the balls.
Don't give up!
He ain't gonna do it!
Shut the fuck up!
Watch this!
Hey, you like that?!
Oh, God!
Okay!
- Hey, put that gun down!
- Don't cut her!
Put your hands
where l can see them,
and step out in the light.
Kill 'em all!
All right!
I'm coming out!
Put your hands
where l can see 'em!
Now step out in the light.
Come on.
Yeah, come on out here.
Step outside, big shot.
All right!
Someone come get this bitch.
Come on...
get the big bad wolf.
Come on, come on,
give me that.
- You're in my light, motherfucker!
Shove over!
Oh, God, my eye!
Hold your fire!
Don't kill him!
I'm going to fuck with him!
No! Do not kill him!
One camera
all you can muster, Jack? Huh?
You ain't that big a star yet,
cocksucker.
You're on, you and me,
one on one, let's go.
Fuck you! Yeah!
Bring it, bring it, bring it.
Fry this cop killer!
How's that feel, big shot?
Fuck you!
Make that motherfucker dance!
Hey, Mickey.
Want a drink?
- Fuck you!
- Just jokin'.
Where's my baby?
Where is she?
Let her go...let her go.
You okay, babe?
Yeah, you're all right.
"These boots were made for walkin"'
"And that's just what they'll do"
"One of these days these boots"
"Are gonna walk all over you"
Hey, no pictures!
Clear the area!
- Always wanted to meet you, Scagnetti.
- Oh?
I really respect you.
You know what?
I even bought your book.
- And I read the whole goddamn thing.
- Oh, yeah?
How 'bout an autograph?
Warden...
...Jack Scagnetti.
Dwight McClusky.
Welcome to hell.
Great to meet you warden.
So how the hell
are my two favorite assholes?
We got them two ratfucks
back up in there.
- I guess you'll want to see 'em.
- Why not?
- I seen you on TV.
- Oh, yeah?
I even read your
goddamned book.
- I'm impressed.
- Oh.
Surprised Hollywood
ain't found you yet.
Your story would make
a lot better movie
than that "Serpico" shit.
I'll tell you something, Scagnetti...
in all my days
in the penal business-
and that ain't
no small amount of days, right boys?
- Oh, no.
- Nope.
Mickey and Mallory Knox
are, without a doubt,
the most twisted,
depraved pair of shitfucks...
it's ever been my displeasure
to lay my goddamn eyes on.
I'm telling you,
these goddamn motherfuckers...
are a walking reminder
of how fucked up
...this system really is.
Don't get me started, okay?
Don't get me started.
Dwight.
You call me Dwight.
They killed a shitload
of inmates and guards?
Three inmates, five guards,
one shrink...
...all in one year's time.
Open that goddamned gate.
- Psychiatrist?
- Yeah.
Miss Mallory,
strangled his ass...
when he made mistake of asking
what her parents were like.
She done it all
on tranquillizers.
Ain't love grand?
Ain't that the truth?
it's like that other big lie...
"Love makes the world go 'round."
I need to talk to you
about something...
How's a fella like you get to be
a specialist in psychos, anyway?
I'd recommend
having your mother killed by one.
After that happened,
I developed an interest.
I spent the first part
of my life in Texas.
You don't have an accent.
I don't wanna talk
like those assholes.
My mother was from Texas.
The ones who beat
the shit out of me.
When I was eight
we went to play in the park.
The same day Charles Whitman
started shooting strangers
from the top of
the University of Texas.
- And you was with her?
- Sure was.
The thing is,
I didn't hear any of the shots.
One minute
I'm with my mother...
and all of a sudden,
chest explodes.
She hits the ground.
Her forearm flies off,
her hip explodes,
and I'm not hearing
any of these shots.
Boom!
Chest explodes.
I spent all goddamned day
lying on the grass,
being eaten alive
by fuckin' ant's, thinking...
"What happened to my mom?"
And since then
I've had a strong opinion
about the psychopathic fringe
thriving in America's fast food culture.
I tend not to exhibit
the self discipline,
becoming of a police officer.
You got it right, Jack.
You don't mind do you,
if I call you Jack?
We got an army of
shrinks in here...
that talks about mania and
schizophrenia and multiphrenia...
...and obsessions.
it makes me sick.
it's all pride.
it's arrogance...it's bullshit.
Mickey and Mallory Knox
are not the sickest
I've ever seen.
Tonight's movie will be
"Escape from the Planet of the Apes".
So, why me, Dwight?
What's this really about?
Can you feel it, Jack?
- Silence in the air?
- Yeah.
it's the one thing
you don't want in prison, Jack.
- Silence.
- Uh-huh.
You boys all right?
What the fuck
is you lookin' at?
You boys all right?
I said, what the fuck
is you lookin' at?
Drop it!
Try this on, big boy!
Try it on there,
you son-of-a-bitch.
Now come on up here! Boy!
Now sit your ass up here.
Stick his ass
in F block for a month!
Then bring him to see me!
Jesus Christ, Dwight,
you could be on American Gladiators.
30 minutes a day,
shake and roll it.
Somebody goes for you...
you go straight for
their throat, right?
Mickey and Mallory got
the whole prison worked up.
- Like sharks to chum bait.
- Smell of blood drives 'em nuts.
80*/* of these assholes
are violent offenders.
We're over 200*/* capacity.
This ain't a prison anymore,
it's a time bomb.
Fry the pricks.
Every time we do
they kill somebody new,
and we gotta start
all over again.
Sounds like a hemorrhoid
you can't get rid of, Dwight.
That's why we're sending them
for testing to Nystrom with you.
Lobotomy Bay?
Vegetable land.
Home of the criminally insane.
- That hasn't been done in years.
- We got a stage one ruling.
it won't stick with these asshole
do-good shrinks around,
but it'll get 'em under your control
for a couple of hours.
Then what?
You're a celebrated law man.
Public loves you.
15 years on the force.
Best-seller out in paperback.
A modern day Pat Garrett with a
deadly axe to grind with maniacs.
That is why
you have been chosen
to delver Mr. and Mrs. Knox.
We, the Prison Board, know
once you get 'em on the road...
- if anything should happen...
- An accident.
- Fire.
- Escape attempt, anything.
Jack "Super Cop" Scagnetti
will be there,
to look out for his
public's best interest.
I'm getting the picture here, Dwight.
'Course, nobody
in their right minds
will cry for these
two pigfuckers...
if they happen to take
a little lead.
A lot of lead, Jack.
You write the script.
Call it anything you want to.
"Showdown in Mojave"
"The Extermination
of Mickey and Mallory Knox'
I don't give a shit.
I'm giving you
my two best men,
Kavanaugh and Wurlitzer.
We got a special disliking'
for these punkolas!
Have we found our man?
You know her,
you love her.
You cannot
fucking live without her...
Mallory Knox.
"...One in my heart"
"I guess I was born"
"Naturally born"
"Born bad"
Hey, Knox. Somebody out here
that wants to meet you.
"Born bad"
"it's such a sin"
"I guess I was born"
"Naturally born"
"Born bad"
Jesus Christ!
Don't worry about it.
She does this all the time.
She ain't changed a bit, huh?
So, where's the other half?
We got his stinking' ass
in the deepest, darkest cell
...in the whole dungeon.
You can't see him right now.
- He's got a special visitor.
- Oh, yeah, who's that?
Wayne Gale.
Wayne Gale?
The TV scumbag?
We call them medla, Jack.
Don't you like the media?
A worm in my bloodstool's
got more attraction to me than that.
The guy lives
to fuck cops over.
Can't say no to the media, Jack.
You want this job?
You come say hello.
I have a television show.
And every couple of weeks we do-
it's our thing about
"Current America"-
we do a profile
on a different serial killer.
Technically, mass murderer.
Well, whatever you want.
Anyway, the episode we did
on Mickey and Mallory,
was one of our
most popular ones.
Ever do one on
John Wayne Gacy?
Uh, yeah.
Who got the higher rating?
You blew him away.
What about that crazy motherfucker,
Ted Bundy?
Oh, that crazy guy?
You got the larger Nieison share.
You're big.
You're huge.
What about Manson?
Manson beat you.
Well, it's pretty hard
to beat the king.
Yeah. Anyway,
Julle, my producer and I...
We've waited a long time
to do a follow up episode on you.
And that time has definitely come.
I feel it's apparent to anyone
who's hip to what's going on,
that these prison boys
have thrown the Constitution...
...straight out the fucking window.
You and Mallory may be killers,
but nuts? insane?!
Today they wipe clean your mind,
because they feel
your actions are dangerous.
Tomorrow, they might
clean my mind...
or dump me into
fucking syndication,
because they feel
what I say is dangerous.
Where does it all end?!
Now, I have interviews
with the Prison Board,
and the psychiatrist,
Emil Reingold,
and with that warden,
Dwight McClusky,
and I'll tell you, Mickey,
they look bad.
Now, if you give an exclusive
to Wayne Gale,
we are talking
a  event here,
some promos on the Super Bowl.
The network will cream for it.
Oh, my God!
What a great idea, Julle!
We are  about
nothing less...
...than television history.
The first sit-down,
in-depth interview
with the most charismatic
serial killer ever,
one day before he's being
shipped away to a mental hospital...
...for the rest of his life.
This is Wallace and Noriega.
This is Elton John confessing
his bisexuality to Rolling Stone.
This is the Maysles Brothers
at Altamont.
This is the fucking
Nixon/Frost interviews.
What do you say, mate?
Why in the hell are you lettln'
this scumbag do this, Dwight?
Oh, relax. if I don't,
we'll be excoriated in the press.
if I do, it'll be weeks
before they can clear it.
Legal, appeals.
M&M are gonna be toast
before that ever happens. Rlght, Jack?
Nobody's gonna give a flylng fuck
about two dead losers.
Wayne:
What do you say?
Deputy:
Time, motherfucker.
Hey, hey...
come on!
Hey, come on!
Leave him alone,
he's a human being, for Christ sake!
Wait a minute...
just let him answer me.
Time's running' out, mate.
What's the answer?
I say, go for it.
Wayne:
in any case, he says yes.
Dwight: I thought he would, but
we're gonna keep contact to a minimum.
Wayne:
Okay...you just give me a large room,
I'll take it from there, okay?
We're stealth journalists.
if I was you, I'd worry more
about the promos
that start hittin'
the air next week.
You'll be a national face, Warden,
a hero to the public.
- No...
- it's true. Who knows...?
you could even
launch a new career here.
Julle, my producer, is gonna fax you
in the morning with the details.
I've gotta get back
to the Rotten Apple.
I'm doing a benefit tonight
for the homeless transsexual veterans.
"Dearest Mallory:
You once told me
I had no feelings.
You were right,
and you were wrong.
I got more feelings now
than I ever had before.
I've been reading a lot,
and doing yoga with this guy...
but, he pissed me off.
He's not around anymore.
At night, I pretend
you're lying next to me.
I lie in my cell...
I imagine kissing you,
not making love,
just kissing for hours
and hours on end.
I remember everything
about our time.
I remember every secret
you ever shared.
I remember every single time
you laughed...
and your dancing,
oh, my God, your dancing.
I lie on my bed
and go over every day,
every minute of our happiness.
I take it all as it comes,
and I live that day again.
That way, when I get
to our first kiss,
they're not just memories.
I feel that joy again."
Dr. Reingold, are they insane?
insane?
...No.
Psychotic...yes.
it's right after the Super Bowl.
We've got 'em in their homes,
the game has just sucked,
and they want to see this guy, Mickey.
What's he like...?
A country numb with violence...
These guys want to tear
their wives' heads off!
Yeah, but some of them...
Mickey and Mallory
know the difference
between right and wrong.
They just don't give a damn.
This will be the most talked about
event in television history!
...they were sexually abused
as children, Dr. Reingold?
I can't imagine.
I don't think...that it's...
I would say...no.
When you suggested that I marry
your daughter after I got her pregnant,
that's exactly what I did.
Now, you listen to me...
if you blow this,
CBS will be eating your lunch
next season,
and I'll be there with them,
'cause I'm out of here!
I'm out!
...Mallory Knox has said
that she does want to kill you.
I never really believe
what women say to me.
Margaret, darling, I don't know
what you think you found,
but it's not
what you think it is.
Margaret:
Just tell me who Ming is.
"Ming"?
There's no "Ming".
That's a fuckin' restaurant!
What do you mean
going through my drawers?
I don't go through your drawers.
Davey, this looks like it was cut
with a fuckin' meat cleaver.
And where's my close ups?
Now, listen...
less of the shrink,
keep the teens,
keep the longhairs...
I love the cop
at the doughnut shop,
and I love McClusky.
Cut in on him in the middle
of that horrific fuckin' laugh.
Freeze frame on him.
Don't even let him answer.
Then, cut to me at the trial.
"Their subsequent trial...
turned into a sick,
pathetic circus.
The nation caught Mickey
and Mallory fire."
Mike Griffin is who these
misguided should be revering.
Mike Jerome Griffin was killed
in the line of duty...
by these suckling,
degenerate bags!
We Want Mickey!
We Want Mallory!
What do you think
of this turnout, Mallory?
I've never had more fun in my life!
Scumbag!
Ming...Ming, first of all,
slow down. Speak English.
Okay? You're paranoid.
Nah, she's not on to us.
I don't give a fuck
what the I Ching says!
Just don't put anything
down on paper. Ever.
if she calls back, you say,
"Hello, Ming Dynasty Restaurant...
Number Five,
may I take your order?"
What do you have to say
to your fans?
You ain't seen nothin' yet.
How the hell did you let
this show go live, Dwight?
Couldn't help it,
just got out of hand.
Doesn't change a thing, though.
Gonna move them in the morning,
just a little bit
ahead of schedule, that's all.
You know, Dwight, when I do
these two ratfucking douche bags,
I'll go right up there
with Jack Ruby, huh?
World famous, huh?
Hall of Fame.
You'll be bigger, Jack.
Lee Harvey Oswald was a pussy.
Oswald might have been a pussy,
but he was a great shot.
Do you hear it, Jack?
- Hear what?
- it's dead quiet.
it's dangerous
when it's dead quiet.
A- hem-
Okay.
Testing, one-two-three...
Wayne, don't blow this.
Hey, how goes it, brother?
Doing some hard time, huh?
What'd they get you for?
Murder.
Yeah, that's a rough one, there.
I'm with you.
Show time.
TV: And Dallas, your Cowboys
are the Super Bowl Champions...
Rlght after the game,
stay tuned for a special
"American Maniacs",
on W-A-T-C-H.
Mickey Knox is the most
dangerous man in America,
but Wayne Gale isn't afraid
to meet him, one on one,
to learn what 48 people died for.
is this man insane? Or does he belong
where he sent so many others-
...in the grave?
Mickey Knox,
thank you for this time.
I've got a few questions
to start with, if you don't mind?
Ahem-Well, that's really
nice, Wayne.
Mickey Knox, when did you
start thinking about killing?
Birth. I was thrown into a flaming
pit of scum forgotten by God.
What do you mean by that?
I mean, I came from violence,
it was in my blood.
My dad had it,
his dad had it.
- it's just my fate.
- Do you believe in fate, boy?
- My fate.
- No one is born evil, Mickey...
it's something you learn.
What about your father?
How did he die?
You were only 10 years old,
and there's a lot of speculation...
I didn't kill my father,
and I don't wanna talk about that shit.
Hey, hey...!
Watch it, watch it-
it's all right, it's okay...
it's okay.
Go on to something else, okay?
Please, let's do.
So, tell me, how can you look
at an ordinary person,
an innocent guy with kids,
and then, shoot him to death?
I mean, how can you
bring yourself to do that?
innocent? Who's innocent,
Wayne? You ?
I'm innocent, yes, I am.
Of murder, definitely.
it's just murder, man.
All of God's creatures do it,
some form or another,
I mean, you look in the forest...
you got species
killing other species.
Our  is killin' all the species
including' the forest,
and we just call it
"industry", not murder.
But I know a lot of people
who deserve to die.
Why do they deserve to die?
I think everybody got
something in their past,
some sin, some awful,
secret thing.
A lot of people walking around
out there, already dead.
Just need to be
put out of their misery.
That's where I come in.
Fate's messenger.
"Except a corn of wheat
falleth to the ground and die,
it abideth alone. But if it die,
it bringeth forth much fruit."
Oh, the theory that "everyone
meets a serial killer halfway" thing?
Is that what you're saying?
The wolf don't know why he's a wolf,
the deer don't know why he's a deer.
God just made it that way.
You're saying the world itself
is predatory,
that when a mountain lion
takes down an elk,
it's because it's the
elk's time to go.
And all the b.s. liberal agenda
about saving the animal herds...
only serves to overpopulate
the balance of nature.
Maybe you're right, Mickey.
I don't think so,
but maybe you're right.
Corporate predators...
environmental predators,
nuclear predators.
Life is a hunt.
I've seen it. I was there.
When the
hit the fan at Grenada,
I saw it all go down at Grenada.
So tell me, Mickey,
any regrets?
Three weeks, 50 people killed.
Not too cool, Mickey.
52, but I don't spend
a lot of time with regret.
That's a wasted emotion.
Seriously, you must have
some regret. Rack your brain.
Well, I wish that indian
hadn't got killed.
Bad, bad, bad
bad, bad!
One of your last victims.
Man had a rattlesnake
sitting' in the corner.
A rattlesnake?
Could pick it up, pet it.
He saw it.
He saw what?
The demon.
He saw the demon.
The demon?
What demon?
Everybody got the demon
in here, okay?
The demon lives in here.
it feeds on your hate.
Cuts, kills, rapes...
it uses your weakness, your fears.
Only the vicious survive.
All right, you tell 'em.
We're told we're no good pieces of shit
from the time we could breathe.
After a while,
you kind of become bad.
After the indian
we were gonna quit killin'.
The old man
took it out of us.
- What happened?
- it was just a mistake, you know...
Man was tryin' to help us,
you know, pet us.
Same dream I've had
since I was a kid, I guess.
I was just runnin' with the animals
in the darkness.
Mr. Rabbit, bloody fangs,
Christmas hat...
little, uh...
madness going on and I don't know,
we're just runnin'...
and I'm just...
I'm Mr. Rabbit. I'm eating'
every other animal in the forest.
Death, just-death
kinda becomes what you are.
After a while,
you begin to like it.
You know about realization?
I mean, all this, is just illusion.
Mr. Rabbit says,
"the moment of realization...
the moment of realization...
is worth...
a thousand prayers."
You're crazy, mate.
I don't think I'm any crazier
than you are.
I'm extremes, dark and light.
You know that.
I'm light with Mal.
Mal...Mal.
That's your shadow on the wall,
you know.
You can't get rid of your shadow,
can you, Wayne?
Now, you know, the only thing
that kills a demon?
Love.
That's why I know
Mallory's my salvation.
She was teaching me
how to love.
Mallory:
I forgive you, baby.
Yeah, it was just like...
being in the Garden of Eden.
"Only love...
can kill the demon."
Hold that thought.
Are these guys
in your eye line? I'm sorry, man.
You want some powder?
Do you want some powder?
Rise and shine, Mallory.
Turn around and face the wall.
Relax, fellas.
We wanna have a little talk, is all.
Mr. Scagnetti, don't get close to her.
She'll kill you.
One way or the other,
she'll kill you.
Relax. Read my book, okay?
I've met women who were crocodiles,
but this little lady...
I think she's got
a sweet streak for me.
Here, y'all take that.
it's okay. Come on.
- Sir, we're not allowed.
- That's okay. Come on.
it's okay, guys.
Smoke?
I know you smoke.
I'm not here to hurt you, Mallory.
I want to be
your friend, okay?
if I ever met a girl
who needs a friend...
it's you.
You're a very pretty girl.
Remember the last time
you got fucked? Huh?
Remember?
What I want you to do
is close your eyes...
and remember the last time
ol' Mickey gave you the high hard one.
Thinking' about it?
Don't forget it,
'cause it's never gonna happen again.
When they get through with
all that electroshock shit
they got lined up
for that cocksucker,
ol' Mickey
ain't gonna be worth a shit.
- And was it really worth it?
- Was what worth it?
Was massacring all those people
worth being separated
from your love
for the rest of your life?
You mean, was an instant of my purity
worth a lifetime of your lies?
Please explain, where is the purity
that you couldn't live without
in the 52 people
who are no longer on this planet,
because they met you and Mallory!?
What's so pure about that?
How do you do it?
You'll never understand. You and me,
we're not even the same species.
I used to be you,
then I evolved.
From where you're standing,
you're a man.
From where I'm standing,
you're an ape.
You're not even an ape,
you're a media person.
Media's like the weather,
only its man made weather.
Murder? it's pure.
You're the one
that made it impure.
You're buyin' and sellin' fear.
You say, "why?"
I say, "why bother?"
Are you done? Great.
Now let's cut the b.s. and get real.
Why this purity that you feel
about killing?
Why, for Christ sake, why?
Don't lie to me!
I guess, Wayne, you gotta hold
that ol' shotgun in your hand...
and it becomes clear,
like it did for me the first time.
That's when I realized
my one true calling in life.
And what's that, Mickey?
Shit, man...
I'm a natural born killer.
Julie:
And...commercial. Two minutes, guys.
Did you get that?
inmate:
All right, Mickey!
Great. Great, man.
Hello, Wurlitzer here.
Guard:
We got a riot in B wing.
Oh, shit.
Thanks.
Every fuckin' moron
in the world just saw that, mate.
Leroy: Warden, we got a riot
going on and it's out of control.
- We need help.
- God Almighty, shitfire! Where at?
in the rec room, B wing.
We're outmanned already.
We need help.
All right. You mobilize the men,
I'm on my way.
Mr. Gale, close them cameras down.
We got a riot in B wing.
Just a sec, we have to finish.
We're live-!
You sure as hell are finished!
They got guns, hostages, explosives.
Close that camera down, now!
Turn 'em off!
We'll never get this chance again!
We'll be famous!
You stay here and shut up.
I gotta find out what's going on
before I can let you
film anywhere.
The whole world is watching!
We'll never get this chance again!
This asshole is trying to tell me
what I'm gonna do in my jail!
Fuck him! This fuck don't know
what he's dealing with,
but we do. Keep your fingers
on the triggers of your shotguns,
and follow me.
This is a tough room.
All right, one more.
Mother says to Sister,
"You can go out with Bobby,
but you got to take little Johnny."
Sister goes, "Okay."
So they go, they come back,
Mother grabs little Johnny aside,
says, "All right, now...
what happened?"
Little Johnny can't talk.
Mother says,
"They went to the drive-in,
I know that, what happened then?"
Little Johnny goes...
"Oh, they were kissing'!
What else?"
You heard this one?
"What else?"
Little Johnny goes...
"He felt her up?
Well..."
Little Johnny goes...
"They took off their clothes?"
"Well, what else?"
Little Johnny goes...
"They did that?
What the hell were you doin'?"
Little Johnny goes...
"Little Johnny, no!"
Oh...shit!
Drop it!
The gun, goddamn it!
Smart move.
Okay, empty the shells.
Hurry it up!
Everybody, raise your hands!
You think you're gettin'
out of here, boy?
They're gonna mop you up.
They're gonna put you in a bucket.
Kavanaugh, you're the law.
I'm the law breaker.
Oh, you motherfucker!
Wayne, where are you?
Hey, I'm all right, man.
I'm okay, I'm okay.
All right, new friend.
Get your camera.
Where's Roger?
I'm right here.
- Where's Scotty?
- He's hit. I think he's dead.
Aw, shit.
Put the shells on the table!
Drop your belt!
Hands behind your head!
- Got that camera going yet?
- They're both shot to shit.
- Well, that's too bad for you-
- N-no, wait!
I got a shoulder pack
with remote Beta on it.
- I can get an image off of that.
- Very innovative.
Put it on your shoulder.
Let's go.
We're gonna play "Follow the Leader'.
Everybody follow me out.
One big, happy family.
Shooting everything I do.
Kavanaugh, get up!
Take me to Mallory's cell,
and you hope she's in one place.
Everybody, get behind Kavanaugh.
Press up against his back.
Let's go! Young lady,
you want to come along with us?
Come on, darlin', get up.
Go, go, go! Come on.
You got the keys?
Come on, hustle it!
Stay with me!
Come on, assholes!
That's my camera,
you motherfucker!
Come on, stick together!
Oh, now I remember you.
You're Jack.
I'm not really as bad
as they say I am.
I'm actually a really nice person.
Yeah, I know.
I've done some pretty
bad things myself.
I killed somebody.
No shit.
Anyway...
You know what I think about?
Sex.
Fuckin'.
I think about hands on my tits.
And I think about flesh...
flesh...
and sweat.
My mind drives me crazy.
Sit down.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to kiss me
and squeeze my nipple.
Oh, you're so specific.
Squeeze it-
You like a little bit of pain?
Harder...ow!
How sexy am I now, fucker?
You stupid dick!
Aw, shit! Shit!
Carl, what happened?
Jack:
You whore!
Mallory:
You want a sexy little whore?!
I'm trying, I'm trying!
Fucking bitch broke my fucking nose!
Give me that gun!
I'll kill you!
I'll fuckin' kill you!
- Whoa! No gun! Put it away!
- Give me your fucking mace!
You fucking whore!
So, you wanna play, bitch?
You want some? How about this?
Get down!
I told you I liked you!
And now, a special report
from Channel Six News.
We're on the air...!
Are we on?
Good afternoon, I'm Antonia Chavez...
this is a WATCH special report.
I'm being told that we're taking
you live to Batongo Penitentiary,
where Wayne Gale continues
his interrupted interview
in the middle of a full scale riot.
Wayne, can you hear me?
Wayne, tell us what's happening.
Are you safe?
This is Wayne Gale,
resuming live from Batongovllle,
where you can tell by the blood
and carnage around me,
that the final chapter
in the book...
called, "Mickey and Mallory",
has yet to be written!
Are you in danger, Wayne?
Can you tell us, are you in danger?
War has broken out here
unlike anything I've ever seen!
Batongo will stand alongside-
Antonia:
What's happening, Wayne?
Batongo...Batongo...
Batongo, Batongo!
in Batongovllle!
I thought you liked me!
Hey, Jack...
Mickey's back!
Jack:
Drop the shotgun!
Looks like we got us
a Mexican standoff.
We've had this date
from the beginning, huh, Mickey?
Now, slide that shotgun over here.
Put your hands behind your head
and your forehead on the floor!
Or-what? You'll wound me?
I could blow you in half,
and you know it.
I never wounded anything in my life!
I got you locked
right between the eyes, Mickey!
I've had you locked
from the jump, you phony!
You got me locked,
you take your shot.
Okay, Jack. You win.
Oh, baby!
Wayne:
Ladles and gentlemen, this kiss...
...has been a year in the coming.
They're doing something everyone said
they would never do again.
At this moment, they are
the only two people on earth.
Wayne:
Shut up, Jack!
You're losing your touch, Jack.
I was out of shells.
You still like me now, Jack?
Die!
- What's this?
- The list of prisoners!
What the fuck do I want that for?
I asked for a list of hostages!
Hostages?
How am I supposed to know?
Just get it.
Do I have to do everything?
I'm working on it!
All right...Jesus Christ.
What are those guys right there?
Track it, track it!
Close one, two, three again.
- Still jammed open, sir.
- Well, jam 'em shut!
- There's a fire at Five Six North.
- I can see the goddamn fire!
The psych unit looks like a zoo,
informants are being tortured-
TV:
Hey Mabel, come here. Look at this.
Warden!
- Yes, what is it, Natapundi?
- Napalatoni.
I don't care
what your fuckin' name is!
Mickey and Mallory Knox are loose.
Scagnetti's dead!
And-we're live
on network TV.
Live on network TV?!
Jesus Harold Christ
on a fucking rubber crutch!
Is this happening to me?!
You fucking sick motherfuckers!
Come on.
Yeah, come on.
Man:
Come on.
Come on, Mickey.
This way.
Mickey:
Who are you?
My name's Owen.
What the hell
do you want from us?
I want you
to take me with you.
Where the hell are we?
it's a place I come to think
when things get hectic.
Follow me.
Let's go, Kavanaugh.
Owen:
Follow me.
Now we're in B wing.
Where we goin,' Owen?
Out...through...
down.
Hold up!
Okay, Kavanaugh...
Don't shoot!
Motherfuckers!
How you doin', Wayne?
I'm fuckin' great!
You got the feelin'?
I'm alive for the
first fuckin' time in my life.
Thanks to Mickey!
Let's kill all these motherfuckers!
- Gimme that.
- Why?
You're not centered, Wayne.
Here, shoot with this.
Okay, let's go.
Kavanaugh, stop slackin' off.
End of the line, Knox.
Drop 'em.
One move, and he's dead!
He's already dead, dickweed!
You got shit!
Fire!
Back off!
I'll blast him!
Shut up, Gale, you prick!
Mickey, Mallory,
just let me say-
Put your hand up!
You see?
Now shut up!
Mickey, I made a place.
Come, come!
Let's go, Mal!
60 seconds,
and I'm coming up!
Mickey:
Think, think, think...
Fuck.
Yes...?
Hello, Margaret.
How you doin', Mal?
I'm all right.
You done good, baby.
Thank you.
I want you to know...
no matter what happens,
I love you.
I love you more
than I ever loved myself.
I know that, Mickey.
I'm never comin' home.
Don't you get it?
I'm alive,
for the first fucking time
in my life, I'm alive!
Because I don't love you anymore.
I love Ming.
That's right, Ming is not
a fucking restaurant!
I don't care, take the money!
it's all yours, anyway!
And one more thing,
piss off, you cunt!
it's good to be with you, Wayne.
You do a lot of good for people.
The fuckin' jail is exposed,
and you're dealing with these two...
when we've got
more important things to do!
These two-these are the ones,
they die today, you hear me, Sparky?
I'm gonna wipe that scum
off the face of the fucking earth,
if it's the last
fucking thing I do!
You know what I say?
I say, to hell
with going back to our cells.
Let's go out there,
and run down the stairs,
and go out in a hall of bullets.
And then we'll die,
and then we'll really be free.
That's poetry.
But we'll do that
when all else falls.
I just left her.
That's right.
Put a bottle of Dom on ice,
and get some Ecstasy,
I'm gonna come over tonight,
and put a hot pepper up your arse...
Ming:
No, you're not.
I love you, Ming...Ming...?
Ming!
Duncan-Duncan,
hold this.
Are you married?
I don't wanna die,
I don't wanna die-
That wasn't the question.
Are you married?
Yes, I'm married.
- Do you have children?
- I have a boy...and a girl-
- I don't wanna die...
- Mal, could you come here, please?
The only way we're gonna get
out that front door,
is if they don't wanna kill
you two more than they wanna kill us.
Respected Journalist!
Hold that.
Duncan-Duncan Homolka,
Wayne Gale.
You wanted reality?
You got it.
My name is Wayne Gale!
I am the star of "American Maniacs",
watched by 40 million
people a week!
I am a respected journalist,
winner of the Murrow
and the Golden Globe Award,
to name a few!
I have been shot,
you are on camera!
We are live. if anybody tries
to fuck up our escape,
I will make it my life's mission,
to put Dwight McClusky
out of commission!
I will do expose after expose,
revealing the inhumanity,
the brutality of the conditions
that exist here.
You! Back up, back up!
My name is Wayne Gale! I am the star
of "American Maniacs"-!
You're all on camera!
We are live!
Just how far do you think
you're gonna get?
Mickey:
Rlght out the front door.
That will never happen.
it is happening.
My name is Wayne Gale!
I am a friend of Bill Clinton's!
if anybody puts me in danger-
You open that gate!
My name is Wayne Gale-!
I will personally hunt you down...
blow the head
off your fucking whore wife...
and plant your sick ass
into the ground all by myself!
Another day, perhaps,
but not today.
This is Wayne Gale,
unfortunately no longer live.
I am wounded,
all my crew is dead.
I have left my wife,
and my girlfriend has left me.
Mallory:
Look back up, that was good!
Mickey Knox's plan worked;
we walked out the front...
into my news van
and made our getaway.
When we were followed
by patrol cars,
Mallory shot Deputy Sheriff
Duncan Homolka,
and tossed his body out the back.
Mickey:
Show 'em your ear.
Aghh!
Oh, my God,
that is so gross!
Why helicopters were not deployed,
I don't know.
My only thought is, it all happened
too fast for arrangements to be made.
- Wayne?
- We've pulled up alongside the road...
to do this interview.
Tensions run high as we-
We ain't got all fuckin' day.
So without any further ado,
Mickey and Mallory.
So, Mallory, after Mickey's incredible
rescue, what did you think next?
I was just wondering'
how long it would be...
until me and Mickey
could be alone together,
and if I could wait that long.
So...did you have anything
to do with the riot?
We didn't have nothin' to do
with that riot.
That was...
whatchamacallem...?
- Faked?
- Faked.
They wanna say we masterminded
the whole fuckin' thing.
Let 'em. it's not like
it's gonna keep us up at night.
But the truth is, it was...
fate.
Ah, yes. Faked it was.
And you saw it right here,
on "American Maniacs".
You believe in reincarnation, Wayne?
Yes, I believe we've all
lived many times.
So, what's next for the Knoxes?
Well, I'm thinkin' we can lay
in a big king-size bed,
and sleep for about two days,
and I've been thinkin'
about motherhood.
So, I think me and Mickey
are gonna get started on that,
as quickly as possible.
Gotta go.
How do you two
intend to disappear?
You're probably the most
famous couple in America.
There is that underground railroad-
Okay, end of the interview.
Let me just
swing the camera around,
and do my wrap up,
and we're off.
Oh, we're gonna do
a little wrap up all right, Wayne.
But it won't be you in the camera,
lookin' dumb and actln' stupid.
instead, you're gonna be starin'
down the barrels of our shotguns,
and we're blowin' your brains
all over that tree back there.
Wait, wait! Time!
Cut, cut, cut!
That's a fuckin' joke, right?
I thought during
this whole escape thing...
a bond had built between us.
No, not really.
You're scum, Wayne.
You did it for ratings.
You don't give a shit about us,
or about anybody
except yourself.
That's why nobody
gave a shit about you,
that's why-
"helicopters were not deployed".
Wait a minute, you fuckin' hypocrite.
What about the indian?
You said you were done with killing,
you said, "Love beats the demon."
You said that love beats the demon!
I am, and it will.
it's just that you're
the last one, Wayne.
Don't fuckin' kill me.
This is not about you,
you egomaniac. I kinda like you.
But if we let you go,
we'd be just like everybody else.
Killin' you,
and what you represent, is...
a statement.
I'm not 100% sure
exactly what it's sayin',
but Frankenstein
killed Dr. Frankenstein...
Mickey:
Wayne...?
Have some dignity.
All right, so I'm a parasite.
So what?
Life is cruel, no one said
it was gonna be easy.
But don't you two kill!
You belong to us!
To the public,
to the media!
That's how it is,
and we are married, mate!
And the point is,
what do we do next?
I say, we do
a Salman Rushdie-type thing.
Books, talk shows...
we lay low, we jump up,
we bob and weave,
we do Oprah,
we do Donahue,
do you have any idea
how huge we could be?
Let's make a little music, Colorado.
Wait, wait, wait!
Don't Mickey and Mallory leave
somebody alive to tell the tale?
We are...
Your camera.
Okay.
I'm gonna miss him.
- Come on, let's go.
- Okay, baby.
Antonia:
Can we hear him?
I can't hear him.
I'm not getting anything off this.
Oh, my God.
in other news, a wedding reception
turned into a nightmare...
...My dad.
People...
...because it would end in sex.
That's all I thought about.
He punched me,
he slapped me again,
I just wanna say...
you know, can we-