Hello.
Hello, sweetie.
Daddy.
It's early.
Yeah, I know.
I just wanted to let you know
I'm sending you something.
Mmm. Does it smell nice?
No,
but it's sparkly.
Does it have a receipt?
I'm sending it
to you from the store.
Why don't you just come by?
We'll have some breakfast, hmm?
Well, it'd be a long trip.
I'm in Venice.
With your parole officer's
approval, of course.
Well, I like the guy, Stella,
you know that,
but we never really connected.
So I think I've paid
my P.O. his last visit.
What are you into, Dad?
Don't break my heart.
You told me you were through.
After this I am, I swear to you.
Is Charlie there?
I'm on a cell phone, darling.
I'll call you tomorrow
from a land line.
I love you.
Go back to sleep. Bye.
D... Dad?
I love you, too.
I sent it.
You're supposed
to do your shopping
after we pull off the job.
I feel so optimistic.
So?
How do you feel?
I'm fine.
Fine?
You know what "fine"
stands for, don't you?
Yeah, unfortunately.
"Freaked out."
- "Insecure."
- "Neurotic."
- And "Emotional."
- Good.
See those columns behind you?
What about them?
That's where they used
to string up thieves
who felt "fine."
Well... after you.
For after the haul.
Hope I get to fire it up.
Still no word
from the garbagemen?
No.
If they're no-shows,
three months of prep
down the tubes
and I dragged you out
of retirement for nothing.
Oh, this is fun.
I like this.
You've taken over the reins,
all the worries.
Me loosey-goosey,
just along for the ride.
I'm glad you're
enjoying yourself, John.
Just remember, a police boat
can get from the station
to our position in seven.
That means you got
four minutes to work your magic.
Now, you told me ten,
and you said I would have five.
When?
Do not be messing
with me right now, okay?
- I will kick your ass.
- Oh, yeah?
Come on, take your best shot.
Come on.
What? Uh-oh.
Let's go.
What is it this time?
Da Vinci. Architect.
Engineer. Painter.
Yeah, fascinating.
Hey, look, look. Check this out.
"Learn the language of poetry,
art, romance, sex."
Unlike you, my friend,
I don't need a guidebook.
Can we go? Please?
Right, guv'nor.
Come along,
make yourself useful.
Untie that line.
Today.
Yeah.
Yeah, Gilligan.
If you don't mind.
- We set?
- Yeah. I've enhanced
the viewing matrix to track both
the Cartesian coordinates
and three altitude angles,
the yaw, pitch and roll
to give us
the exact position and
orientation of our baby.
We're in Italy.
Speak English.
Steve, how we looking?
Papa took the boat to work at
8:15, so the garage is empty.
Mama left with daughter
at 8:30 for preschool as usual.
So for the next 45 minutes,
we own this place, gentlemen.
Still no word
from the garbagemen?
Hey, who got you
the beekeepers in Budapest?
They'll be there.
You can trust these guys.
Steve, how many times
do I have to tell you?
I trust everyone... I just don't
trust the devil inside them.
We're in.
Just tell me where to paint.
Your men are still not
in position?
They will be.
Well, you don't know that,
Steve. We should abort.
I'm sorry, John, but I think
that's Charlie's call now.
Our baby's being taken
out of here tonight.
This is our only shot at it.
Charlie?
Keep going?
It's up to you, kid.
It's a go.
Okay, Steve.
From the west wall,
measure 14 feet, eight inches.
Got it.
Now measure
eight feet, five inches
from the north wall.
That's the northwest corner
of our baby.
Got it.
Well, it's right above you.
Now, paint.
Two feet, nine inches wide.
Two feet, five inches deep.
Okay, Left Ear.
You're up.
14 feet four inches
from that west wall.
Yeah.
Bene.
The garbagemen
are in position, John.
All right, Charlie,
someone just called it in.
The police boat's
heading your way.
Seven minutes and counting.
Let's go.
We got four minutes
to load and leave. Let's go.
Whoa! Whoa!
Hey, you guys. Come here.
I want to propose a toast.
To us.
Yay!
And I want to propose
a toast to Charlie
because we just stole
$35 million worth of gold
without even holding a gun
because he planned this
down to a "T."
Nobody else
could have done that.
Nobody. Charlie!
- Charlie!
- Yay!
Thank you.
So, come on, gentlemen.
Shopping list.
Who's doing what?
Spare no dirty details.
Come on, you guys.
Take a lesson from an old man.
Don't spend it.
Invest.
In what?
In gold.
Let's figure out
how to get out of here first,
all right?
What are you getting, Rob?
I don't know...
there's a lot of things
you can buy with a lot of money.
You know, I'm just thinking
about naked girls
in leather seats.
Obviously. See?
Suppose I get
the Aston Martin Vanquish?
There's not a lot
a girl won't do
on the passenger seat
of one of those things.
I'm going to get a NAD T770
digital decoder with a 70-watt
amp and Burr Brown DACs.
Yeah.
It's a big stereo.
Speakers so loud they blow
women's clothes off.
Now you're talking.
$35 million... you can't get
more creative than that, man?
I'm going to Andalucia,
south of Spain...
right there.
Get me a big house...
get me a library
full of first editions.
Get a room for my shoes.
What about you, Steve?
I don't know...
I haven't decided yet.
You haven't decided yet?
Come on, man,
is it the mountain air, just...?
I liked what you said.
I'll take one of each of yours.
Well, well, two of everything
- For Steve then.
- Two of those.
Oy!
Loved the toast.
But you could've pulled this off
with your eyes closed.
No, you were incredible.
Just incredible.
You saw the whole picture.
You covered all the angles.
You know, Charlie,
there are two kinds of thieves
in this world:
the ones who steal
to enrich their lives,
and the ones who steal
to define their lives.
Don't be the latter.
Makes you miss out
on what's really important
in this life.
What are you talking about,
John?
You've been a good father.
Sitting in prisons
doesn't make you a good father.
I spent half my kid's life
in prison.
Don't get to be my age
with nothing but this, Charlie.
Find somebody you want to spend
the rest of your life with
and hold onto her forever.
- Okay?
- Hey.
Let's go...
I'm freezing my ass off.
Yeah.
Steve's getting cold.
You, too?
I'm all right.
I love you, kid.
You did really great.
Thanks, John.
Let's go.
Money
It's a gas
Grab that cash with both hands
and make a stash
New car, caviar,
four-star daydream...
You should've seen Rob
behind the wheel of that boat.
He was like Don Johnson.
Oy, yeah, from Brixton.
Yeah, what the hell do you know
about Brixton, eh?
Look at this idiot
right in the middle of the road.
What's this, what's this?
Who the hell are these guys?
Hey!
Take your hands off the wheel.
Steve!
Don't even think about it...
just do it.
No, no, no, no,
- No, no, no, no, John.
- Steve,
what the hell are you doing?
Made a few plans of my own.
There's nowhere you can go
where we won't find you, Steve.
You know that.
I think that's probably right,
John.
Go! Go!
Charlie.
We got to go, Charlie.
You always work in the dark?
Makes me feel like I'm alone.
Not bad.
Not bad, Stella.
Damn. Hurley couldn't
crack that safe.
Neither could Spears.
Now you know
who to call first.
You're expensive, Stella.
Those guys cut us a break
on subpoena jobs.
Good will, community service.
I do it for the money, Paul.
I'll be sending you a bill.
Don't you want to see
what's inside?
I never look inside.
Have a good day.
Hey, George.
Hi, Stella.
I came, I saw, I kicked some ass
The pain I cause,
it makes me laugh
'Cause the way I do my thing
is strange
Time, time for this girl
to sing
Damn if I thought
that you would change
And my life would stay
the same
Things will come
and things will go
And one thing I know
for sure
Is that the wreckoning,
the wreckoning, the wreckoning
I'm walking out the door
Wreckoning, the wreckoning,
the wreckoning
Oh, it's time...
How long to crack it?
Four minutes and 43 seconds.
Oh! You're the man.
What's on the lineup?
Todd Milliken called.
He has a prototype
combination lock.
He wants you to test out.
He says he added
two false contact points
on the tumbler.
I'll pretend to be stumped
for a couple of seconds,
give him a thrill.
And, there's a Charlie Croker
in your office.
Says you two know each other.
Charlie Croker.
Hey, Stella.
Didn't I tell you I never
want to see you again?
I think it was when you told me
how my father died,
right in front of your eyes,
after you pulled him
in for one last job.
We found him, Stella.
He's in Los Angeles.
The gold bricks he stole from us
had a Balinese dancer
stamped on them.
I just got word,
from a contact of mine
called Skinny Pete,
that a gold dealer out in L.A.
has been buying those bricks.
Yeah?
Well, how do you know it's him?
Skinny Pete sent me this.
Steve changed his last
name to Frazelli.
Why you telling me
all of this?
Been checking out the databases
behind safe companies.
Found out Steve
had a Worthington 1000
delivered to his home office.
You don't install
a Worthington 1000
unless you've got something
really big to guard.
No, you don't.
The problem now is no one
in my crew
can handle Steve's safe.
And I need somebody
I can trust.
Look, I'm a professional
safe and vault technician.
I'm not a thief.
Hey, it's not about the gold,
Stella, okay?
John was like a father
to me, too.
Look, I'm sorry, all right?
I just can't move on until
I've set things right.
I've moved on.
Come on, Charlie.
Come on.
Hello?
I want to see the look
on that man's face
when his gold is gone.
He took my father from me;
I'm taking this.
She's in.
That's a good thing?
It's a very good thing.
She can crack a Worthington 1000
without even flinching.
I'm not sure having
a civilian on the crew's
a good idea, Charlie.
She's got the skill
and she's got the motivation.
Exactly.
She's emotional.
You know what happens
when emotion gets into it.
Look, don't kid yourself,
all right?
We're all emotional on this one.
Let's go.
Are you ready?
Of course I am.
You're not ready.
That was quick.
Where are they?
We're a little early.
I didn't expect us to get here
quite that fast.
There.
That's Lyle.
He's my computer genius.
You know, he's who really
invented Napster.
At least that's how
Lyle tells it.
Said Shawn Fanning
was his roommate in college
and stole his idea.
Think it's his first time
riding that bike, though.
Hey.
Oh...
You okay?
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
That's Left Ear.
Demolition and explosives.
When he was ten,
he put one too many M-80s
in the toilet bowl.
Fire...
Whoa.
Yeah, that was cool.
How'd you do that?
What?!
I said,
how did you do that?
What?!
Lost the hearing
in his right ear.
He's been blowing
stuff up ever since.
Handsome Rob.
Premier wheel man.
Once drove all the way
from Los Angeles
just so he could set the record
for longest freeway chase.
- You're a heartbreaker...
- You know, he got 110
Iove letters
sent to his jail cell
from women
who saw him on the news?
You're a heartbreaker
Dream-maker
Love-taker
Don't you mess around,
no, no, no...
And you?
I never heard
how you got your start.
Me?
Well, I've been a thief
since I had baby teeth.
Okay, you both know what to do.
Cough it up, now!
Come on, now,
shake it, shake it, baby, ho!
One, two, three, baby...
Watch it, spaz!
Hey, now, do, re, me, baby...
Hey, what's your problem, man?
A-B-C, it's easy
As one, two, three...
Hey, Charlie.
Good to see you, man.
- Looking good.
- Yeah?
- Charlie Hustle.
- Good to see you.
Hello, Charlie.
Rob, what's up?
Good?
Guys...
Stella Bridger.
Hi.
How you doing?
Nice to meet you.
Phones?
Yeah, they're all
fresh and clean,
I got internal chips in them.
Please change them twice a day.
We will get heat on line.
I.D. s?
"James Hymen?"
Come on, man, one time,
give me a cool name.
140 pounds? Try 165.
Try lifting some weights.
- Try lifting up these.
- Guys, enough.
Come on, we leave
tomorrow, all right?
Let's go.
Hey, Charlie...
Handsome, can you help
him with the bike?
Yeah, help Knievel set up
for his next jump.
Like a sound you hear
that lingers in your ear
But you can't forget,
from sundown to sunset
No, no
It puts a brand-new kind
of thinkin' in your mind
And you can't go wrong
'Cause you're groovin'
all day long, ha-ha!
California soul
Ooh-ooh-ooh
California soul...
Man, out of all of the places
for a thief to hide,
this joker picked Hollywood.
He's a punk,
but he ain't stupid.
All right...
we need to figure out a way
to get in Steve's house
and make a video blueprint
of the interior.
I want audio surveillance
on his phone.
Oh, yeah, I been wanting
to try something.
I crack into the phone company's
remote monitoring system,
and fool it into thinking
there's a legal tap on the line.
Just reroute the digital copies
of the calls to our own
listening post.
I been doing it
to my ex for years.
How long?
No... how long will it take?
Not how long have you
been doing it to your ex.
I'll burn through the night;
I'll have it running by morning.
Sorry I'm late.
We got to work on getting
Steve out of the house.
Stella, how much time you need
with the Worthington?
Five minutes flat.
Don't be cocky, young lady.
It's not the same as opening
a safe for the police.
The perspiration
on your fingertips,
your heart's pounding
in your ears...
whole different ball game.
I appreciate your concern.
I'll be fine.
Look, just remember,
this is all the easy part, okay?
It's the getaway
that can get us caught.
So what's the sketch?
We drive to Union Station.
Getaway car goes
right onto the train with us.
We need to know exactly
how long it's going to take
to get from Steve's house
to Union Station.
Oh, great.
Carson Security System.
How good is it?
Carson's held
an annual contest...
$50,000 to anybody
that can bypass the system.
The Who's Who of ex-cons
always show up.
Five years running,
no one's been paid.
Okay, party people,
here's the status.
It's an anti-scaling fence.
It's hardened,
electro-plated steel.
Yeah, I'm going
to have to paint that up
with some nitromin.
Security on the property?
Got an armed guard here.
Little rent-a-cop,
with a nine-millimeter
on his hip.
But that booth...
Security booth looks prime
for a chemical grenade.
Nitromin, chemical grenades...
I mean, that stuff's
pretty hard to come by.
Yeah, Lyle, it's a bear market.
Shit.
This dude got dogs.
I don't do dogs.
I had a...
real bad experience, man.
What happened?
I had a bad experience.
Damn it. I'm deaf.
You turn in your badge
and your weap...
Oh, shoot.
Turn in your badge
and your weapon!
Crush.
I don't want to see you
anywhere near
this investigation.
And turn in
your badge and your weapon.
I don't want to see you
anywhere near
this investigation.
Hey! It's a green!
Turn in your badge
and your weapon.
- Green!
- I don't want to see you
anywhere near this...
Turn in your badge
and your weapon.
Unbelievable.
There he is.
Let's get to work.
It's either bad traffic,
peak traffic,
slit-your-wrist traffic.
You know, five people died
from smoking
in between traffic lights today.
You know, they do have
the Metrorail, Rob.
You could always use that.
That'd be ideal
for carrying a ton of gold,
wouldn't it, genius?
What's your guesstimate?
The last 20 times
I've done the journey,
you've got an average of 32
minutes and a top time of 50,
but if we had green
lights all the way,
we could do it in 14 minutes.
Wait, you couldn't get
through traffic?
Whoa.
We could do anything
with green lights all the way.
Lyle?
I'll see what I can do.
You're right on time.
All these poor bastards
out there,
putting their life
savings in banks,
and S&Ls, and mutual funds.
How do they think,
when the collapse comes,
they can depend
on the government?
I don't think so.
Are you taping me?
Of course not.
I never tape you...
come look,
see for yourself.
Governments are nothing more
than puppets and strings
in a world where NAFTA
can overrule the Supreme Court.
Like my cousin Mashkov
always says: "This
is our only refuge, baby...
gold."
Every time I look
at these engravings...
She's so beautiful.
Where'd you say you got these?
I didn't.
A little walking around money.
I guess I'm not walking
as far as I thought.
I'm... sorry.
I can only buy two bricks
from you today.
- That wasn't the agreement.
- What can I say?
I'm just middleman.
I'll buy the other two
from you on Wednesday.
Don't waste my time, Yevhen.
So, what does a man
with 35 million dollars worth
of gold do at night?
He watches his big-ass TV.
That's our in.
Stella.
Jesus!
Charlie!
How did you get in here?
I knocked,
but you didn't answer.
What... so you just
let yourself in?
I was just making sure
you were okay.
I apologize. I just...
- I...
- Don't look.
Okay.
You got a lot of stuff here.
You know,
your dad was old school.
Did the whole thing by touch.
That worked for him;
this works for me.
Technology guarantees speed
and accuracy, you know?
Yeah, but there's no guarantees
in this business, Stella.
Why the headphones?
Just training myself.
Ambient noises, you know,
just in case.
What do you want, Charlie?
We're going to knock out
Steve's cable,
and we need to send in
a repairman.
To get your video blueprint
of the interior.
Yep.
Only problem is
Steve thinks we're all dead.
Except me.
I'll do it, Charlie.
I'm in all the way,
whatever it takes.
All right.
I'll set it up.
Okay.
Um... you, um...
maybe want to get a drink
downstairs with me
before I go back to my room?
I sh... I should finish
this stuff up, you know?
Just get it all done tonight.
Yeah.
Sorry I scared you.
It's okay.
|
Good night.
Bye.
And then he's just...
the media darling.
He's on the cover
of all the magazines.
I should've been on the cover
of Wired Magazine.
You know what he said?
He said he...
he named it Napster
because it-it was his nickname,
'cause of the nappy hair
under the hat,
but he... it's 'cause
I was napping
when he stole it from me!
He didn't even graduate.
I think it's time to move on,
don't you?
They shut him down.
I wish they'd
do the same to you.
Here... here we go.
Cable chick.
Becky.
Nice name... I wonder
what she calls
the other one.
And it's such a mystery
why you don't have
a girlfriend, Lyle.
So, all we need is a...
service truck like that one,
a work shirt like hers.
You think Stella
can pull it off?
I have my doubts.
There's no talking
to Charlie, though.
You think he's...
mixing business with pleasure?
He should know better.
Only I'm allowed to do that.
Right. Where you going?
To get a work shirt
and a service truck.
Are you kidding me?
How does he do that?
How do you do that?
What are you saying?
Hey, how are you?
Oh, good. I'm good.
Nice to meet you,
I'm... Handsome Rob.
And you are...?
Oh, my name's...
my name's Becky,
but it's written on my shirt.
Listen, I'm going to need
your shirt... and your truck.
Perfect.
I'll give them both to you.
Would you... would you like
my virginity as well?
If it's on the menu.
Ha, ha, ha, ha,
oh, you're so witty.
Why don't you
take advantage of me?
Yeah, you're
not too bright, are you?
No.
Perfect.
What can I do for you,
Mr. Frazelli?
The cable's out.
The TV, the modem, everything.
Now, get somebody up here,
and tell them to hurry up.
Netcom Cable,
how can I help you?
Hi, I'm up at 3320 East Skyway,
and the cable's
just gone out...
our modem, everything.
Okay, um, let's see, sir.
I have a Thursday
between 9:00 and 3:00
if that would be good.
That's going to work. Thank you.
Guard just called
the cable company.
What time's the appointment?
Thursday between 9:00 and 3:00.
Hello?
Hi, I'm calling
from Netcom Cable.
I understand your service
is out,
and there was an appointment
set up for Thursday.
Yes.
Well, we have
a technician working
in your area who's finished
with an appointment
earlier than expected.
Will somebody be there
for the next hour?
Sure, that'd be great.
All right, our technician
will see you then.
Have a nice day.
Here's all the paperwork
you need.
Just get him to sign
and date at the bottom.
Let's check out the camera.
Stella,
you'll be going patriotic today.
Make sure you walk slowly,
or the image will streak.
- Ow.
- Ooh.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
Sorry... Couldn't pin
the corsage
on my prom date either.
But you had a prom date?
It was his cousin.
There's cable lines
in the kitchen,
living room, bedroom,
and the cable modem on
the computer in the office.
You need to locate
the safe in the office.
Okay.
Just want you to know
I think you're very
brave going in there.
I know it won't be easy.
I second that.
It's going to be fine.
What?
You know what fine stands for?
Freaked Out. Insecure...
Neurotic, and Emotional.
You'll be great.
Yeah.
Morning.
Can I see some I.D.?
Thanks for coming so soon.
Hey, that's part of the job.
All right.
Aston Martin Vanquish.
Looks like that bastard
took my car.
Nasty-ass dogs.
Hey! Hey!
Relax,
Jesus Christ.
Come on,
they won't bother you now.
Come on.
House.
Go on, get out of here.
It's okay,
I'm used to running into
all sorts of animals on my job.
Steve Frazelli.
Becky.
Want to show me that problem?
Yeah, of course.
This way.
You have a really nice house.
Yeah. 1922.
All the original tiles.
Every stone in that courtyard
hauled from some
monastery in Seville.
What a tactic.
Monastery?
Monastery for punk-ass creeps.
You don't seem impressed.
No, it's just that I don't think
lugging a bunch of rocks
from one place to another
is quite... that interesting.
You know, it doesn't quite
do it for me.
What does do it for you?
Um... TVs?
I have a monster TV.
Not working right now, but...
But you know, I should
probably check out
the cable modem, you know.
Yeah? Yeah, right.
Over here.
I paid 30 grand to some punk kid
to put this system in.
One day, it just goes out.
I ought to have him strung up.
Here we go.
There's our baby.
We got him.
Got any, uh, wiring
coming through here?
There's no wiring in here.
Just right here?
Yeah.
Look at that, that's my...
That's my NAD T770.
That's...
That's my stereo.
I bet most of your customers
are pretty surprised when
they go to open the door
for the cable man
and find you standing there.
Oh, yeah.
He's hitting on her.
There's no problem here.
I should maybe
just check the TVs.
Okay.
You know what,
end this shit right now.
I'm going to blow this shit
right off the mountain
right now.
No, no, no.
No, no, hey, hey, hey.
I see you got the AVM processor.
Only the best.
Check the box.
I'm just going to...
reset your system.
Sometimes these things just get
jammed up you know?
That should do it.
|
It's fixed?
Turn her on, let's see.
Now.
Japan's Nikkei index...
Perfect.
...was the ending price
and as you can see,
we've now gone below...
Becky, huh?
Have we met before?
...a loss of 1.1 percent
on the...
No, I don't think so.
If you can just sign there.
So, if I was to ask you
out to dinner...
would I be the first
one of your customers
to ever do that?
What, you asked your last cable
repair guy out for a date?
No, but the last one
was, like, 300 pounds,
had a handlebar mustache.
You know, not really my type.
I don't think it's a good idea.
Why, is that, like,
some, cable company rule?
No, actually, it's just my rule.
I don't go out
with strange men.
I just met you five minutes ago.
So, I guess I have to, like,
sabotage my cable, you know,
till we get to know each other
well enough.
Have a nice day.
Come on,
I'll be a perfect
gentleman, I promise.
I won't even ask you
for your phone number.
I'll just... I'll meet you.
Anywhere you want to go.
Come on, break your rule once.
It's just dinner.
Is that a yes?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
He touched my hand.
He came on to me.
Hey, at least I...
I created a window
of opportunity, right?
When he goes out Friday night,
we go in.
By the time he realizes
you've stood him up,
we'll be long gone
with that gold.
Yeah.
Make sure you shuffle
them cards this time, Left.
Hey, Lyle,
what's the distance between
the front door and the vault?
Don't deal
when my back's turned.
You've got that loser's
paranoia.
Lyle!
He only answers
to The Napster now, Charlie.
No.
I'm not calling you The Napster.
Why not, you call him Left Ear.
Well, I am.
And him, Handsome Rob.
Well, that's because
he is Handsome Rob.
Well, you can call me
The Napster.
Come on, they were at the
same college at the same time.
Why are you encouraging this?
It is a verifiable fact...
he was my roommate,
he stole my ideas.
I am The Napster.
All right, all right.
What is the distance
between the front door
and the vault, Napster?
It's farther
than you want to carry it.
Yeah, but, so,
how do we get the gold
from the vault
to the getaway car?
How wide is the hallway...
Napster?
Six feet.
Okay, you've got your gold.
Whoo!
We need more cars
to handle the weight.
Looks like I'm going to need
some help
with the custom work, too.
I know a man for the job.
So I modified the camera
to include the...
so we can create really
hi-res digital maps.
Who's that?
Rob's mechanic friend.
- Hey, Charlie.
- Hey.
Charlie, this is Wrench.
Hey, what's up, man?
Rob tells me you
got real talent.
We need some body work done.
Need to pack up to 2,700 pounds
of cargo in these Minis
with enough suspension
and horsepower
to outrun anything chasing us.
2,700 pounds of what?
Of whatever.
So, what do I get out
of this mystery deal, man?
10,000.
All right.
What comes around...
Oh, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey.
We didn't get a chance
to meet yet.
Wrench.
Ham and cheese.
Oh. Oh, that's cold.
Damn, that's cold. Mmm.
What comes around
Just comes around
What comes around...
You want all greens?
'Cause, ah, 'cause you got them.
What have you got?
Welcome to L.A. 's
Automated Traffic Surveillance
and Control Operations Center.
See, they use video feeds
from intersections
and specifically designed
algorithms
to predict traffic conditions,
and thereby control
traffic lights, so
all I did was come up
with my own
kick-ass algorithm to sneak in,
and now we own the place.
You want to do a dry run?
I thought you'd never ask.
See, red light?
Green light.
- Danielson?
- Yeah?
What's up with Grid 34?
Let's check it out.
Hey, hey.
Oh, oops, did I...?
Oops, wow, but it's awesome.
Is that not awesome?
- Can you change it back now?
- Yeah.
Lights are working fine.
Just an accident.
That's good.
What are those?
Unnecessary engine parts.
I lost your smog controls,
and 200 pounds of body fat.
You got yourself
a sweet ride now, Charlie.
Put the pedal to the metal
and I'm off
And never getting lost
Which way will I turn
when roads cross?
Press the petal to the metal,
little more when it's scary
But one thing for sure,
keep my foot on the floor
Put the pedal to the metal
and I'm off
And never getting lost
Which way will I turn
when roads cross?
Press the petal to the metal,
little more when it's scary
But one thing for sure,
keep my foot on the floor
Won't stop driving
till it's over
Still be cruising
when the sun goes down
Won't stop driving
till it's over
Put the pedal to the metal
and I'm off
And never getting lost
Which way will I turn
when roads cross?
Press the petal to the metal,
little more when it's scary
But one thing for sure,
keep my foot on the floor...
You know what
I'm thinking about right now?
The look on Steve's face.
You're early.
I'm in a hurry.
Of course, you know
that the Florida
vote rigging was a CIA
and mob operation.
Is that so?
Yeah, which is not
so very different
from when your John F. Kennedy
won a rigged election
with the help of his father.
You're uncomfortable
that I mentioned it.
No, Yevhen, I don't like
making two trips.
You Americans.
You love your heroes.
A holiday for Columbus?
He makes the wrong turn,
and wipes out an entire
indigenous people.
And you know
what he was looking for?
I bet you're going to tell me.
Gold.
Supposedly for Queen Isabella,
but don't think that
the Medicis back in Italy
didn't want a part
of that action.
And what did Italy
need gold for?
For the long-distance
slave trade based in Venice.
Venice...
that's where
these bricks...
You were saying something?
Nothing... No...
No, you were really
on a roll there.
Don't stop. I'm interested.
Please, I'm confused,
my English...
You understand fine.
Now what do you know
about my gold?
No, I don't...
Don't you even think
about lying to me.
Okay,
okay, l, I heard a rumor
about a heist in Venice.
35 million in bricks,
with an imprint
of a Balinese dancer on them.
- Who have you told?
- No one.
Who have you told?
No one!
I swear to God!
You swear to God?
You crazy?
I swear to God.
I didn't!
Well, then I guess
I believe you.
Yevhen?
Let's putt it this time...
Putt, not drive.
Very good.
If you can just get it,
I know you can,
I know you can do it.
Much better.
I'm here to see Skinny Pete.
Yeah, he's over there.
Thanks, man.
- Don't stare.
- Huh?
Don't stare.
He doesn't like
when people stare at him.
Stare at what?
That was good.
Try that one, I know
you're going to get that one.
That was great.
- Skinny Pete.
- Yo, Charlie.
What's up, man?
How's it going?
So was I right
about the gold bricks or what?
Oh, I'm not here to talk
about that. We need, uh...
some supplies.
Baby, go relax.
Baby...
Go relax.
Yo.
Supplies.
What's wrong?
Huh?
Uh... um, some, uh,
some nitromin,
uh...
some, uh...
some nitromin, primer...
- What's wrong?
- Huh?
Yo.
Uh, nothing.
I'm-I'm cool. I'm-I'm great.
Uh, I just need some,
uh, big can of...
Nitromin, primer,
- Detonating cord...
- Right, right.
...two triple-charged chemical
grenades and a launcher.
Right, like I had, uh,
you know, told you... earlier.
All right.
Cost you about five G's.
Done. Call me.
Thanks, man.
I'm sorry about that.
Uh-Uh, all right, man.
- Peace.
- Come on.
Get out.
There.
Vance has something
to tell you.
Go on.
A couple weeks back...
I was working counter
at your cousin's shop.
A guy come in asking
about gold bricks with Balinese
dancer on them.
What did you tell him?
I told him
that I'd seen some bricks.
I'm sorry.
What did this man look like?
He had, uh...
long black hair,
big tattoo on his neck.
He must have weighed
at least 400 pounds.
I know that guy.
Baby, go relax.
Do you know who I am?
You're Mashkov.
That's right.
You were asking
about gold bricks
with a Balinese dancer
on them.
Tell me why.
Steve just called to confirm
his 8:00 reservation
at the Water Grill.
Okay, let's go over it
one more time.
Gas the guards,
doors open 8:15.
Safe popped by 8:25.
Loaded by 8:35,
out the door by 8:45.
Straight to Union Station.
Only green lights on your route.
The rest of the city's red.
Cops are stuck in the traffic,
like everyone else.
Train leaves at 10:00.
Cars have to be
on the carrier by 9:30.
Timing's got to be dead on.
Let's get ready.
Let's get it.
Wow, that is a nice car.
Sorry, Rob.
Coast is clear, guys.
This is it, guys.
Moment of truth.
What the hell is this?
Shit!
Steve's neighbor's
throwing a party.
Are you here
for the, uh, Baker party, sir?
No.
We're not blowing
any gates tonight, guys.
Too many witnesses.
Stella.
I know, I know.
I'm late for my date.
Yeah, and you got to be
charming.
You'll need him
to ask you out again.
Sorry.
Let's get out of the street.
I really can't imagine
you doing that.
What's that supposed to mean?
Well, you don't really seem
like the adventurous type,
you know?
Don't let the cable uniform,
you know, throw you.
I wasn't making assumptions.
I've made some
assumptions about you.
Oh, really?
And?
Well... you're just going
to have to wait and see.
Why wait?
Let's get a check.
Let's go back to my place.
No assumptions...
Not tonight.
It's late.
I should go home.
What, you have
a cable company curfew?
No,
but I've made some
bad calls in the past.
Hey.
We should take this maybe a
little slower, you know?
This lovely dinner,
sparkling conversation...
you still don't trust me?
Oh, I trust everyone.
It's the devil inside them
I don't trust.
It's an interesting saying.
It's charming.
Where'd you pick that up?
Can't remember.
Really?
I knew a guy who said it
exactly like that.
Really?
Yeah. He's the only person
I've ever heard say that.
He said it all the time.
His name was John Bridger.
You're hurting my wrist.
He had a daughter
and she was about your age.
Let go of my wrist.
I knew that there was
something familiar about you.
You're exactly like
your old man, you know that?
I liked him, too,
right from the start.
I liked him right up
until the minute I shot him.
Who are you working with?
She's with us.
Gang's all here.
You know, the only thing
worse than a thief, Bendel?
A coward.
Then you should have seen
the way your daddy
begged for his life.
It's not worth it.
Put a leash on your cat.
Hi, Steve.
Charlie.
Not bad, Charlie.
Really, not bad.
You have no idea
how hard it is for me
not to reach across
this table and kill you
with my bare hands.
You know better than that,
Charlie.
Can't let emotion
into these things.
Tell me it wasn't about emotion
when you shot John
and left us all for dead.
That wasn't about emotion.
It was about a lot of gold,
and I wanted it.
Anything you think you
deserved, you didn't.
Hey, don't talk about right
and wrong with me, man,
'cause I just don't give a shit.
Okay?
You got your cards,
I got my cards,
we made our play,
and I came out on top, okay?
Now if you want to start
the game up again,
that's fine with me.
But what, I mean, what
is your play here, really?
I mean, come on, what do you...
what do you think?
Y-you'll try to take out
my guards, right?
I have five of them
that you don't know about.
You'll try to have
Lyle hack the system.
I'll change it again
tomorrow morning.
What, what, what was
y-your final move?
I mean, you were going
to have Bridger's daughter
come in and try
to crack my safe?
I mean, that's...
that's very poetic and all,
but I just don't see it.
I don't think she'll get
anywhere near it.
Same old Steve, huh?
Always thinking defensively.
That's why you're
always number two.
How do you figure that?
You got no imagination.
Couldn't even decide what
to do with all that money.
You had to buy what
everybody else wanted.
Oh... well, try this on
in your imagination, okay?
That gold is already gone.
That's bullshit, Steve.
No, really, it's over Charlie.
I'm trying to move
the last two bricks.
You want to come after me
over a couple of lousy bricks?
I mean, really, be my guest.
But you're off to a bad start,
you know?
'Cause you just blew
the best thing
you had going for you.
You just blew the element
of surprise.
Surprised?
It's over when I say it's over.
Are you all right, sir?
How you doing?
Good...
considering...
considering the fact
that I'm doing all of this
for a man I barely knew.
You know what bothered me
all those years, Charlie?
It was that, whenever
he'd call me to tell me
that he was on some job,
I knew you were right there
with him.
You got to know him
a lot better than I did.
Just 'cause he was around
me more doesn't mean
he wasn't thinking
about you all the time.
Be nice if it was true.
It is true.
He always regretted
not having been
a good enough father
to you, Stella.
How do you know that?
Because he told me.
What did you do to your hand?
I punched Steve.
Why do you get to punch him
and I don't?
Those hands are
way too valuable.
Hey.
Okay?
There'll be nothing left
of that if you keep rubbing it.
Tell Mr. Frazelli
we'll see him at 8:00.
Charlie!
He's flying the coop.
When?
His security guard called
for a private helicopter
at 4:00 PM.
There's an armored car service
coming to his house at 5:00.
There is a cargo plane scheduled
to depart LAX at 8:00 PM
to Mexico City.
What if he's moving the safe
as a diversion?
We crack it, it's empty,
the gold's somewhere else.
Steve's not about to let
that gold out of his sight.
It's going to be in that truck
and he's going to be watching it
every step of the way
from the helicopter.
So the gold's headed to Mexico.
Who knows where?
They could change
the flight plan in midair.
Slow down, slow down.
You guys are looking at this
the wrong way.
This is good news for us.
Charlie, what do you
mean, "good news"?
We've been trying to get
to the gold in the safe,
now the safe is coming to us.
We're going to boost it
in transit.
Charlie, it could take
a dozen different routes
to the airport.
We have no idea which one.
We can't take out an armored
truck during rush hour.
We're already set up to do it.
Napster,
gridlock every route
except for the one we choose.
Force that truck to go
exactly where we want it to go.
Where do we want it to go?
We can't have a shoot-out
with armed guards. We'd lose.
We do it like the Italian job.
Hello?
Why'd you do it?
Do what?
Yevhen.
You didn't have to clip him.
Whoa, whoa.
What are you talking about?
We didn't clip anybody.
Yevhen's cousin is under
the distinct impression
that you did.
Why does he think that?
Because you want to know
about the gold
with the Balinese dancer.
You told him that?
Listen to me, man.
If there's one thing that I know
is never to mess
with Mother Nature,
mother-in-laws
or mother-freakin' Ukrainians.
Look, I need a favor.
Yeah.
Had a hiccup last night.
Could use some help.
Want hands-on this time.
You interested?
Could be.
But I don't like
to be kept in the dark.
If I'm in, I'm in.
Okay, you're in.
All right.
What do you think, Charlie?
This'll work.
Let's go.
You're amazing.
It's a work of genius.
Uh-huh.
You okay?
Just give me a moment.
Now?
I'm about to insert this pin
into this detonator tube,
and if the brass touches
the sides,
we'll both be the last people
we ever see.
Take all the time you need.
Hey, Charlie.
What?
I love you, man.
I love you, too.
Okay.
Your attention, please.
Metrolink train number 774
will arrive
in approximately 15 minutes.
Check positions.
Napster?
I'm in position.
Handsome Rob?
We're in position.
Everything's quiet, Charlie.
Wrench?
Set.
Charlie, we got
an uninvited visitor.
Some motorcycle guard
following the truck.
We'll deal with it.
Who are these cats?
What's wrong?
Charlie, you won't believe this.
He's brought in
three armored trucks.
It's a shell game.
Shell game now.
Well, boss,
I can't reroute the truck
if I don't know which truck
to reroute.
Just go with the one
Steve follows in the helicopter.
Remember, he said he'd never let
that gold out of his sight.
Unless he's playing us,
and he is.
Okay, let's go!
Moving out!
Here we go.
They're pulling out.
Napster,
pull up the traffic cameras
you're watching.
Where's the first camera
the trucks go past?
Vine and Yucca; they're all
going to cross there.
See which one's riding low.
First one is...
First two are the same, so...
Houston, we have our truck.
It is number 128.
We're moving out.
Three-kilo-bob
to two-fox-mike,
we're heading to the airport.
Okay, guys, truck 128
has turned right heading west.
Gridlock time.
Mr. Scott, pick up
a courtesy telephone please.
Mr. Scott, pick up a courtesy...
We've crashed.
It's not a crash.
We've got power.
I can't log in.
They are about to hit a major
detour and be sent your way.
Oops.
You'll... never... shut down...
the real... Napster.
What's your problem?!
Truck 128,
what is your progress?
This is truck 128.
Traffic's out of control here.
We've got to look
for another route.
Check the police band.
Okay, I'm opening up
a space on Highland.
Oh, get us out of here.
I'm trying.
And he's taking it.
Police scanners are saying
computers are down
at Traffic Control Center.
Nice, Charlie.
What are you up to?
Go back.
I now command you to turn left.
Come on, take the left.
Yeah, you did.
You did.
Give us the flag.
Metro just passed through
the station.
You are clear for 90 seconds.
Go.
Come on, Steve.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Look out!
30 seconds and counting.
15 seconds,
you're either blocked in
or you're paint on the train.
Go, go, come on, come on!
Stay right on me,
this is gonna be tight.
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
You're gonna stop right there.
Okay, guys.
Coming into position.
Stay cool.
Ten...
nine...
eight...
seven...
six...
five...
four...
Don't lose 'em,
don't lose 'em,
- Don't lose them.
- Three...
two...
one.
Damn.
Where's my truck?
What...? What the fuck
happened to my truck?!
It just blew right through
the street.
Well, get under there.
We have another problem, guys.
What?
This isn't the Worthington 1000.
He switched safes on us.
Can you do it?
It's Israeli made.
It's got a glass re-lock system.
There's a pane of glass
right here behind this door.
And if I don't drill perfectly
through that hole,
steel rods snap into place
and you can't open the safe.
And then we're up shit creek.
I think I just
cracked the glass.
I don't think it broke though.
I can't drill it again.
I have to do it by touch.
I can't get through.
The train's blocking the tunnel.
Where does the Metro rail
come above ground?
11th and Fig.
Positions two and three,
meet at 11th and Figueroa
and double back
to Hollywood and Highland.
Hurry up!
Your attention please.
Baggage for train number 22
is now available
at carousel number four.
Baggage for train number 22
is now available
at carousel number four.
I can't do this, Charlie.
Stella...
I can't do it...
I need a drill,
a borescope, something.
- I need to...
- You don't need any of that.
Come on, Charlie.
Hey, you can do this.
Slide.
Come on, come on.
Hey.
Don't you want to see
what's inside?
Absolutely.
Napster.
Yeah?
13 across, four high, four deep.
That's, uh, 208 bricks.
How much?
Oh. Uh, 208 times...
2.7... 2.7 million.
What?
No, it's 27.
That's 27 million.
That's $27 million
worth of gold.
Yeah!
Got the... holy spirit.
You should get on it.
It's a good train.
What did you think, John?
27 million.
Say it again.
- 27 million.
- Say it again.
- Say it again!
- 27 million.
Say it again!
Two motorcycles on us, Charlie.
I've got three Minis
in the storm drain
heading east towards
the L.A. River.
Stop them before they get
to the street.
Shit!
Whoa!
Here we go.
Whoo!
Whoa! Whoa!
Open your door.
Come on, guys, we're moving.
There, there, there, there,
there, there.
Hey, come on, come on, look out.
Come on!
Where you going?
I'm going to take Steve.
You guys go straight
to Union Station.
I'll meet you there.
Stay on him.
Stay on him!
Okay, Charlie, I'm opening up
a spot on lower Grand.
I know it's you, Charlie.
Take your next left.
Nice move, Steve.
Get out!
- Get out!
- Okay.
I said get out!
They got a bunch of cars
in there, right?
Mini Coopers?
Look, look, man...
- I don't know anything...
- Hey, don't worry about them.
I'll give you five grand
you put me inside that car.
Buy your girlfriend
something nice.
Come on.
Half now, half when
you help me unload.
I've got to hand it
to you, Steve.
You actually played this one
pretty smart.
Decoy trucks...
you switched safes.
The helicopter routine,
I mean, that was
pretty damn good.
But now I've got the gold...
and you, you've got nothing.
I got this.
So cut the crap,
and give me my goddamn gold!
Who the hell are you?
I am Mashkov...
and you killed my cousin Yevhen.
Got to have some insurance,
Steve.
Yevhen was already dead
when I got there.
I'm sorry about that,
but Yevhen dealt with
a lot of unsavory people.
Now, this guy's
trying to play you.
You are right...
no imagination.
There's a lot of gold in there.
We're the only ones with guns.
I'll make you a good deal.
I've already made my deal.
What do you want?
You know this was
never about the gold.
Whatever helps you
sleep at night, sweetheart.
Bitch!
Charlie! Come on, Charlie!
Okay.
Wait a minute
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. I'll double
whatever he's giving you.
Just don't shoot me.
Don't worry, I'm not
going to shoot you.
No, I'm going to take you
to my workplace.
I think you would be
very interested
in some of the machinery I use.
No, come on.
Guys.
I want to make a toast.
To John Bridger,
the most brilliant
master planner of all.
Father and friend.
To my dad.
Stella was right.
It wasn't about the money.
Of course that
didn't stop the guys
from having a little bit of fun.
Money!
Handsome Rob
got his Aston Martin.
Get a good job with good pay...
He took it
for a ride to break it in.
Money, it's a gas
Grab that cash with both hands
and make a stash
He got off with a warning.
New car, caviar,
four star daydream
Left Ear got his dream house
in the south of Spain
with a room just for his shoes.
Buenos dias.
Money, get back
Lyle finally made the cover
of Wired Magazine.
I'm all right, Jack, keep
your hands off of my stack
Are you really the Napster?
Money!
Yes, I am.
And he got that
kick-ass stereo he wanted.
Uh, would you listen
to something for me?
With speakers so loud
they'd blow
a woman's clothes off.
I'm in the high-fidelity...
If you would.
...first class traveling set
And I think I need a Lear jet
And me?
I took John Bridger's advice.
I found somebody I want to spend
the rest of my life with
and I'm gonna hold on
to her forever.
Money!
It's a crime
Share it fairly, but don't
take a slice of my pie
Money, so they say
Is the root of all evil today
But if you ask for a raise
it's no surprise
They're giving none away
Away... away...
Away...