7
00:01:35,450 --> 00:01:36,610
Anne.

8
00:01:44,090 --> 00:01:45,170
Mary.

9
00:01:46,330 --> 00:01:47,310
Wait.

10
00:01:49,340 --> 00:01:50,610
Wait for me.

11
00:01:50,690 --> 00:01:53,160
I received a request for marriage today...

12
00:01:53,560 --> 00:01:56,900
for Anne from the Carey family.

13
00:01:57,180 --> 00:01:59,370
William, their eldest son.

14
00:01:59,740 --> 00:02:01,440
Oh, that's wonderful.

15
00:02:01,440 --> 00:02:05,110
I turned it down. Offered them Mary instead.

16
00:02:06,950 --> 00:02:08,020
Mary.

17
00:02:09,220 --> 00:02:12,690
Everyone improves the standing of their family with their daughters.

18
00:02:12,750 --> 00:02:15,590
I think Anne can do a lot better than a merchant's son.

19
00:02:16,340 --> 00:02:17,770
And Mary can't?

20
00:02:18,520 --> 00:02:22,500
- I think you underestimate her. - No, no, that's not true.

21
00:02:23,030 --> 00:02:26,710
I think she's the kinder of the two, quite possibly the fairer.

22
00:02:28,070 --> 00:02:30,980
To get ahead in this world, you need more than fair looks...

23
00:02:30,980 --> 00:02:32,350
and a kind heart.

24
00:02:32,350 --> 00:02:34,080
I'll beat you, I'll beat you.

25
00:02:43,980 --> 00:02:47,760
Well done, Anne. Well done, children.

26
00:03:57,030 --> 00:04:00,180
You look... You look adequate.

27
00:04:00,180 --> 00:04:04,110
Not too adequate, I hope. This is our sister's day.

28
00:04:04,600 --> 00:04:06,460
One wouldn't want to outshine her.

29
00:04:17,170 --> 00:04:19,270
Mary, may we come in?

30
00:04:23,900 --> 00:04:25,240
Look at you.

31
00:04:26,350 --> 00:04:29,970
Younger than me. More beautiful than me.

32
00:04:30,160 --> 00:04:33,700
Married before me. I'm eclipsed.

33
00:04:33,710 --> 00:04:35,260
I'm the other Boleyn girl.

34
00:04:35,580 --> 00:04:36,800
Hardly.

35
00:04:37,650 --> 00:04:40,820
So is this it, Mrs. Carey?

36
00:04:41,820 --> 00:04:43,960
Do we...? Do we lose you now, forever?

37
00:04:43,960 --> 00:04:47,550
No, never. I'll be married, that's all.

38
00:04:47,550 --> 00:04:49,700
Apart from that, it won't change a thing.

39
00:04:51,110 --> 00:04:53,820
Come, George, let's leave our sister.

40
00:04:54,430 --> 00:04:56,440
She needs to make herself pretty.

41
00:05:15,040 --> 00:05:16,300
Was it a boy?

42
00:05:21,690 --> 00:05:23,430
Stillborn, Your Majesty.

43
00:05:31,400 --> 00:05:35,070
No brother for you to make this country safe.

44
00:05:38,580 --> 00:05:39,740
I'm sorry.

45
00:05:46,370 --> 00:05:47,920
Tell His Majesty.

46
00:06:00,440 --> 00:06:01,600
Your Majesty.

47
00:06:03,470 --> 00:06:04,630
Your Majesty.

48
00:06:09,010 --> 00:06:10,280
I'm so sorry.

49
00:06:58,830 --> 00:06:59,990
Are you happy?

50
00:07:00,070 --> 00:07:01,150
I am.

51
00:07:01,670 --> 00:07:04,610
You don't wish you'd married someone grander? With a title?

52
00:07:05,060 --> 00:07:06,850
I want a husband who loves me.

53
00:07:07,270 --> 00:07:10,040
Who thinks it first thing every morning and last thing at night.

54
00:07:10,210 --> 00:07:11,830
Then you have found the right man.

55
00:07:18,180 --> 00:07:20,210
He continues to stare.

56
00:07:20,210 --> 00:07:22,230
- Who? - Henry Percy.

57
00:07:22,630 --> 00:07:24,960
Well, why ever would he interest you?

58
00:07:25,210 --> 00:07:27,100
What could you possibly want with the sole heir...

59
00:07:27,100 --> 00:07:29,130
to the richest landowner in England?

60
00:07:29,130 --> 00:07:31,870
Oh, I had no knowledge of that. I simply like his face.

61
00:07:31,870 --> 00:07:33,350
Oh, really?

62
00:07:34,760 --> 00:07:39,020
- Well, he's betrothed. - Betrothed is not married.

63
00:07:39,020 --> 00:07:41,570
It's a long journey from bended knee to the altar.

64
00:07:47,800 --> 00:07:50,500
- Sister. - Hello, brother.

65
00:07:51,600 --> 00:07:52,660
Thomas.

66
00:07:53,050 --> 00:07:54,780
- A proud day for you. - Yes.

67
00:07:57,740 --> 00:07:59,250
How is His Majesty?

68
00:07:59,590 --> 00:08:01,560
These are difficult times, Thomas.

69
00:08:03,670 --> 00:08:05,660
The King and Queen, once happily married...

70
00:08:05,660 --> 00:08:07,250
now barely speak.

71
00:08:07,620 --> 00:08:10,930
The failure to provide a male heir has consumed them.

72
00:08:11,720 --> 00:08:15,280
The Queen has lost yet another child, a boy.

73
00:08:15,920 --> 00:08:17,000
I imagine it won't be long

74
00:08:17,000 --> 00:08:19,550
before he seeks solace with a mistress.

75
00:08:22,570 --> 00:08:24,410
Obviously I've given it some thought and wondered

76
00:08:24,410 --> 00:08:27,670
which Howard girl I can place under his nose.

77
00:08:27,880 --> 00:08:31,000
You imagine the riches and influence that would give us?

78
00:08:31,460 --> 00:08:35,040
If we could help the King with this delicate matter?

79
00:08:37,210 --> 00:08:38,620
What about Anne?

80
00:08:40,770 --> 00:08:44,900
I realize, as a Boleyn, she's not officially a Howard...

81
00:08:45,380 --> 00:08:47,120
but as your sister's daughter.

82
00:08:47,120 --> 00:08:51,160
But, Thomas, she's your first born, and your favorite.

83
00:08:52,010 --> 00:08:55,560
Wouldn't you prefer her to have a simple, uncomplicated marriage?

84
00:08:55,830 --> 00:08:57,040
Like Mary?

85
00:08:57,590 --> 00:09:00,570
If Anne were a simple, uncomplicated girl like Mary...

86
00:09:00,570 --> 00:09:03,870
I'd say yes. But she's not.

87
00:09:04,520 --> 00:09:06,200
She's anything but.

88
00:09:19,460 --> 00:09:20,660
Are you afraid?

89
00:09:24,530 --> 00:09:25,740
A little.

90
00:09:27,770 --> 00:09:30,450
I should be able to tell you how it will be tonight.

91
00:09:32,470 --> 00:09:34,180
Give you advice on what to do.

92
00:09:36,100 --> 00:09:38,160
I've failed you as an elder sister.

93
00:09:39,530 --> 00:09:41,700
No one could wish for a better sister.

94
00:10:02,490 --> 00:10:04,250
And tell me everything in the morning.

95
00:10:04,260 --> 00:10:07,660
- I promise. - No details spared.

96
00:10:44,120 --> 00:10:45,250
Lie back.

97
00:11:13,410 --> 00:11:15,550
- Anne. - Father.

98
00:11:17,190 --> 00:11:18,240
Uncle.

99
00:11:19,550 --> 00:11:20,840
You asked to see me.

100
00:11:21,120 --> 00:11:23,130
An opportunity has arisen.

101
00:11:23,130 --> 00:11:25,290
An opportunity in which, were you to succeed...

102
00:11:25,290 --> 00:11:27,700
you could secure for yourself and for this family...

103
00:11:27,700 --> 00:11:29,870
incalculable wealth and position.

104
00:11:29,870 --> 00:11:32,000
There is a strain on the King's marriage.

105
00:11:33,680 --> 00:11:37,710
In such circumstances, a man sometimes seeks comfort elsewhere.

106
00:11:37,730 --> 00:11:40,250
At present because of your uncle's friendship with His Majesty

107
00:11:40,250 --> 00:11:42,650
we're alone in knowing this. It won't be long

108
00:11:42,650 --> 00:11:45,230
before the other families discover the truth

109
00:11:45,230 --> 00:11:48,300
and parade their daughters under his nose.

110
00:11:48,300 --> 00:11:50,820
Before watching somebody else profit, we would sooner have...

111
00:11:50,820 --> 00:11:51,930
What?

112
00:11:52,490 --> 00:11:55,810
- Have me bed him instead? - No, that... That's not...

113
00:11:55,810 --> 00:11:56,930
Yes.

114
00:11:58,190 --> 00:11:59,400
Exactly.

115
00:12:01,940 --> 00:12:04,310
The favor he would bestow upon us...

116
00:12:04,310 --> 00:12:08,080
I mean upon you, if he liked you.

117
00:12:08,080 --> 00:12:10,750
To be mistress of the King of England

118
00:12:11,080 --> 00:12:13,210
is by no means to diminish yourself.

119
00:12:13,210 --> 00:12:15,010
And after he's finished with me?

120
00:12:15,130 --> 00:12:17,150
My reputation and prospects will be ruined.

121
00:12:17,150 --> 00:12:18,420
On the contrary.

122
00:12:19,120 --> 00:12:21,140
Under such circumstances, when the time came...

123
00:12:21,150 --> 00:12:22,220
to find you a husband,

124
00:12:22,220 --> 00:12:25,040
it would be a marquis or a duke at least.

125
00:12:28,570 --> 00:12:30,340
Will you accept the challenge?

126
00:12:43,170 --> 00:12:45,320
Don't resist this.

127
00:12:45,400 --> 00:12:48,860
The King and his retinue will spend two nights here next month.

128
00:12:48,860 --> 00:12:50,910
Your brother has arranged it. It's done.

129
00:12:50,910 --> 00:12:52,460
Well, I don't like it.

130
00:12:52,640 --> 00:12:55,490
It'll cost a fortune to get this house ready for a royal visit.

131
00:12:55,690 --> 00:12:57,160
It's money we can't afford.

132
00:12:57,790 --> 00:12:59,140
And what if he doesn't like her?

133
00:12:59,140 --> 00:13:02,890
And what if you were to look on the bright side, just once?

134
00:13:02,890 --> 00:13:05,690
Risk nothing, you gain nothing. Anne understands that.

135
00:13:05,690 --> 00:13:09,070
Anne understands nothing. She's just a child.

136
00:13:09,460 --> 00:13:11,130
Tell me, when was it

137
00:13:11,130 --> 00:13:13,620
that people stopped thinking of ambition as a sin...

138
00:13:13,620 --> 00:13:15,710
and started thinking of it as a virtue?

139
00:13:17,010 --> 00:13:18,600
That's easy for you to say.

140
00:13:18,760 --> 00:13:21,280
You've had position and wealth all your life.

141
00:13:22,080 --> 00:13:24,340
Until I married you, Thomas.

142
00:13:24,880 --> 00:13:27,090
And I was happy to give it up for love.

143
00:13:31,920 --> 00:13:34,610
So how was it, the wedding night?

144
00:13:37,190 --> 00:13:39,110
It was very satisfactory.

145
00:13:39,820 --> 00:13:43,790
Really? William Carey, a good lover.

146
00:13:43,810 --> 00:13:44,980
Yes.

147
00:13:47,570 --> 00:13:50,680
Oh, God. He was in rather a hurry.

148
00:13:50,840 --> 00:13:52,880
- And he snores. - No.

149
00:13:53,000 --> 00:13:55,830
He got up in the middle of the night and used a pisspot...

150
00:13:55,840 --> 00:13:58,870
by the side of the bed. It was awful.

151
00:13:59,620 --> 00:14:00,660
No.

152
00:14:04,670 --> 00:14:06,740
I also have something to tell you.

153
00:14:07,220 --> 00:14:09,710
Last night, our father put his trust in me...

154
00:14:09,710 --> 00:14:12,280
and gave me a commission.

155
00:14:12,500 --> 00:14:13,820
Tell, tell.

156
00:14:14,510 --> 00:14:16,540
To divert the King.

157
00:14:16,540 --> 00:14:18,950
The King of England himself, on his visit.

158
00:14:19,000 --> 00:14:20,420
Divert him?

159
00:14:20,900 --> 00:14:25,540
Divert him. Beguile him. Enchant him.

160
00:14:25,800 --> 00:14:27,170
He has a wife.

161
00:14:27,590 --> 00:14:30,310
I know. But who knows what could happen?

162
00:14:30,390 --> 00:14:33,090
If he liked me, I'd be married off to a duke.

163
00:14:34,150 --> 00:14:35,740
I could be a happy duchess.

164
00:15:12,190 --> 00:15:13,320
The King.

165
00:15:15,580 --> 00:15:16,670
The King.

166
00:15:18,540 --> 00:15:20,200
The King will be here betimes.

167
00:15:20,200 --> 00:15:21,890
- The King. - Look alive.

168
00:15:22,140 --> 00:15:23,300
The King.

169
00:15:27,090 --> 00:15:28,220
To your places.

170
00:15:29,760 --> 00:15:31,900
Come on, set to, everyone. The King.

171
00:15:32,440 --> 00:15:34,310
Take the horses to the yard and prepare.

172
00:15:37,140 --> 00:15:39,110
Where's the spit boy? Where is he?

173
00:15:39,110 --> 00:15:40,250
Get over here.

174
00:15:46,550 --> 00:15:48,000
Do you think he'll like me?

175
00:15:49,460 --> 00:15:51,380
Course he will, sister.

176
00:15:53,060 --> 00:15:54,320
How could he not?

177
00:17:05,300 --> 00:17:06,520
Sir Thomas.

178
00:17:08,060 --> 00:17:10,410
Your Majesty. You're most welcome.

179
00:17:13,110 --> 00:17:14,390
Lady Elizabeth.

180
00:17:16,560 --> 00:17:19,420
May I present my daughter, Anne.

181
00:17:19,420 --> 00:17:22,470
A daughter? No one said anything of a daughter.

182
00:17:22,530 --> 00:17:24,600
Had we known, we might have come sooner.

183
00:17:25,830 --> 00:17:27,080
Your Majesty.

184
00:18:00,050 --> 00:18:04,790
Anne, Anne. Go to bed, get a good night's rest.

185
00:18:04,800 --> 00:18:08,350
Tomorrow there's the hunt. You must excel at that.

186
00:18:08,350 --> 00:18:10,430
Everything depends upon it.

187
00:18:36,130 --> 00:18:37,320
Good morning, Anne.

188
00:18:37,320 --> 00:18:38,900
Good morning, Your Grace.

189
00:18:39,600 --> 00:18:42,930
- Who will you ride with? - On my own, Your Grace.

190
00:18:43,510 --> 00:18:44,720
On your own?

191
00:18:45,070 --> 00:18:47,390
There's a new saddle now which allows this.

192
00:18:50,900 --> 00:18:52,320
But with no man to hold on to...

193
00:18:52,330 --> 00:18:54,450
how do you propose to stay on the horse?

194
00:18:54,470 --> 00:18:56,060
As you do, Your Grace.

195
00:18:57,040 --> 00:18:58,680
With my thighs.

196
00:19:01,870 --> 00:19:02,910
Away.

197
00:19:35,840 --> 00:19:37,220
What's keeping them?

198
00:19:46,340 --> 00:19:47,580
Where are they?

199
00:20:24,820 --> 00:20:26,050
Is someone hurt?

200
00:20:28,460 --> 00:20:29,900
My God, it's the King.

201
00:20:30,190 --> 00:20:33,750
The King? What? What happened?

202
00:20:34,160 --> 00:20:37,100
The stag went into the woods and led us to the deep ravine.

203
00:20:37,590 --> 00:20:40,370
Everyone was prepared to concede defeat and let the animal go.

204
00:20:41,630 --> 00:20:42,730
Except Anne.

205
00:20:42,730 --> 00:20:46,310
Oh, no. What? She knows that ravine.

206
00:20:46,310 --> 00:20:48,360
She must have ridden it a thousand times.

207
00:20:51,140 --> 00:20:53,960
What, and the King followed, and then he fell?

208
00:21:03,260 --> 00:21:04,420
Oh, Lord.

209
00:21:06,050 --> 00:21:07,680
- What happened? - He fell.

210
00:21:08,240 --> 00:21:09,480
He's in some pain.

211
00:21:10,160 --> 00:21:12,610
Although I suspect his pride is hurting rather more.

212
00:21:13,560 --> 00:21:14,880
It was my fault.

213
00:21:16,980 --> 00:21:18,270
- Anne. - How could I?

214
00:21:18,270 --> 00:21:19,790
Fetch Mary to me, would you?

215
00:21:40,520 --> 00:21:41,790
And who are you?

216
00:21:43,240 --> 00:21:44,730
Mary, Your Grace.

217
00:21:46,170 --> 00:21:47,570
Anne's sister.

218
00:21:53,590 --> 00:21:55,100
You've been here all the time?

219
00:21:56,980 --> 00:21:58,800
How could I have overlooked you?

220
00:22:01,170 --> 00:22:03,250
Next to Anne, it's easy to do.

221
00:22:12,930 --> 00:22:14,220
And you're married.

222
00:22:14,700 --> 00:22:17,960
Yes, Your Grace, to William Carey.

223
00:22:19,060 --> 00:22:21,140
Then why haven't I seen you at court?

224
00:22:22,710 --> 00:22:26,110
Because I've persuaded him to spend a year or two here first.

225
00:22:26,970 --> 00:22:28,480
We have a small manor.

226
00:22:28,810 --> 00:22:31,420
Nothing much, but enough to start a family.

227
00:22:32,880 --> 00:22:37,060
Charmed life in the country, away from it all.

228
00:22:37,750 --> 00:22:38,820
Yes.

229
00:22:40,740 --> 00:22:42,450
You don't think he'll miss court?

230
00:22:42,810 --> 00:22:44,450
A young ambitious man.

231
00:22:44,450 --> 00:22:46,280
He says not, Your Majesty.

232
00:22:46,970 --> 00:22:48,590
But if he ever changed his mind...

233
00:22:48,590 --> 00:22:51,060
as his wife, of course, I would do his bidding.

234
00:23:07,810 --> 00:23:09,710
Lady Elizabeth, thank you.

235
00:23:13,180 --> 00:23:14,330
Sir Thomas.

236
00:23:17,680 --> 00:23:19,330
You will take care of that matter?

237
00:23:21,220 --> 00:23:24,840
Yes, of course. Of course, Your Majesty, thank you.

238
00:23:52,150 --> 00:23:55,010
Mary, you've obviously made a deep impression on the King.

239
00:23:55,010 --> 00:23:57,780
He's requested that you come to court with immediate effect.

240
00:23:57,950 --> 00:24:00,410
The King has secured for you,

241
00:24:00,430 --> 00:24:03,430
a position in the Queen's household.

242
00:24:05,040 --> 00:24:08,400
But I don't want to go to court. Nor does my husband.

243
00:24:13,600 --> 00:24:15,840
The King has also offered me a position...

244
00:24:16,970 --> 00:24:19,010
as a gentleman of the Privy Council.

245
00:24:19,010 --> 00:24:22,180
Do you hear that, Mary? Privy Council.

246
00:24:22,880 --> 00:24:25,480
Attending upon His Majesty himself.

247
00:24:25,740 --> 00:24:27,320
The inner sanctum.

248
00:24:27,690 --> 00:24:29,660
What about our future in the country?

249
00:24:29,660 --> 00:24:31,750
Oh, you must put that out of your mind.

250
00:24:32,260 --> 00:24:34,430
From now on, your future is at court.

251
00:24:34,440 --> 00:24:35,740
William, please.

252
00:24:36,660 --> 00:24:39,560
Don't you understand what this means? They'll separate us.

253
00:24:39,710 --> 00:24:41,140
Put me in different accommodation,

254
00:24:41,140 --> 00:24:43,230
where the King can always find me.

255
00:24:43,630 --> 00:24:44,530
Happily, your husband

256
00:24:44,530 --> 00:24:47,290
understands the value of such an opportunity.

257
00:24:48,560 --> 00:24:49,910
For us all.

258
00:24:54,710 --> 00:24:57,340
What about Anne? Couldn't she go instead?

259
00:24:57,340 --> 00:24:58,460
Anne?

260
00:24:58,740 --> 00:25:02,180
The way Anne has behaved, she's fortunate to be coming at all.

261
00:25:12,020 --> 00:25:13,920
Mother, please, speak to Father.

262
00:25:13,920 --> 00:25:15,920
Do something. I don't want to go.

263
00:25:15,920 --> 00:25:20,380
This is not a request. We have been summoned.

264
00:25:24,350 --> 00:25:26,320
Please don't be angry with me.

265
00:25:26,730 --> 00:25:28,970
You think I desire to go for this purpose?

266
00:25:28,970 --> 00:25:31,920
All I know is that a man that didn't know who you were...

267
00:25:32,030 --> 00:25:34,280
was with you in that room for half an hour...

268
00:25:34,770 --> 00:25:36,450
and came out besotted.

269
00:25:36,500 --> 00:25:38,520
I don't know what you said or did.

270
00:25:38,520 --> 00:25:39,960
Nothing, sister.

271
00:25:39,960 --> 00:25:42,610
Except sing your praises and talk about my husband.

272
00:25:42,610 --> 00:25:45,710
Really? Well, you must show me how you did that some time.

273
00:26:35,320 --> 00:26:38,540
- Mary Carey, Your Majesty. - Who?

274
00:26:38,540 --> 00:26:41,700
Your new lady-in-waiting and her sister Anne.

275
00:26:41,910 --> 00:26:45,230
Really? I wasn't aware I was expecting one.

276
00:26:45,230 --> 00:26:48,700
Appointed by His Majesty the King.

277
00:26:52,290 --> 00:26:55,430
By my husband? Really?

278
00:26:56,280 --> 00:26:57,370
Well...

279
00:26:58,530 --> 00:27:02,920
then she must be some kind of gift or surprise.

280
00:27:03,560 --> 00:27:06,820
He must have seen in her some talent he knew would please me.

281
00:27:07,900 --> 00:27:09,120
Tell me.

282
00:27:09,550 --> 00:27:12,180
What special talent is it that you have...

283
00:27:12,200 --> 00:27:15,430
apart from your obvious youth and beauty?

284
00:27:18,290 --> 00:27:19,690
I...

285
00:27:23,660 --> 00:27:26,630
- Poetry, perhaps? - No.

286
00:27:26,820 --> 00:27:29,560
- Or dressmaking? - No.

287
00:27:29,560 --> 00:27:33,090
- Singing then, surely? - No, Your Majesty.

288
00:27:33,090 --> 00:27:37,250
Come, you're too modest. Sing for us.

289
00:27:38,920 --> 00:27:41,060
- Really, I beg you. - Sing.

290
00:28:25,090 --> 00:28:26,240
Bravo.

291
00:28:28,960 --> 00:28:30,530
A nightingale.

292
00:28:32,130 --> 00:28:33,800
Welcome at court.

293
00:28:40,980 --> 00:28:43,130
Mary? Stop.

294
00:28:44,930 --> 00:28:46,980
That can't have been easy for you.

295
00:28:47,220 --> 00:28:49,450
But put yourself in the Queen's shoes.

296
00:28:49,450 --> 00:28:50,310
She knows the only reason...

297
00:28:50,310 --> 00:28:53,130
the King has asked you here is because he desires you.

298
00:28:53,630 --> 00:28:55,580
She's a good woman, trust me.

299
00:28:56,760 --> 00:28:58,020
Jane Parker.

300
00:29:32,980 --> 00:29:34,590
It's embarrassing.

301
00:29:35,930 --> 00:29:38,030
Look, she has her eye on you.

302
00:29:38,030 --> 00:29:40,820
Sweet Jane Parker would be a match to please our father.

303
00:29:40,820 --> 00:29:42,990
Oh, vile girl.

304
00:29:43,300 --> 00:29:46,280
She's the most ambitious little serpent at court.

305
00:29:47,310 --> 00:29:49,180
She can't stop watching.

306
00:30:02,760 --> 00:30:04,280
How about you, Stafford?

307
00:30:04,780 --> 00:30:06,050
I'm well, thank you.

308
00:30:07,510 --> 00:30:09,810
I'm not sure I'm one for court life.

309
00:30:12,380 --> 00:30:13,870
I'm a little homesick.

310
00:30:15,660 --> 00:30:17,070
Well, you and I both.

311
00:30:17,320 --> 00:30:19,790
Now, in my view it... it changes people.

312
00:30:21,180 --> 00:30:22,940
And not necessarily for the better.

313
00:30:24,640 --> 00:30:26,790
Your sister, though, is thriving.

314
00:30:27,410 --> 00:30:29,920
She's truly caught the eye of Henry Percy.

315
00:30:30,290 --> 00:30:33,630
Why does she do this? He's already taken.

316
00:30:58,770 --> 00:30:59,890
Tonight.

317
00:31:19,830 --> 00:31:24,320
My little sister. My little golden sister.

318
00:31:26,000 --> 00:31:28,060
My milk-and-honey sister.

319
00:31:28,790 --> 00:31:30,470
It should be you in my place.

320
00:31:30,470 --> 00:31:32,350
Don't concern yourself with me.

321
00:31:35,240 --> 00:31:36,860
I'll make my own way.

322
00:31:42,720 --> 00:31:44,040
Shall I walk with you?

323
00:31:44,220 --> 00:31:45,360
No need.

324
00:31:46,360 --> 00:31:49,900
Try to please him. If you can.

325
00:32:25,180 --> 00:32:26,350
Your Grace.

326
00:32:28,230 --> 00:32:29,330
Come in.

327
00:32:38,000 --> 00:32:39,290
Can I bring you something?

328
00:32:39,540 --> 00:32:40,710
No.

329
00:32:41,900 --> 00:32:44,240
Anything to ease your comfort or well-being?

330
00:32:46,420 --> 00:32:49,700
Perhaps you might ask your servants to bring me some water.

331
00:32:53,500 --> 00:32:54,650
Please.

332
00:33:06,140 --> 00:33:08,910
There. There are no servants.

333
00:33:14,160 --> 00:33:15,600
So this is it?

334
00:33:16,430 --> 00:33:18,720
Where the King of England sleeps.

335
00:33:19,000 --> 00:33:20,720
And reads and writes.

336
00:33:21,100 --> 00:33:23,460
Finds a few moments each day for himself.

337
00:33:25,140 --> 00:33:27,140
And yet you invite me here?

338
00:33:28,810 --> 00:33:32,240
Because I like you and trust you.

339
00:33:33,460 --> 00:33:35,100
You hardly know me.

340
00:33:36,460 --> 00:33:38,470
I'm lied to a hundred times a day.

341
00:33:38,840 --> 00:33:40,550
Petitioned, lobbied.

342
00:33:40,990 --> 00:33:43,190
One learns how to decipher a face.

343
00:33:43,190 --> 00:33:46,070
And yours is as the sun.

344
00:33:46,070 --> 00:33:47,940
One shouldn't gaze too long.

345
00:33:50,480 --> 00:33:52,610
My flattery, it makes you uncomfortable.

346
00:33:55,700 --> 00:33:58,760
Because compliments in your family are usually for someone else.

347
00:34:00,050 --> 00:34:01,430
The elder sister.

348
00:34:04,870 --> 00:34:07,410
That's something I understand.

349
00:34:07,410 --> 00:34:09,950
What it is to be the second child.

350
00:34:10,920 --> 00:34:12,880
Forever in the shadows.

351
00:34:17,560 --> 00:34:19,380
I'm making you uncomfortable again.

352
00:36:19,660 --> 00:36:21,110
- Morning. - Stafford.

353
00:36:21,110 --> 00:36:22,130
Morning.

354
00:36:22,200 --> 00:36:24,100
I have orders to bring you to your father.

355
00:36:25,170 --> 00:36:26,670
Better not keep him waiting.

356
00:36:42,170 --> 00:36:43,210
Well?

357
00:36:45,190 --> 00:36:46,460
Did he have you?

358
00:36:53,350 --> 00:36:54,460
Yes.

359
00:36:55,270 --> 00:36:56,620
More than once?

360
00:36:58,940 --> 00:37:00,880
You better get used to talking about it.

361
00:37:01,230 --> 00:37:04,250
When you sleep with the King, it ceases to be a private matter.

362
00:37:08,060 --> 00:37:09,680
Yes, more than once.

363
00:37:10,280 --> 00:37:11,920
And was he satisfied?

364
00:37:15,010 --> 00:37:17,950
- I believe so. - Did he say so?

365
00:37:18,360 --> 00:37:20,310
He did not need to, uncle.

366
00:37:22,760 --> 00:37:23,970
Well, you may go.

367
00:37:33,780 --> 00:37:34,850
Good.

368
00:37:36,130 --> 00:37:37,650
Now our work begins.

369
00:37:38,170 --> 00:37:39,240
It's one thing to catch a King,

370
00:37:39,240 --> 00:37:41,020
quite another to keep him.

371
00:37:41,450 --> 00:37:45,190
She must be well-read, know her music, excel in company...

372
00:37:45,190 --> 00:37:47,560
and she must be clean.

373
00:37:47,690 --> 00:37:50,120
- Anne will see to it. - See to what?

374
00:37:50,880 --> 00:37:53,090
Mary is already all of these things.

375
00:37:53,200 --> 00:37:55,550
Thanks to the education I have given her.

376
00:37:56,090 --> 00:37:58,950
And for what? That she may be traded like cattle...

377
00:37:58,950 --> 00:38:01,710
for the advancement and amusement of men?

378
00:38:01,710 --> 00:38:04,570
Sister, you may leave us also.

379
00:38:10,110 --> 00:38:11,260
Katherine of Aragon

380
00:38:11,260 --> 00:38:13,550
will never give Henry Tudor a son.

381
00:38:15,910 --> 00:38:18,120
But if Mary could give him a child,

382
00:38:19,650 --> 00:38:21,610
and that child could be a boy...

383
00:39:26,900 --> 00:39:28,780
If I gave your husband an assignment

384
00:39:28,780 --> 00:39:30,480
that took him away from court...

385
00:39:30,610 --> 00:39:32,120
would you object?

386
00:39:36,010 --> 00:39:39,700
I would not presume to interfere in affairs of state.

387
00:40:00,090 --> 00:40:02,180
- Amen. - Amen.

388
00:40:14,720 --> 00:40:18,450
"My heart and I surrender themselves into your hands."

389
00:40:51,880 --> 00:40:52,960
It's Anne.

390
00:40:54,860 --> 00:40:56,570
She's married Henry Percy.

391
00:40:56,880 --> 00:40:59,090
Wedded and bedded without telling anyone.

392
00:41:00,130 --> 00:41:02,480
You... You don't look pleased.

393
00:41:02,480 --> 00:41:03,740
Why would I be pleased?

394
00:41:03,740 --> 00:41:06,930
Well, it will make her the future Duchess of Northumberland.

395
00:41:07,790 --> 00:41:10,420
- Our sister. - George, they'll never allow it.

396
00:41:10,860 --> 00:41:13,250
He's already precontracted to Mary Talbot.

397
00:41:13,250 --> 00:41:15,960
If this gets out, it will damage her.

398
00:41:15,970 --> 00:41:17,960
Her reputation will be ruined.

399
00:41:19,240 --> 00:41:22,070
I have to tell father. For her own protection.

400
00:41:24,730 --> 00:41:26,060
What were you thinking?

401
00:41:26,520 --> 00:41:29,690
The marriage of a senior noble is a matter of the state.

402
00:41:29,690 --> 00:41:31,980
Something only the King can decide.

403
00:41:32,550 --> 00:41:34,190
Who else knows about this?

404
00:41:35,170 --> 00:41:36,590
- No one. - Good.

405
00:41:36,620 --> 00:41:39,120
Well, that's how it will remain. Forever.

406
00:41:39,120 --> 00:41:41,770
But you cannot undo what has been done before God.

407
00:41:42,120 --> 00:41:43,930
And consummated too.

408
00:41:45,930 --> 00:41:49,850
There have been improper intimacies?

409
00:41:50,310 --> 00:41:52,400
I have lain with my husband.

410
00:41:52,750 --> 00:41:54,340
There's nothing improper about it.

411
00:41:54,340 --> 00:41:56,420
By God, if you were my daughter.

412
00:41:57,740 --> 00:41:59,650
The boy will return to Northumberland...

413
00:41:59,650 --> 00:42:02,950
where he will marry the Talbot girl, as arranged.

414
00:42:16,480 --> 00:42:18,480
You will be sent to France and stay there...

415
00:42:18,480 --> 00:42:21,010
- until you have learned your lesson. - What?

416
00:42:21,210 --> 00:42:22,290
No.

417
00:42:23,320 --> 00:42:24,740
Father, please.

418
00:42:24,740 --> 00:42:27,760
How can you have done this? You knew full well...

419
00:42:27,760 --> 00:42:28,920
Mary's friendship with the King

420
00:42:28,930 --> 00:42:30,980
is at an extremely delicate stage.

421
00:42:30,980 --> 00:42:35,210
Any scandal, any mark upon her name could be fatal.

422
00:42:35,410 --> 00:42:37,980
You will join the court of the French Queen...

423
00:42:37,980 --> 00:42:41,320
and stay there until your father has forgiven you.

424
00:42:47,060 --> 00:42:48,740
You told them, didn't you?

425
00:42:48,740 --> 00:42:52,010
It was for your own good. You never would have got away with it.

426
00:42:52,010 --> 00:42:53,120
It would have ruined your prospects forever.

427
00:42:53,120 --> 00:42:55,320
Really? For my good?

428
00:42:55,600 --> 00:42:58,710
Well, I'll try to remind myself of that while I'm in exile.

429
00:42:58,750 --> 00:43:00,890
And you're here in the King's bed...

430
00:43:00,890 --> 00:43:03,460
not challenged for our father's affection...

431
00:43:03,460 --> 00:43:05,930
that is was for my good and not yours.

432
00:43:05,930 --> 00:43:07,050
Anne.

433
00:43:09,500 --> 00:43:12,280
You would be wise to regard this as an opportunity.

434
00:43:15,230 --> 00:43:18,390
You are educated. It's a chance I never had.

435
00:43:19,400 --> 00:43:23,350
Now go to France. The Queen of France is sophisticated.

436
00:43:23,750 --> 00:43:26,510
Be useful to her, amuse her.

437
00:43:26,510 --> 00:43:28,060
She'll admire your spirit.

438
00:43:28,660 --> 00:43:29,960
Learn from her.

439
00:43:30,660 --> 00:43:31,940
Observe the ladies of the court.

440
00:43:31,940 --> 00:43:33,220
See how they achieve...

441
00:43:33,220 --> 00:43:34,200
what they want from their men,

442
00:43:34,200 --> 00:43:36,580
not by stamping their little feet...

443
00:43:37,110 --> 00:43:38,300
but by allowing the men

444
00:43:38,300 --> 00:43:40,680
to believe that they, indeed, are in charge.

445
00:43:41,470 --> 00:43:43,420
That is the art of being a woman.

446
00:45:26,420 --> 00:45:29,980
Still shut, keep them shut. Careful, careful.

447
00:45:32,900 --> 00:45:35,380
All right, now open.

448
00:45:39,670 --> 00:45:42,750
I am to become an earl, your brother a viscount.

449
00:45:42,750 --> 00:45:46,140
In addition, we have received a number of new grants and estates.

450
00:45:46,140 --> 00:45:47,890
So our debts are paid, and more.

451
00:45:47,890 --> 00:45:49,360
George, the King will

452
00:45:49,360 --> 00:45:52,920
arrange a match between you and Jane Parker.

453
00:45:55,640 --> 00:45:57,900
I beg you, Father, no.

454
00:45:58,110 --> 00:46:00,670
I thought you had ambitions for this family?

455
00:46:00,900 --> 00:46:04,190
The girl's well connected. Her father is cousin to the King.

456
00:46:04,190 --> 00:46:05,980
Must I actually marry her?

457
00:46:05,980 --> 00:46:09,040
Of course you must marry her. Have you no pride?

458
00:46:09,080 --> 00:46:11,260
Or would you rather leave everything to Mary?

459
00:46:15,830 --> 00:46:16,930
No, sir.

460
00:46:30,130 --> 00:46:33,330
It'll be a wedding attended by the King of England...

461
00:46:33,330 --> 00:46:35,700
with all the greatest lords of the land.

462
00:46:36,020 --> 00:46:38,070
Would a smile be too much to ask?

463
00:46:38,090 --> 00:46:39,780
What's there to smile about?

464
00:46:40,700 --> 00:46:44,180
I'm a mother with one child ordered to marry a girl he hates...

465
00:46:44,180 --> 00:46:45,830
another banished abroad in disgrace...

466
00:46:45,830 --> 00:46:48,910
and a third, whoring in public

467
00:46:48,910 --> 00:46:51,070
with an adulterer.

468
00:46:51,570 --> 00:46:54,170
You say you're concerned for her happiness.

469
00:46:54,530 --> 00:46:56,930
Will Mary be happy when he leaves her?

470
00:46:57,090 --> 00:46:59,360
Because you know that will happen in the end.

471
00:46:59,360 --> 00:47:01,060
Only God knows how anything will end.

472
00:47:01,060 --> 00:47:04,770
God? He turned his back on all this a long time ago.

473
00:47:04,770 --> 00:47:06,780
And these rooms, our new position?

474
00:47:06,840 --> 00:47:08,540
Does none of my work please you?

475
00:47:08,540 --> 00:47:12,230
These gifts, this favor

476
00:47:12,230 --> 00:47:14,380
will go as swiftly as it came.

477
00:47:15,250 --> 00:47:17,610
These rooms once belonged to the Duke of Buckingham...

478
00:47:17,610 --> 00:47:19,610
the King's closest friend.

479
00:47:20,640 --> 00:47:22,710
His head now rots on a spike.

480
00:47:22,710 --> 00:47:23,720
He committed treason.

481
00:47:23,720 --> 00:47:25,530
Treason? What is treason?

482
00:47:25,830 --> 00:47:29,120
Anything the King or his lawyers decide it to be.

483
00:47:30,120 --> 00:47:31,290
On a whim.

484
00:48:19,940 --> 00:48:21,130
The baby lives.

485
00:48:22,170 --> 00:48:23,630
She's not miscarried.

486
00:48:25,260 --> 00:48:26,920
But for the sake of the child...

487
00:48:27,860 --> 00:48:29,930
she must begin her lying-in, immediately.

488
00:49:07,190 --> 00:49:10,660
Now that Mary is lying-in, the King will no longer bed her.

489
00:49:12,260 --> 00:49:14,650
Out of compassion, he'll visit her every day for,

490
00:49:14,650 --> 00:49:16,440
what, a week?

491
00:49:17,070 --> 00:49:18,660
The Queen will have his head spinning...

492
00:49:18,660 --> 00:49:20,710
with pretty little Spanish things.

493
00:49:20,710 --> 00:49:24,400
Not to mention the Seymours and that milky-faced girl of theirs.

494
00:49:25,620 --> 00:49:29,280
We must influence him in our favor with whatever means we have.

495
00:49:35,030 --> 00:49:36,130
Yes?

496
00:49:36,740 --> 00:49:37,990
Well, l...

497
00:49:38,260 --> 00:49:41,770
I was going to suggest Anne.

498
00:49:41,770 --> 00:49:43,340
You couldn't control that girl last time.

499
00:49:43,340 --> 00:49:44,550
What makes you think a couple months...

500
00:49:44,550 --> 00:49:46,740
in France have made any difference?

501
00:49:48,700 --> 00:49:52,590
I receive regular reports from the Dowager Queen.

502
00:49:53,990 --> 00:49:57,810
It seems that she's quite changed.

503
00:50:03,170 --> 00:50:06,310
And so you must return as your uncle bids.

504
00:50:08,150 --> 00:50:10,030
You are to entertain the King...

505
00:50:10,430 --> 00:50:13,940
and keep his mind on Mary at all times.

506
00:50:13,980 --> 00:50:16,610
That is your task and no more.

507
00:50:47,310 --> 00:50:48,710
What's the noise?

508
00:50:50,980 --> 00:50:52,870
It's Mistress Boleyn, Your Grace.

509
00:50:52,870 --> 00:50:55,360
Her stories of life at the French court.

510
00:50:55,730 --> 00:50:57,830
I'm aware of one Boleyn girl.

511
00:50:58,010 --> 00:51:00,780
But she's lying-in with a certain child in her belly.

512
00:51:02,520 --> 00:51:04,240
Well, Boleyn girl...

513
00:51:05,790 --> 00:51:07,300
show your face.

514
00:51:16,050 --> 00:51:17,560
What's so amusing?

515
00:51:18,140 --> 00:51:21,150
I was merely offering my thoughts on the new French King.

516
00:51:21,910 --> 00:51:26,730
Who has such great power, yet such meager authority as a man.

517
00:51:29,090 --> 00:51:32,850
- Continue. - His pettiness is astounding.

518
00:51:32,890 --> 00:51:35,740
He will bear a mortal grudge over the mildest of slights.

519
00:51:35,740 --> 00:51:37,950
Spoiled cub with a spike in its paw.

520
00:51:37,950 --> 00:51:40,350
Riven with resentment.

521
00:51:40,740 --> 00:51:42,940
Unable to forgive or forget.

522
00:51:44,250 --> 00:51:45,760
A great King...

523
00:51:46,910 --> 00:51:50,950
A great man, rises above such things.

524
00:51:52,250 --> 00:51:54,360
And what would you know of great men?

525
00:51:54,860 --> 00:51:57,880
I've read enough books and heard enough talk...

526
00:51:58,170 --> 00:52:02,100
to believe I'd know one if he were before me.

527
00:52:02,740 --> 00:52:05,540
Then look about you. I'm curious.

528
00:52:05,540 --> 00:52:08,080
Do you see one here?

529
00:52:12,500 --> 00:52:14,130
Looking, My Lord.

530
00:52:14,810 --> 00:52:17,060
Still looking, My Lord.

531
00:52:19,860 --> 00:52:22,550
There. Found one.

532
00:52:26,340 --> 00:52:30,530
So forgiveness, you say, makes a man great.

533
00:52:30,530 --> 00:52:31,780
What else?

534
00:52:32,980 --> 00:52:34,360
Generosity.

535
00:52:35,120 --> 00:52:36,420
Humility.

536
00:52:37,730 --> 00:52:40,430
The ability to recognize his match in others...

537
00:52:40,430 --> 00:52:42,510
and not be threatened by it.

538
00:52:43,150 --> 00:52:45,800
- His match in other men? - Women too.

539
00:52:46,350 --> 00:52:47,610
You believe that?

540
00:52:48,110 --> 00:52:50,400
That women can be the match of men?

541
00:52:50,410 --> 00:52:53,410
It's a question women have asked themselves for some time.

542
00:52:53,690 --> 00:52:56,130
But we concede men do have some value.

543
00:52:56,690 --> 00:52:58,780
So we accept them as equal.

544
00:53:02,340 --> 00:53:04,910
I find you much changed, Mistress Anne.

545
00:53:05,330 --> 00:53:07,500
Then my prayers have been answered.

546
00:53:10,480 --> 00:53:12,290
Welcome back at court.

547
00:53:15,270 --> 00:53:16,470
My Lord.

548
00:53:19,890 --> 00:53:20,950
What?

549
00:53:21,530 --> 00:53:24,990
I suppose he felt that she'd been banished long enough.

550
00:53:25,200 --> 00:53:27,930
But in whose interest do they imagine she'll act?

551
00:53:28,390 --> 00:53:29,900
Certainly not mine.

552
00:53:32,100 --> 00:53:34,390
Why do they make this room such a dungeon?

553
00:53:35,250 --> 00:53:37,170
Does it have to be this dark?

554
00:53:51,100 --> 00:53:54,360
- Where were you? - Just visiting Mary.

555
00:53:55,960 --> 00:53:57,220
As ever.

556
00:53:57,590 --> 00:54:00,350
Well, now that Anne's back, you can be doubly jealous.

557
00:54:01,770 --> 00:54:03,070
I'm your wife.

558
00:54:05,420 --> 00:54:06,900
You never lie with me.

559
00:54:23,120 --> 00:54:25,270
Yes, it has.

560
00:54:26,280 --> 00:54:27,880
I hope you know what you're doing.

561
00:54:29,260 --> 00:54:32,010
These are vagabonds who'll stop at nothing to take your money.

562
00:54:32,140 --> 00:54:33,820
We're not gambling, Your Grace.

563
00:54:33,820 --> 00:54:36,010
Mistress Boleyn is reading our fortunes.

564
00:54:38,990 --> 00:54:40,210
Read mine.

565
00:54:45,660 --> 00:54:47,620
Another talent picked up in France?

566
00:54:47,770 --> 00:54:51,060
The Queen offers her ladies a broad education.

567
00:54:52,030 --> 00:54:55,220
Last I heard, she was entertaining Lutherans and heretics.

568
00:54:55,800 --> 00:55:00,070
Scholars and philosophers, My Lord, escaping persecution.

569
00:55:00,310 --> 00:55:02,890
- I hope you kept your ears shut. - I did.

570
00:55:02,890 --> 00:55:06,580
And a cross close to my heart at all times.

571
00:56:49,470 --> 00:56:53,130
- From the King, Mistress Anne. - Open it.

572
00:56:55,110 --> 00:56:56,310
Open it.

573
00:57:14,220 --> 00:57:15,690
Now send it back.

574
00:57:20,790 --> 00:57:22,180
You heard me.

575
00:57:25,380 --> 00:57:26,670
She did what?

576
00:57:27,790 --> 00:57:29,550
Sent it back, Your Grace.

577
00:57:42,760 --> 00:57:43,840
Anne.

578
00:57:49,560 --> 00:57:53,500
I meant to come sooner. I'm sorry I did not.

579
00:57:53,930 --> 00:57:56,400
- I've been kept occupied. - So I hear.

580
00:57:56,630 --> 00:57:57,880
Amusing the King.

581
00:57:57,880 --> 00:58:00,140
Only that, sister. I assure you.

582
00:58:00,400 --> 00:58:01,900
Despite his best efforts.

583
00:58:01,900 --> 00:58:03,600
What? And not yours?

584
00:58:08,700 --> 00:58:09,860
How is it?

585
00:58:11,350 --> 00:58:12,760
The child is strong.

586
00:58:14,080 --> 00:58:17,810
It gives me no rest. Like his father.

587
00:58:20,140 --> 00:58:22,580
Do you feel as awful as you look?

588
00:58:22,590 --> 00:58:23,880
You know, in France...

589
00:58:23,880 --> 00:58:26,250
no woman would allow herself to get in such a state.

590
00:58:26,260 --> 00:58:29,710
Why did you come, Anne, if all you desire is to torment me?

591
00:58:29,780 --> 00:58:31,710
Perhaps now you know

592
00:58:31,710 --> 00:58:34,930
how it feels to be deceived by your sister.

593
00:58:34,950 --> 00:58:37,740
- I did nothing. - You stole the King away.

594
00:58:37,740 --> 00:58:40,080
And then you betrayed me over Henry Percy.

595
00:58:40,080 --> 00:58:42,460
If that's what you think, tell yourself that.

596
00:58:42,460 --> 00:58:46,760
I did, sister. Every day and every night I was in exile.

597
00:58:52,520 --> 00:58:55,170
A gift from the King.

598
00:58:56,430 --> 00:58:57,870
Give it to my sister.

599
00:58:59,690 --> 00:59:01,480
It's for you, Mistress Anne.

600
00:59:02,800 --> 00:59:03,960
Me?

601
00:59:04,610 --> 00:59:07,840
Then send it back. Immediately.

602
00:59:11,930 --> 00:59:13,540
How dare he?

603
00:59:15,890 --> 00:59:17,020
You see...

604
00:59:18,150 --> 00:59:20,290
I have your interests at heart.

605
00:59:20,720 --> 00:59:21,860
Why?

606
00:59:23,190 --> 00:59:24,950
Why this cruelty?

607
00:59:26,490 --> 00:59:28,300
You know I love him.

608
00:59:29,940 --> 00:59:31,850
Well, perhaps you should stop.

609
00:59:59,740 --> 01:00:00,760
Your Grace.

610
01:00:01,960 --> 01:00:04,150
Your daughter. Where is she?

611
01:00:05,140 --> 01:00:06,210
Leave us.

612
01:00:08,440 --> 01:00:09,560
Where is she?

613
01:00:11,340 --> 01:00:12,420
Which one?

614
01:00:17,470 --> 01:00:19,160
Your Grace, which one?

615
01:00:22,240 --> 01:00:24,550
- Anne. - Your Grace?

616
01:00:24,550 --> 01:00:26,890
- You received my gifts? - Yes.

617
01:00:26,890 --> 01:00:28,980
And? They did not please you?

618
01:00:28,980 --> 01:00:30,490
On the contrary, My Lord.

619
01:00:30,490 --> 01:00:31,690
They pleased me greatly.

620
01:00:31,690 --> 01:00:33,780
Why do you insult me by returning them?

621
01:00:33,780 --> 01:00:36,020
Because you insult me by sending them at all.

622
01:00:36,070 --> 01:00:38,510
My sister lies in bed with your child.

623
01:00:38,770 --> 01:00:39,850
If you wish to please me, sir,

624
01:00:39,850 --> 01:00:41,560
send her the gifts you send me.

625
01:00:41,560 --> 01:00:44,430
I have shown Mary enough kindness and generosity.

626
01:00:44,540 --> 01:00:46,800
Now it pleases me to show you some.

627
01:00:50,920 --> 01:00:53,890
I beg you, My Lord, do not do this.

628
01:00:54,140 --> 01:00:55,590
What has changed so?

629
01:00:55,590 --> 01:00:58,050
You. You have changed.

630
01:00:58,050 --> 01:00:59,320
How could I forget?

631
01:00:59,350 --> 01:01:01,860
You chose Mary above me when we first met.

632
01:01:01,940 --> 01:01:03,150
No, Anne.

633
01:01:03,290 --> 01:01:06,070
Yours was the only face I saw in the crowd that day.

634
01:01:06,080 --> 01:01:08,750
And what I wouldn't give to go back to that day, My Lord.

635
01:01:09,020 --> 01:01:12,400
Have my chance again. But it's too late.

636
01:01:13,390 --> 01:01:15,350
And I would never betray my sister.

637
01:01:15,930 --> 01:01:19,060
Now I beg you, leave me.

638
01:01:19,460 --> 01:01:21,980
- This is too difficult to bear. - You see?

639
01:01:22,340 --> 01:01:24,140
The same pain as mine.

640
01:01:24,140 --> 01:01:26,540
Proof you feel the same way.

641
01:01:26,730 --> 01:01:29,280
Perhaps, but since it can never come to...

642
01:01:29,280 --> 01:01:32,930
No, let me decide that. Allow me hope.

643
01:01:34,990 --> 01:01:36,040
Leave me.

644
01:02:23,790 --> 01:02:26,730
- Does the King know? - He's been told.

645
01:02:36,020 --> 01:02:38,290
- Any moment, Your Grace. - How is she?

646
01:02:39,470 --> 01:02:42,970
Brave and strong. All may be well.

647
01:03:20,000 --> 01:03:22,910
Anne. Have you considered what I asked?

648
01:03:22,910 --> 01:03:24,070
Is there hope?

649
01:03:24,240 --> 01:03:25,950
How could I ever trust you...

650
01:03:26,170 --> 01:03:28,730
when I've seen how you betrayed your first wife...

651
01:03:28,920 --> 01:03:30,410
now my sister?

652
01:04:04,230 --> 01:04:07,590
I vow I will never lie with my wife,

653
01:04:07,590 --> 01:04:09,720
nor speak to your sister again.

654
01:04:11,210 --> 01:04:12,850
Just allow me to hope.

655
01:04:18,600 --> 01:04:19,670
A boy.

656
01:04:21,260 --> 01:04:23,420
I will take care of Mary and the child.

657
01:04:23,460 --> 01:04:24,570
Your Grace.

658
01:04:26,630 --> 01:04:27,820
A son.

659
01:04:30,250 --> 01:04:31,370
A son.

660
01:04:45,600 --> 01:04:47,160
Very well, My Lord.

661
01:04:49,840 --> 01:04:51,260
You may have hope.

662
01:04:57,070 --> 01:04:58,620
My one true love.

663
01:05:11,440 --> 01:05:12,530
My Lord.

664
01:05:20,030 --> 01:05:21,090
My Lord.

665
01:05:38,080 --> 01:05:41,860
Damn you. Not a single detail was left to chance.

666
01:05:42,010 --> 01:05:43,690
In the moment of our greatest glory...

667
01:05:43,690 --> 01:05:46,150
Glory? What glory?

668
01:05:46,160 --> 01:05:48,920
A mistress gave a man a bastard. No more.

669
01:05:48,920 --> 01:05:50,520
A male bastard. A son.

670
01:05:50,520 --> 01:05:52,810
The Queen may yet give birth to a son.

671
01:05:52,820 --> 01:05:55,480
The Queen no longer bleeds.

672
01:05:58,660 --> 01:06:01,620
- Can you be sure? - One of her physicians.

673
01:06:02,030 --> 01:06:04,030
The moment this family provides a son...

674
01:06:04,030 --> 01:06:06,080
he turns his back on it on your account.

675
01:06:06,080 --> 01:06:08,740
You better have a plan, and that plan had better work.

676
01:06:08,740 --> 01:06:10,780
- Or what, uncle? - Enough.

677
01:06:12,790 --> 01:06:13,970
Both of you.

678
01:06:17,070 --> 01:06:18,410
And what about Mary?

679
01:06:19,360 --> 01:06:22,110
And her child? Or have we forgotten about them already?

680
01:06:22,110 --> 01:06:25,380
Mary and her bastard child will go back to the country.

681
01:06:25,410 --> 01:06:28,490
It is the King's wish, and mine.

682
01:06:29,830 --> 01:06:31,020
Very well.

683
01:06:32,270 --> 01:06:34,320
And you can be the one to tell her.

684
01:06:34,900 --> 01:06:36,720
I think you've earned that privilege.

685
01:07:02,560 --> 01:07:04,490
How can you show your face in here?

686
01:07:07,300 --> 01:07:08,720
My own sister.

687
01:07:14,360 --> 01:07:15,510
Take care.

688
01:07:16,830 --> 01:07:19,250
Because he'll only do to you what he's done to me.

689
01:07:19,710 --> 01:07:21,940
You should not have given yourself so lightly.

690
01:07:22,310 --> 01:07:24,060
These are the consequences.

691
01:07:24,870 --> 01:07:27,390
I gave myself to a man I loved.

692
01:07:28,790 --> 01:07:32,760
- And he loved me. - A man's love is worthless.

693
01:07:32,980 --> 01:07:35,570
Our mother succumbed to love. Look what it got her.

694
01:07:35,860 --> 01:07:37,500
A feeble husband.

695
01:07:38,360 --> 01:07:41,440
Love is of no value without power and position.

696
01:07:42,460 --> 01:07:44,200
If I give the King a son,

697
01:07:44,200 --> 01:07:46,110
he will not bear the name "Bastard."

698
01:07:51,600 --> 01:07:53,900
What you suggest is treason.

699
01:07:54,320 --> 01:07:57,400
He cannot marry you. He has his Queen.

700
01:07:57,920 --> 01:08:00,140
Who cannot produce a male heir.

701
01:08:01,360 --> 01:08:04,220
You've reached too high, as always.

702
01:08:04,220 --> 01:08:06,110
The King will deal with Katherine.

703
01:08:06,340 --> 01:08:09,030
You'll hear about it from where I'm sending you.

704
01:08:10,040 --> 01:08:12,200
You are to go back to Rochford.

705
01:08:13,340 --> 01:08:15,330
Isn't that what you always wanted?

706
01:08:16,140 --> 01:08:20,650
A life in the country, alone with your child.

707
01:08:41,300 --> 01:08:43,660
Peter, over here. Fetch my lady's leg-warmer.

708
01:09:25,490 --> 01:09:27,540
Your sister is gone, as you wished.

709
01:09:28,300 --> 01:09:30,130
Will you give yourself to me now?

710
01:09:30,130 --> 01:09:33,610
No. When you are loyal to me above all others.

711
01:09:33,750 --> 01:09:36,010
- But I am. - No, you are loyal to the Queen...

712
01:09:36,010 --> 01:09:37,480
above all others.

713
01:09:37,530 --> 01:09:38,920
I barely see Katherine.

714
01:09:38,920 --> 01:09:41,010
But she sits on a throne beside you.

715
01:09:41,090 --> 01:09:42,840
Your right hand in matters of state.

716
01:09:42,840 --> 01:09:44,360
For appearances' sake only.

717
01:09:44,360 --> 01:09:49,050
Still, she is your Queen. And ever present.

718
01:09:50,870 --> 01:09:52,630
I feel her eyes on me.

719
01:09:53,890 --> 01:09:56,040
And those of her spies.

720
01:09:57,910 --> 01:10:02,550
Look at us. Forever reduced to meeting in secret like this...

721
01:10:02,560 --> 01:10:06,610
speaking in whispers. Hardly conducive to passion.

722
01:10:07,600 --> 01:10:09,470
Well, what would you have me do?

723
01:10:13,290 --> 01:10:16,310
We must now find a legal way around this instantly.

724
01:10:16,310 --> 01:10:18,980
The only way forward is by legal means.

725
01:10:18,980 --> 01:10:22,560
I don't care! I need to be rid of her.

726
01:10:22,570 --> 01:10:24,220
Find a reason.

727
01:10:25,890 --> 01:10:27,530
Wolsey has agreed to draw up plans

728
01:10:27,530 --> 01:10:29,240
to send the Queen to a nunnery.

729
01:10:29,970 --> 01:10:32,110
This will leave you all alone in court.

730
01:10:33,140 --> 01:10:34,990
Queen in all but name.

731
01:10:37,860 --> 01:10:39,770
Is this assurance enough for you?

732
01:10:40,470 --> 01:10:42,460
Will you give yourself to me now?

733
01:10:43,780 --> 01:10:45,060
My Lord.

734
01:10:46,190 --> 01:10:48,050
I desire nothing more.

735
01:10:49,700 --> 01:10:51,800
But as long as we remain unmarried...

736
01:10:51,970 --> 01:10:54,640
any child I gave you would be dubbed "Bastard."

737
01:10:54,640 --> 01:10:56,310
And I a whore.

738
01:10:56,310 --> 01:10:58,160
Do you really wish that for me?

739
01:10:58,160 --> 01:11:01,280
What alternative is there? Katherine is my wife.

740
01:11:02,200 --> 01:11:03,410
I really do not know...

741
01:11:03,410 --> 01:11:06,250
why we waste our time talKing of convents...

742
01:11:06,750 --> 01:11:09,490
when you could simply annul the marriage.

743
01:11:14,490 --> 01:11:15,620
Then you...

744
01:11:16,970 --> 01:11:18,460
my sweet Lord...

745
01:11:19,770 --> 01:11:21,690
will be free to remarry.

746
01:11:24,780 --> 01:11:27,330
And I could give myself to you fully...

747
01:11:29,200 --> 01:11:31,510
give you everything you desire.

748
01:12:28,000 --> 01:12:30,330
- Mary Talbot. - Who?

749
01:12:30,330 --> 01:12:31,750
Mary Talbot,

750
01:12:31,750 --> 01:12:33,790
Henry Percy's bride. Leave us.

751
01:12:37,800 --> 01:12:39,150
She has petitioned the King...

752
01:12:39,150 --> 01:12:42,120
demanding a divorce from her husband on the grounds...

753
01:12:42,470 --> 01:12:45,860
that his prior betrothal to you was actually consummated.

754
01:12:45,860 --> 01:12:48,390
I knew this would come to haunt us.

755
01:12:48,630 --> 01:12:50,730
- I must go to the King. - He doesn't want to see you.

756
01:12:50,730 --> 01:12:53,530
He doesn't want to hear a word. He won't even talk to me.

757
01:12:53,560 --> 01:12:55,310
The only Boleyn he'll talk to...

758
01:12:55,320 --> 01:12:59,430
the only person whose testimony he will trust, is Mary.

759
01:13:01,060 --> 01:13:04,210
Then bring her here. Now.

760
01:13:11,400 --> 01:13:13,510
You asked to see me, Your Majesty?

761
01:13:15,070 --> 01:13:17,140
The Queen is to be tried

762
01:13:17,140 --> 01:13:18,420
to test the validity of our marriage.

763
01:13:20,020 --> 01:13:23,170
Before I subject a good woman to such an ordeal...

764
01:13:23,450 --> 01:13:24,850
I need to be satisfied...

765
01:13:24,850 --> 01:13:28,680
that the woman I'm replacing her with is beyond reproach.

766
01:13:29,490 --> 01:13:32,590
This charge that Anne and Henry Percy...

767
01:13:32,620 --> 01:13:34,780
consummated their marriage...

768
01:13:35,410 --> 01:13:38,990
she denies it ever happened, but I need to be certain.

769
01:13:43,670 --> 01:13:45,170
Can I trust her?

770
01:13:47,320 --> 01:13:48,670
Why would you not?

771
01:13:50,800 --> 01:13:52,840
Usually, my instincts are sharp.

772
01:13:54,110 --> 01:13:55,490
But with your sister...

773
01:13:57,440 --> 01:13:59,130
she has a power over me.

774
01:14:07,710 --> 01:14:09,920
I'm asking you because I trust you.

775
01:14:11,050 --> 01:14:13,280
And because I believe, perhaps mistakenly...

776
01:14:13,280 --> 01:14:14,730
that you care for me.

777
01:14:16,420 --> 01:14:19,170
And that you would put a matter of this importance...

778
01:14:19,170 --> 01:14:21,080
before family ambition.

779
01:14:35,980 --> 01:14:38,400
I want to thank you for what you did today.

780
01:14:41,340 --> 01:14:43,380
I am forever in your debt.

781
01:14:44,280 --> 01:14:45,670
You owe me nothing.

782
01:14:47,130 --> 01:14:49,650
I did it as a peace offering between us...

783
01:14:50,460 --> 01:14:55,170
so we may finally draw a line beneath everything.

784
01:14:55,180 --> 01:14:57,220
Well, then let it be exactly that.

785
01:14:59,190 --> 01:15:02,510
A new start between us, here at court.

786
01:15:02,510 --> 01:15:04,780
Thank you, but I must return to the country.

787
01:15:04,780 --> 01:15:06,600
You would leave me here alone...

788
01:15:07,210 --> 01:15:09,210
when the Queen is going on trial?

789
01:15:10,110 --> 01:15:11,650
Out of the question.

790
01:15:13,780 --> 01:15:15,360
Out of the question?

791
01:15:17,170 --> 01:15:18,680
Stay here with me.

792
01:15:20,100 --> 01:15:21,430
Please.

793
01:15:22,700 --> 01:15:25,430
I need my sister here by my side.

794
01:15:42,120 --> 01:15:43,580
Crowds are with her.

795
01:15:43,770 --> 01:15:45,720
The crowds have no vote...

796
01:15:46,050 --> 01:15:48,360
and the bishops that do are in Wolsey's pocket.

797
01:15:50,360 --> 01:15:51,930
She's coming towards us.

798
01:15:57,430 --> 01:16:00,270
So...the Boleyn whores.

799
01:16:01,090 --> 01:16:02,960
Two former ladies of mine.

800
01:16:03,400 --> 01:16:05,210
What did I do to upset you...

801
01:16:05,210 --> 01:16:07,190
that you should turn against me like this?

802
01:16:07,190 --> 01:16:08,910
You failed to give England an heir.

803
01:16:08,910 --> 01:16:10,570
And that upsets you so?

804
01:16:10,570 --> 01:16:13,820
- What upsets the King upsets me. - How dare you?

805
01:16:15,060 --> 01:16:18,230
Katherine, Queen of England, come to court.

806
01:16:18,750 --> 01:16:21,300
You want me to creep away and become a nun?

807
01:16:21,490 --> 01:16:23,460
Well, I shall not.

808
01:16:23,750 --> 01:16:25,130
You want me to lie before God...

809
01:16:25,130 --> 01:16:28,010
and admit my first marriage was consummated?

810
01:16:28,110 --> 01:16:29,620
Well, it was not.

811
01:16:29,930 --> 01:16:32,960
You want me to retire and give up my daughter's claim...

812
01:16:32,960 --> 01:16:35,000
as sole rightful heir to the throne?

813
01:16:35,270 --> 01:16:38,610
Well, I shall not. Not in a thousand years.

814
01:16:38,610 --> 01:16:41,790
Not if you rack me to within an inch of my life.

815
01:16:43,120 --> 01:16:46,460
I am Katherine, Queen of England,

816
01:16:46,460 --> 01:16:48,020
the King's one true wife...

817
01:16:48,020 --> 01:16:50,220
and mother of the heir to the throne.

818
01:16:50,340 --> 01:16:53,840
Beloved of the people, and beloved of a King...

819
01:16:54,010 --> 01:16:55,740
you have bewitched.

820
01:17:25,100 --> 01:17:28,970
My Lord, how have I offended you?

821
01:17:29,340 --> 01:17:31,510
I have been a true, obedient wife.

822
01:17:31,810 --> 01:17:35,690
I have loved all those whom you loved and given you children...

823
01:17:36,070 --> 01:17:38,680
though it has pleased God to take them away.

824
01:17:39,500 --> 01:17:42,020
If there is any just cause against me...

825
01:17:42,380 --> 01:17:45,520
I will happily depart to my shame and dishonor...

826
01:17:46,280 --> 01:17:50,330
but I tell you, as God is my witness, there is none.

827
01:17:51,670 --> 01:17:54,620
So I beg you, dear husband,

828
01:17:54,620 --> 01:17:56,890
to spare me this humiliation.

829
01:17:58,320 --> 01:17:59,890
But if you will not...

830
01:18:00,520 --> 01:18:03,750
and you wish to challenge the validity of our marriage...

831
01:18:04,150 --> 01:18:06,700
then let it be in a proper court

832
01:18:06,930 --> 01:18:09,710
and by the only authority I recognize.

833
01:18:10,510 --> 01:18:14,270
His Holiness himself, the Pope.

834
01:18:29,800 --> 01:18:31,710
- It's a disaster. - Why?

835
01:18:31,940 --> 01:18:33,040
If the trial continues,

836
01:18:33,040 --> 01:18:35,400
the bishops will still find in the King's favor.

837
01:18:35,400 --> 01:18:37,260
Yes, but without the endorsement of the Pope,

838
01:18:37,260 --> 01:18:38,920
the result will be hollow.

839
01:18:39,070 --> 01:18:40,890
The people will never support it.

840
01:18:40,900 --> 01:18:43,200
Why does the King give Rome such power?

841
01:18:43,380 --> 01:18:45,810
He should simply take matters into his own hands...

842
01:18:45,810 --> 01:18:47,420
and annul the marriage.

843
01:18:48,080 --> 01:18:52,330
No, that would mean breaking with the Catholic Church.

844
01:18:53,040 --> 01:18:56,450
- His faith would never allow that. - Nor his good sense.

845
01:18:56,700 --> 01:19:00,110
Breaking with Rome would isolate England politically...

846
01:19:00,110 --> 01:19:02,320
and leave us at the mercy of the Protestants.

847
01:19:02,320 --> 01:19:05,250
But the alternative is leaving England without a male heir...

848
01:19:06,130 --> 01:19:07,730
and risking civil war.

849
01:19:07,870 --> 01:19:10,140
The very thing Henry fears most.

850
01:19:12,660 --> 01:19:15,110
Somehow, I need to make him understand...

851
01:19:15,110 --> 01:19:16,880
that this will be worth it...

852
01:19:17,380 --> 01:19:20,570
when I am his Queen and give him a son.

853
01:19:27,170 --> 01:19:28,380
I know you.

854
01:19:29,540 --> 01:19:32,900
You have decided but it grieves you.

855
01:19:34,170 --> 01:19:37,450
Will you destroy your marriage,

856
01:19:37,480 --> 01:19:38,710
your country, your soul before God...

857
01:19:38,710 --> 01:19:42,200
on the whim of one girl because she denies you?

858
01:19:42,790 --> 01:19:45,020
Because she tortures you with her refusal?

859
01:19:45,980 --> 01:19:48,780
You think she doesn't know exactly what she's doing?

860
01:19:49,210 --> 01:19:52,100
She wants me to step aside.

861
01:19:52,600 --> 01:19:54,540
Where is my wise husband?

862
01:19:55,550 --> 01:19:56,940
Where is he?

863
01:19:58,550 --> 01:19:59,850
You are a King...

864
01:20:03,220 --> 01:20:04,480
so be one.

865
01:20:44,350 --> 01:20:46,500
Now you will give yourself to me.

866
01:20:47,340 --> 01:20:49,440
I thought I had made myself clear.

867
01:20:49,750 --> 01:20:51,020
Until we're married, there's no ques...

868
01:20:51,020 --> 01:20:52,270
Damn you!

869
01:20:53,770 --> 01:20:56,800
I have torn this country apart for you!

870
01:20:56,800 --> 01:20:59,040
For which you should thank me, not be angry.

871
01:20:59,040 --> 01:21:00,240
Broken with Rome.

872
01:21:00,240 --> 01:21:03,420
Freed yourself from the decadence of a corrupt Church.

873
01:21:03,420 --> 01:21:05,120
I've got rid of a good woman in the Queen.

874
01:21:05,120 --> 01:21:07,060
A husk who failed you,

875
01:21:07,060 --> 01:21:08,960
whose Spanish blood shackles you to Rome.

876
01:21:08,970 --> 01:21:10,890
For which I will be excommunicated.

877
01:21:10,890 --> 01:21:14,060
And instead, become head of a new church...

878
01:21:14,350 --> 01:21:16,900
the Church of England. Closer to God.

879
01:21:16,900 --> 01:21:19,660
- Silence! Damn you. - Let go of me.

880
01:21:19,700 --> 01:21:21,170
You're hurting me.

881
01:21:23,180 --> 01:21:25,600
You'll show me it was worth my while.

882
01:21:58,320 --> 01:21:59,770
How was he with you?

883
01:22:03,630 --> 01:22:07,400
He was tender, surprisingly so.

884
01:23:17,260 --> 01:23:21,370
Witch! Witch! Witch!

885
01:23:21,370 --> 01:23:22,940
They're calling me a witch.

886
01:23:23,430 --> 01:23:27,060
It will all pass when they see how he adores you.

887
01:23:27,090 --> 01:23:28,300
Adores me?

888
01:23:40,040 --> 01:23:42,000
Mary. Mary.

889
01:23:43,740 --> 01:23:44,880
Mary, wait.

890
01:23:46,530 --> 01:23:48,050
I must tell you.

891
01:23:48,050 --> 01:23:50,410
I'm leaving court and your father's employment.

892
01:23:50,410 --> 01:23:51,720
I've seen enough.

893
01:23:53,570 --> 01:23:54,800
You and I both.

894
01:23:57,280 --> 01:23:58,700
I've saved some money.

895
01:23:59,770 --> 01:24:03,900
It's not much, but it's enough to keep you.

896
01:24:04,900 --> 01:24:06,320
To keep you safe.

897
01:24:07,210 --> 01:24:08,960
I have my eye on a place in Tatton,

898
01:24:08,960 --> 01:24:11,140
near where I grew up, in the west.

899
01:24:11,140 --> 01:24:13,300
- Stafford. - If you came with me...

900
01:24:13,300 --> 01:24:15,870
I would never betray you or take you for granted.

901
01:24:15,870 --> 01:24:17,600
It's impossible, you know that.

902
01:24:17,930 --> 01:24:20,560
- My family would never allow it. - And you would care...

903
01:24:20,690 --> 01:24:21,730
what they think,

904
01:24:21,730 --> 01:24:23,130
after everything they've done to you?

905
01:24:44,990 --> 01:24:49,960
Just one more. Just one more. Push. One more.

906
01:24:50,280 --> 01:24:52,660
Come on, Anne. Push, push.

907
01:24:54,710 --> 01:24:56,950
It's done. It's done, Your Majesty.

908
01:24:57,450 --> 01:24:58,590
Well done.

909
01:25:12,660 --> 01:25:13,730
What is it?

910
01:25:14,960 --> 01:25:16,380
What is it?

911
01:25:33,530 --> 01:25:34,610
It's a girl.

912
01:25:37,240 --> 01:25:39,130
A beautiful healthy girl.

913
01:25:42,220 --> 01:25:43,280
A girl?

914
01:26:33,390 --> 01:26:38,360
She has named her Elizabeth, after your mother.

915
01:26:41,680 --> 01:26:45,060
- Is the child healthy? - Perfectly, Sir.

916
01:26:58,550 --> 01:27:01,400
Well, if we can have a healthy daughter...

917
01:27:01,400 --> 01:27:03,030
we can have a healthy son.

918
01:27:26,390 --> 01:27:27,470
Who's he with?

919
01:27:32,490 --> 01:27:34,950
- Jane Seymour. - No.

920
01:27:40,000 --> 01:27:42,750
- How could he do this to me? - Anne, you need rest.

921
01:27:42,750 --> 01:27:45,540
If I do not produce a son, who will help me?

922
01:27:45,680 --> 01:27:47,980
Without a boy, he will pass me over.

923
01:27:48,280 --> 01:27:49,600
I will not let him.

924
01:27:58,870 --> 01:27:59,940
Elizabeth.

925
01:28:00,560 --> 01:28:01,930
How dare you?

926
01:28:03,400 --> 01:28:05,820
- Humiliate me like this? - Stop.

927
01:28:05,820 --> 01:28:07,750
- Why don't you just admit it? - Enough!

928
01:28:08,480 --> 01:28:10,740
There's a girl. There now, quiet.

929
01:28:10,740 --> 01:28:12,730
- I tell you, it's not true. - Liar.

930
01:28:12,730 --> 01:28:13,590
Leave me.

931
01:28:13,590 --> 01:28:15,300
I can smell the whore on you.

932
01:28:15,300 --> 01:28:18,060
Get away from me. You disgust me.

933
01:28:18,070 --> 01:28:19,020
Quiet.

934
01:28:23,610 --> 01:28:26,970
I struck him today. What am I doing?

935
01:28:27,560 --> 01:28:31,080
I'm destroying it all on my own. I can't sleep.

936
01:28:31,420 --> 01:28:34,620
- Without sleep, I cannot think. - Anne.

937
01:28:35,120 --> 01:28:37,940
It's getting more and more difficult to arouse him.

938
01:28:38,710 --> 01:28:42,160
Some nights, he cannot do it.

939
01:28:42,190 --> 01:28:46,320
I have to resort to evermore degrading...

940
01:28:46,920 --> 01:28:48,900
He hates himself in the morning.

941
01:28:49,420 --> 01:28:52,060
He hates me for what I made him do.

942
01:28:53,370 --> 01:28:57,290
It's slipping away and it's my fault.

943
01:28:57,890 --> 01:28:59,190
It's my fault.

944
01:29:12,420 --> 01:29:13,870
The Queen is with child.

945
01:29:22,210 --> 01:29:23,720
Anne, that's wonderful.

946
01:29:26,150 --> 01:29:27,260
Take care now.

947
01:29:34,470 --> 01:29:37,670
The Queen is with child but the situation is delicate.

948
01:29:37,770 --> 01:29:40,910
So your concern has just cause

949
01:29:40,910 --> 01:29:42,790
but keep your counsel for now.

950
01:29:44,180 --> 01:29:46,130
This pregnancy is precarious.

951
01:29:46,130 --> 01:29:49,260
If it is a boy, then the Boleyns will be untouchable.

952
01:29:51,080 --> 01:29:54,570
But if it is a girl or a stillborn...

953
01:29:55,560 --> 01:29:58,730
then they and everyone connected with them will perish.

954
01:29:58,730 --> 01:30:00,350
And that includes you.

955
01:30:00,500 --> 01:30:03,010
So you and I need to work together, Jane.

956
01:30:21,950 --> 01:30:24,960
I'm fine. I'm fine, thank you.

957
01:30:26,360 --> 01:30:27,810
Just a bad dream.

958
01:30:30,580 --> 01:30:32,590
You fetch my brother and sister, will you?

959
01:31:13,440 --> 01:31:14,600
I lost it.

960
01:31:17,810 --> 01:31:19,390
Almost without pain.

961
01:31:21,320 --> 01:31:22,720
And so quickly...

962
01:31:24,890 --> 01:31:26,530
as if it never was.

963
01:31:32,610 --> 01:31:33,880
Get rid of it.

964
01:31:34,750 --> 01:31:38,890
Bury it. Get rid of it somehow. On the fire with it.

965
01:32:28,740 --> 01:32:30,040
I feel his eyes on me.

966
01:32:30,780 --> 01:32:34,720
Staring at me, wondering why I do not show.

967
01:32:34,800 --> 01:32:36,430
You haven't told him?

968
01:32:38,020 --> 01:32:42,380
Well, soon the truth will be out, that I cannot bear children.

969
01:32:44,040 --> 01:32:47,320
He will have me burned as a witch.

970
01:32:47,430 --> 01:32:50,490
But there's still time. You could yet fall pregnant.

971
01:32:50,490 --> 01:32:53,060
He won't lie with me and risk damaging the child...

972
01:32:53,060 --> 01:32:54,520
he believes I'm carrying.

973
01:32:55,950 --> 01:32:56,940
No.

974
01:33:02,890 --> 01:33:04,430
Must I spell it out?

975
01:33:06,370 --> 01:33:08,700
But lying with another man would be treason.

976
01:33:21,310 --> 01:33:23,660
Stop it. Anne, it's madness.

977
01:33:23,660 --> 01:33:25,510
No, don't you see? You're my only hope.

978
01:33:25,510 --> 01:33:27,400
- I can't listen, it's monstrous. - Mary.

979
01:33:27,400 --> 01:33:29,070
No. Come, George.

980
01:33:29,070 --> 01:33:30,100
George, please?

981
01:33:31,520 --> 01:33:33,290
My life depends on it.

982
01:33:40,050 --> 01:33:42,010
May God have mercy on you both.

983
01:34:47,080 --> 01:34:50,640
I can't. I'm so sorry.

984
01:34:52,350 --> 01:34:54,400
I just can't. I just...

985
01:34:57,360 --> 01:34:58,690
I'm so sorry.

986
01:35:03,220 --> 01:35:04,730
I'll tell the King in the morning.

987
01:35:07,400 --> 01:35:09,250
Let's pray he takes pity on me.

988
01:35:13,990 --> 01:35:17,890
I saw them. The two of them.

989
01:35:23,390 --> 01:35:24,410
Yes?

990
01:35:27,270 --> 01:35:29,450
Fetch my belongings and bring them to Rochford.

991
01:35:45,190 --> 01:35:49,370
Your Grace. Lady Rochford is here to see you.

992
01:35:51,780 --> 01:35:52,930
Not now.

993
01:35:53,450 --> 01:35:57,390
She has news of her husband, George Boleyn, and the Queen.

994
01:36:02,330 --> 01:36:03,470
What is it?

995
01:36:52,060 --> 01:36:53,770
I couldn't help it, My Lord.

996
01:36:55,040 --> 01:36:57,860
- I beg you, have mercy on me. - You witch.

997
01:36:58,320 --> 01:37:01,930
- No, My Lord. - You cursed, evil witch.

998
01:37:01,930 --> 01:37:02,900
Why?

999
01:37:04,110 --> 01:37:05,340
He came early.

1000
01:37:07,320 --> 01:37:08,430
Our son.

1001
01:37:09,160 --> 01:37:11,830
- There's no blame in that. - No.

1002
01:37:12,460 --> 01:37:15,270
Then what? What else have I done?

1003
01:37:15,270 --> 01:37:16,340
Guards.

1004
01:37:16,930 --> 01:37:19,000
- My Lord? - Guards!

1005
01:37:25,490 --> 01:37:27,050
Please, please. No, spare me, please.

1006
01:37:27,320 --> 01:37:30,020
Please. Please, I beg you, spare me.

1007
01:37:30,020 --> 01:37:33,080
I've done nothing wrong. Please, no.

1008
01:37:47,570 --> 01:37:51,410
My children. My children.

1009
01:38:00,530 --> 01:38:02,920
Look what you have done.

1010
01:38:56,120 --> 01:38:57,560
It's a sad day for England

1011
01:38:57,560 --> 01:38:59,970
when nobles do not rise for their Queen.

1012
01:39:00,220 --> 01:39:02,390
And even sadder when that same Queen...

1013
01:39:02,390 --> 01:39:05,830
is charged with adultery and incest.

1014
01:39:05,830 --> 01:39:09,510
Charged is not convicted, uncle.

1015
01:39:09,510 --> 01:39:11,970
Or is it in this court?

1016
01:39:14,810 --> 01:39:18,290
Master Cromwell, read out the indictment.

1017
01:39:19,930 --> 01:39:21,510
The charge is that

1018
01:39:21,640 --> 01:39:24,910
in the 28th year of the reign of our sovereign Henry...

1019
01:39:24,930 --> 01:39:28,310
King of England, his wife, the Queen...

1020
01:39:28,630 --> 01:39:30,890
being seduced by the Devil...

1021
01:39:33,200 --> 01:39:37,470
did knowingly commit incest, high treason...

1022
01:39:37,950 --> 01:39:40,240
and offenses against God.

1023
01:39:41,080 --> 01:39:42,370
How do you plead?

1024
01:39:43,540 --> 01:39:45,290
Not guilty, My Lord.

1025
01:39:49,090 --> 01:39:51,630
The love I have for my brother

1026
01:39:51,630 --> 01:39:54,160
is the natural love any sister...

1027
01:39:54,160 --> 01:39:56,450
would have for someone with whom she's grown up...

1028
01:39:56,580 --> 01:40:00,510
nursed when sick, played with as a child.

1029
01:40:02,450 --> 01:40:06,460
Judge me, My Lords, but never forget...

1030
01:40:07,020 --> 01:40:08,850
your verdicts will be judged

1031
01:40:08,850 --> 01:40:12,930
by God in the greatest court of all.

1032
01:40:14,170 --> 01:40:16,830
My Lords,

1033
01:40:16,830 --> 01:40:19,490
the time has come to pass judgment.

1034
01:40:30,240 --> 01:40:32,580
- Guilty. - Guilty.

1035
01:40:32,940 --> 01:40:35,650
- Guilty. - Guilty.

1036
01:40:36,010 --> 01:40:39,020
- Guilty. - Guilty.

1037
01:40:41,720 --> 01:40:44,470
- Guilty. - Guilty.

1038
01:40:44,680 --> 01:40:47,530
- Guilty. - Guilty.

1039
01:40:47,780 --> 01:40:49,010
Guilty.

1040
01:40:54,850 --> 01:40:55,890
Guilty.

1041
01:41:19,920 --> 01:41:22,040
No, no, no.

1042
01:41:22,040 --> 01:41:24,850
No, no, no!

1043
01:41:25,080 --> 01:41:27,500
Please, please, you must believe me.

1044
01:41:28,850 --> 01:41:31,220
You must believe me.

1045
01:41:31,860 --> 01:41:34,720
I've done nothing, please. Please, My Grace.

1046
01:41:37,020 --> 01:41:40,200
The Lord is my shepherd. And thy Kingdom will be free...

1047
01:41:41,360 --> 01:41:44,900
to meet in green pastures

1048
01:41:44,900 --> 01:41:47,560
and he leadeth me to a great lord.

1050
01:41:47,560 --> 01:41:49,000
He quicken my soul,

1051
01:41:49,000 --> 01:41:50,440
he bringeth me in the path...

1052
01:42:05,060 --> 01:42:06,140
Leave us.

1053
01:42:10,200 --> 01:42:11,380
All of you.

1054
01:42:22,990 --> 01:42:24,190
Your Majesty.

1055
01:42:25,730 --> 01:42:28,270
I'm told I'm too late for my brother, George.

1056
01:42:32,300 --> 01:42:33,380
I beg you.

1057
01:42:34,180 --> 01:42:35,580
Spare my sister.

1058
01:42:37,450 --> 01:42:39,310
I understand she has offended you.

1059
01:42:39,310 --> 01:42:40,970
You wish to replace her as Queen.

1060
01:42:40,970 --> 01:42:42,260
But must she die?

1061
01:42:43,010 --> 01:42:45,400
She has been tried and found guilty.

1062
01:42:46,920 --> 01:42:49,050
You could send her away. No one would know.

1063
01:42:49,150 --> 01:42:50,830
Why are you here for her?

1064
01:42:52,010 --> 01:42:54,150
You have put yourself at great risk.

1065
01:42:56,590 --> 01:42:58,350
Because she's my sister...

1066
01:42:59,970 --> 01:43:02,020
and therefore one half of me.

1067
01:43:05,150 --> 01:43:06,790
And I would do nothing...

1068
01:43:07,250 --> 01:43:09,150
to hurt any part of you.

1069
01:43:18,240 --> 01:43:19,330
Go.

1070
01:44:12,220 --> 01:44:13,280
We didn't.

1071
01:44:14,160 --> 01:44:16,400
George and I, we...

1072
01:44:24,080 --> 01:44:25,530
The guards are letting them in.

1073
01:44:26,800 --> 01:44:27,990
You'll be spared.

1074
01:44:28,700 --> 01:44:30,860
The King as good as gave me his word.

1075
01:44:32,680 --> 01:44:33,860
He saw you?

1076
01:44:39,210 --> 01:44:41,150
They say he's with Jane Seymour now.

1077
01:44:43,020 --> 01:44:44,080
Is it true?

1078
01:44:45,980 --> 01:44:47,000
No.

1079
01:44:49,640 --> 01:44:50,750
Thank you.

1080
01:44:52,550 --> 01:44:53,970
A generous lie.

1081
01:44:58,970 --> 01:45:00,160
Will you hold me?

1082
01:45:02,890 --> 01:45:04,540
You'll look after Elizabeth?

1083
01:45:05,530 --> 01:45:08,020
It won't come to that, I promise.

1084
01:45:08,340 --> 01:45:09,510
I promise.

1085
01:45:11,170 --> 01:45:12,630
He'll keep his word.

1086
01:45:12,970 --> 01:45:14,320
I know he will.

1087
01:46:33,540 --> 01:46:34,690
Masters.

1088
01:46:36,880 --> 01:46:38,980
I here humbly submit to the law...

1089
01:46:40,580 --> 01:46:42,400
as the law has judged me.

1090
01:46:46,060 --> 01:46:47,760
As for my offenses...

1091
01:46:49,160 --> 01:46:50,460
God knows them.

1092
01:46:51,390 --> 01:46:53,050
And I remit them to God...

1093
01:46:53,560 --> 01:46:56,060
beseeching him to have mercy on my soul.

1094
01:46:58,430 --> 01:47:00,030
I beseech Jesus...

1095
01:47:00,600 --> 01:47:02,290
save my sovereign...

1096
01:47:02,860 --> 01:47:04,960
and master, the King.

1097
01:47:05,850 --> 01:47:07,000
The goodli...

1098
01:47:07,810 --> 01:47:09,220
The goodliest...

1099
01:47:09,820 --> 01:47:13,520
and gentlest master... ...there ever was.

1100
01:47:17,450 --> 01:47:18,600
My Lady.

1101
01:47:27,340 --> 01:47:31,130
Mary, you risked your life coming to court...

1102
01:47:31,710 --> 01:47:34,580
and were only spared because of my respect...

1103
01:47:34,580 --> 01:47:36,260
and affection for you.

1104
01:47:37,480 --> 01:47:39,760
You are advised not to do so again.

1105
01:47:40,860 --> 01:47:44,180
You will not be shown the same clemency a second time.

1106
01:47:45,750 --> 01:47:47,530
May God bless you...

1107
01:47:48,350 --> 01:47:49,770
and my son.

1108
01:47:51,240 --> 01:47:53,670
And may God have mercy on Anne's soul.

1109
01:48:33,960 --> 01:48:37,200
Sweet Jesus, I commend my soul to thee.

1110
01:49:39,110 --> 01:49:40,930
Mother, hand me the child.

