http://subscene.com/u/659433
Improved by: @Ivandrofly
(MUSIC)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
MARK: Hello.
Thank you for giving me
the opportunity to talk to you today.
My name is Mark Schultz.
I wanna talk about America,
and I wanna tell
you why I wrestle.
This is an Olympic gold medal.
I won this three years ago
at the 23rd Olympic Games
in Los Angeles, California.
This is more than just
some piece of metal.
It's about what the metal
represents.
The virtues it
requires to attain it.
Twenty dollars and zero cents.
Is it Dave or David?
No, it's Mark.
Mark Schultz.
Um...
Yeah. Dave's my brother.
Oh. He was originally scheduled.
Okay.
We both won golds.
MAN 1: Make it
the works, and coffee.
- MAN 2: For here?
- WOMAN: Yes.
MAN 2: Number two,
number three, here.
MAN: Please come, coach.
We don't want to put
any pressure on you right now.
- You gotta think it through and all that.
- DAVE: No, I get it. I appreciate it.
That's why I didn't wrestle him.
But didn't you miss that match?
I missed that match.
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
DAVE: Hey, Mark.
You know the guys from U.S.A.
Wrestling.
Mark, how's it going?
Fred, Bruce, Greg.
BRUCE: Hey, Mark.
Well, all right. All right.
- Just give us a call.
- DAVE: Appreciate it, Bruce.
Thanks for coming all this way.
Okay. All right.
- FRED: Hey, have a good workout.
- DAVE: Thank you.
Hey, buddy.
You all right?
Hey, you been calling
my machine and hanging up?
What? Come on.
What do you mean?
Somebody's leaving hang-ups
on my machine. Come on.
Come on.
How you doing, buddy?
You all right?
Okay.
Mark. Come on.
Keep your hips in.
Keep your hips in, Mark.
(DAVE GRUNTS)
DAVE: Heh.
(BLOWING NOSE)
(GRUNTING)
Same time tomorrow? Yeah.
What'd the U.S.A.
Wrestling guys want?
We're talking about me
doing some coaching.
In Colorado.
Hey. Give me a hug.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(BEEPING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
JACK ON PHONE: Hello. May
I speak with Mark Schultz?
Speaking.
Mark Schultz,
the Olympic wrestler?
Yeah. Who is this?
I'm calling on behalf of Mr. John E.
Du Pont.
He has been anxious
to get in touch with you.
Who? John E. Du Pont
of the du Pont family.
Mr. du Pont asked that you
consider taking a day off
to come out to Foxcatcher Farms,
so you men can
meet face-to-face.
About what?
He'd like to discuss it
in person in Pennsylvania.
If I may, I'd like to make travel
arrangements for you, Mr. Schultz.
First class, of course.
Who'd you say again?
John E. Du Pont,
of the du Pont family.
WOMAN OVER PA: Welcome to Philadelphia
International Airport.
Mark, Mr. du Pont wanted
to fly you himself today.
But last minute, he got called
in by the Newtown Square Police Department.
For tactical support.
He should be back at the estate
by the time we get there.
By the way, that's Valley
Forge below you.
This is the library.
Mr. du Pont should be
here in a few minutes.
MARK: Okay.
JOHN: Mark.
John du Pont.
Thrilled. Thrilled
that you're here.
Let's go downstairs.
We call this the trophy
room, for obvious reasons.
Have a seat.
How was your flight?
It was good. Good.
Thank you.
Can I get you something
to eat or drink?
Oh, no. No, I'm good. Thank you.
I could have them whip
you up something.
No, sir, I'm fine.
Good.
Well, I know how busy
you must be.
I assume you're training for the Worlds?
Yes, sir.
Good.
It's a big one.
How is training?
It's good. Um...
It's intense.
We're in two-a-days.
Conditioning and weights
in the morning
and technique...
We wrestle in the evenings.
That's good. Get
yourself prepared.
Work hard.
You look good. You look strong.
Fit. Thank you, sir.
Feeling confident?
That's one of the most important
elements of entering a match
is feeling the confidence, knowing
that you're going to win.
Feeling it inside.
If you go to a match knowing
that you're going to win that match,
odds are you're going
to win that match.
You're training
with your brother Dave?
Yes, sir. Great Dave Schultz?
Yeah. I'm talking
to the great Mark Schultz.
Do you have any idea why
I asked you to come here?
No. No.
Well, Mark, do you...?
Do you have any idea who I am?
No. No.
Some rich guy calls
you on the phone.
"I want Mark Schultz
to come visit me."
Well, I'm a... I'm
a wrestling coach.
And I have a deep love
of the sport of wrestling.
And I wanted to speak
with you about your future.
About what you hope to achieve.
What do you hope
to achieve, Mark?
Well, I wanna be
the best in the world.
I wanna go to Worlds
and win gold.
I wanna go to the '88 Olympics
in Seoul and win gold.
Good.
I'm proud of you.
Are you getting the support
that you need?
What do you mean, sir?
Well, you know how the Soviets
support their wrestlers.
I do.
Mark, we as a nation have
failed to honor you.
And that's a problem.
Not just for you,
but for our society.
When we fail to honor
that which should be honored,
it's a problem.
It's a canary in a coal mine.
Do you bird-watch?
Uh, no. You can learn
a lot from birds.
I'm an ornithologist.
But more importantly,
I am a patriot.
And I want to see this
country soar again.
I want that too.
I can see that.
(DOOR OPENS)
I'd like us to go
to Seoul, stun the world.
What do you think?
(MUSIC)
JOHN: Three
thousand men died here.
These patriots were willing
to give up everything...
including their lives...
for freedom.
I like to come here to remind
myself what really matters.
We're going to do
great things, Mark.
Great things.
Yes, sir.
♪ Can you answer? ♪
♪ Yes I can ♪
♪ But what would be the answer ♪
♪ To the answer man? ♪
Hey, Mark. Hey.
Can I talk to you for a second?
Hey, Mark. Yeah.
Can I talk to him?
Go on.
XANDER: Here!
Do something.
The country has lost their morals
and values, and the kids are lost
and they don't have role
models, and I agreed with him.
Hm. Everything he was saying.
I couldn't believe he was saying stuff
that I... It was in my head all the time.
Did you guys talk...?
Did you talk money?
Yeah, yeah. What's he talking?
You ready? Yeah.
Twenty-five thousand a year.
He said, "Name your price"
and I just said the highest
price in my head.
And we get to handpick our team.
Who are you gonna train with?
No. No, we're...
I meant "we" as in me and you,
together, picking a team.
Mr. du Pont and I would love
to have you.
(CHUCKLES)
Mark, what's, uh...?
What's he get out of all this?
Mr. du Pont? Yeah.
America winning.
You winning. We
talked about you.
Me winning.
Okay. What are you
thinking about, Dave?
This is it.
This is everything that we've...
That we've ever wanted.
Mark, I can't leave.
I'm settled here.
Nancy's happy.
Xander's doing well at school.
They can come.
Mark,
I got a contract,
I got commitments.
That's great for you.
I should just pass this
up to be your training partner?
Mark. Mark.
This could be a real
good thing for you.
I'm proud of you.
I think you can make something
real good for yourself here.
Yeah? Yeah.
I love you, Mark.
(MUSIC)
Hi. Is, uh, Mr. du Pont home?
Is Mr. du Pont expecting you?
Yes, ma'am.
Not at this exact moment, but,
you know, this week sometime.
I'm Mark Schultz.
Have a seat here, for a moment.
I need to...
Do you have a commode?
Or, like, a washroom
or something I could use?
Just in there to the left.
Thank you.
(URINE TRICKLING)
Mr. Beck will see you now.
I'm... I'm sorry. Who?
All right. How old
are you, Mark?
Twenty-seven.
Education?
University of Oklahoma.
Undergraduate?
And you graduated?
Yes, sir.
Do you own any property, Mark?
No.
Are your parents still together?
How old were you
when they separated?
Two.
Who raised you?
Well, we moved around a lot.
But my brother, mainly.
Okay.
Mark, have you ever
been accused of a crime?
No, sir.
I...
Mr. du Pont. Oh, you're here.
Yes, I drove straight down.
Tonight's speech.
Okay.
So they're putting
him in the chalet?
BECK: Yes, sir. Hm.
Excellent bed.
Good mattress. Firm.
- That's great. Thank you.
- JOHN: All right.
Good.
Utilities are paid for,
gas, electric, water.
Kitchen, dining room.
Refrigerator is fully stocked.
Office.
Here's a key for you.
Thank you.
The gym is close. You
can almost see it.
Couple hundred yards
up is the big house,
in case you ever get
invited to dinner.
Otherwise, it is off-limits.
Okay.
Also, the horses that you
saw on the way in,
they all belong to Mr. du
Pont's mother.
They're all world-class animals.
They're also off-limits.
Your history of the du
Pont dynasty.
One more thing:
Just between you and me,
if you happen to see Mrs. du
Pont, just give her her privacy.
Yeah, of course.
Anything else I can get you?
No. No, no, I'm fine.
Well, I think that's it.
Have a good night.
You too.
MAN ON VIDEO: Du Pont,
a dynasty of wealth and power.
America's need for ammunition
enabled the family
to amass a fortune
and grow their company
into what is today
the largest chemical
corporation in the world.
(FIREWORKS EXPLODING AND
MUSIC PLAYING ON VIDEO)
Mr. du Pont? Shh-shh-shh.
(OWL HOOTING)
Do you hear that?
That's a barred owl.
I hope it's not too late.
No, no, no.
I wanted to make sure
that everything was all right.
That everything was fine. Drop a few things
off that I thought you might enjoy.
Here are some field glasses.
There are many varieties of birds
right here on the property.
That'll give you a better
vantage point. Okay.
And this is from 10 years ago, but I thought
you might find it interesting.
Wait, you wrote this?
I did, yeah.
Thank you.
How long do we have
till the Worlds?
Two months. Well,
a little less, actually.
Well, we'll get it done.
I promise you, I'll give
you everything I have.
I have great faith in you, Mark.
Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
Night.
(MUSIC)
JOHN: Certainly Abraham
Lincoln, Teddy Roosevelt,
they gave me something
to aspire to.
My father was a role model.
MARK: Guys, introduce yourself.
See you guys at 6?
All right.
(MUSIC)
JOHN: Very good, I'll see
you in three months.
Good.
Mark.
Come in.
Have a seat.
May I get you a drink?
No. No, sir. I'm good.
Good. Good man. In training.
How is it looking
with your brother Dave?
Dave?
How do you mean?
You said you were going
to talk to him again.
I did.
When is he coming?
He's not.
He... He's just not...
He's just not willing
to uproot his family.
Does he understand
what we're doing here, Mark?
I told him.
He just really
doesn't wanna move.
How much does he want?
No, it's...
It's not about that.
About what?
Well, you can't buy Dave.
So the World Championships
are coming up soon?
Yes, sir.
I want you to win.
That's why you're here.
(MUSIC)
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
Everything okay, Mark?
Yeah.
What is it?
What's wrong?
Nothing. I'm... I'm fine.
No, you're not.
I just...
I just don't wanna let you down.
(MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY
AND CROWD MURMURING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
DAVE: Do it! Go!
That's it.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
MAN: Attack! Attack! Control his rolling.
Control his rolling.
DAVE: Keep your elbows in!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(APPLAUSE)
ANNOUNCER: Mark Schultz.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Good job, Mark.
(MAN SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
ANNOUNCER: Dave Schultz.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(WHISTLE BLOWS AND CROWD CHEERING)
XANDER: Hello. Hey, Xander.
Hi. Where's your dad?
Over there. Hello.
- DAVE: Hey, Mark. Come on in, buddy.
- XANDER: Yah!
DAVE: Oh, God, he's got me.
Dave, I wanted to... I want
you to meet Mr. du Pont.
DAVE: Hold on a sec. We got a guest.
I gotta get up.
- How you doing? I have to say hi.
- DANI: Keep him...
No. We're not letting you up.
DAVE: I wanna say hi to Mr. du Pont.
Hold on.
- How you doing?
- DANI: Dad, come on.
It's nice to meet you. Dave Schultz.
John du Pont.
DAVE: That's my wife, Nancy.
Hey.
- Hello.
- DAVE: My beautiful, relaxed children.
- This is Xander and Dani.
- DANI: Hello.
- XANDER: Hi.
- DAVE: They're eating me.
NANCY: Hey, Dani?
Dani, come here.
DAVE: Can I get you a drink?
No. No, I should go.
Good luck tomorrow.
Mark, thank you.
MARK: You sure you don't want to...?
No, no.
- No, Mark, stay.
- NANCY: I'm gonna get you.
DAVE: Come here.
Get your brother.
- Hey. Okay. It's bedtime now.
- DANI: I can make an A.
- No.
- DAVE: Let's go.
- NANCY: Here it comes.
- DAVE: Get ready for bed.
Dave, I got that tape on Nanev.
Yeah, pop it in, buddy.
- We need to check out his arm spin.
- DAVE: We'll watch some wrestling.
Get your arm up. Get
your arms out of there.
There we go.
- DANI: Hurry up. Let me go!
- NANCY: I'll have to keep you here.
- DANI: No.
- NANCY: Let me get these tights off.
- Good princess.
- XANDER: Okay, get...
Was it too much for you to come
over and just say hi to him?
XANDER: Aren't they fun?
Excuse me?
You know who that is?
It's John du Pont.
- I said hi, Mark.
- MARK: It's John du Pont.
The most generous man in America. You
can't treat him like he's anyone.
DAVE: Mark, she said hi.
Mark, I said hi, okay?
DANI: She said hi. You
said hi from over there.
Buddy. Mark.
- She said hi, pal.
- NANCY: Mark.
- You're in our room.
- MARK: I'm in your room? Okay. All right.
Great. You know what?
You don't even know.
You don't even know what you don't know.
You know that?
NANCY: Dave? Dad.
Mark. Why? Dad.
- DANI: No.
- NANCY: Yes.
- XANDER: Dad.
- DAVE: Buddy.
Mark.
Buddy. Come here.
Come here.
Give me the tape. Okay.
Nanev can't set up his arm spin
without setting up himself.
You just hit yours first. When
you feel him drive, hit it.
All right?
He's gonna drive
and turn you and...
DAVE: There it is.
That's it. Drive him out.
Drive him out.
Drive him.
Drive, drive!
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(APPLAUSE)
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(MUSIC)
(CROWD CHEERING)
DAVE: Elbows deep, Mark.
Drive! Drive!
Five seconds, Mark!
Drive him. That's it.
Drive him, drive him, drive him!
Pop him up!
Yeah!
That's it, buddy!
Yeah! Yeah!
CROWD CHANTING: U.S.A.!
U.S.A.! U.S.A.!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(DAVID BOWIE'S "FAME" PLAYING)
JOHN: Oh, there we go.
Who needs a refill?
Let's all get very drunk.
MAN: Can I take a look at your medal?
Yeah. Yeah.
What a fantastic evening.
♪ Fame, makes a man ♪
♪ Take things over ♪
♪ Fame, lets him loose ♪
♪ Hard to swallow ♪
♪ Fame, puts you there ♪
♪ Where things are hollow ♪
♪ Fame ♪
♪ Fame, it's not your brain ♪
JOHN: All right. All right.
Enough. Enough!
Turn that off.
Take that down.
(MUSIC STOPS)
- MAN 1: Where do you want me to put it?
- JOHN: I don't care.
Throw it away.
All of it, whole shelf.
Horses are stupid.
Horses eat and shit.
That's all they do.
(LAUGHS)
It's very silly.
It's all very silly.
Hove my mother very
much, but she...
She... It's...
It's ridiculous.
Sitting on an animal
was more dignified.
(LAUGHS)
But I wanted to do
what you're doing.
Let's have those medals.
Give me those.
Give me those medals.
I do not share my mother's affection
for horseflesh,
I'll have you know.
"Did your horse jump
over the thing?"
"Did you catch the fox, Mother?"
Anyway,
the proof is in the pudding.
We caught the fox, didn't we?
MAN 2: Yeah. This is the fox.
MAN 3: Yes, sir.
I am going to put
these in there.
Gentlemen, I give
you Mark Schultz,
Foxcatcher world champion.
Yes. Good.
(APPLAUSE)
Oh!
Whoa, whoa, coach.
- MAN 4: You all right?
- MARK: Get him up.
- MAN 5: Coach, you all right?
- MAN 6: I think he had too much to drink.
ALL: Oh!
(ALL LAUGHING)
- MAN 1: Drive! Drive!
- MAN 2: Drive, drive!
- MAN 3: Get on his other side.
- MAN 4: Get on him.
- MAN 5: Push him.
- MAN 6: Come on. You got him.
- MAN 1: What?
- MAN 2: The jig's up.
Climb up on him. Come on. Come on.
Work him, work him, work him!
(ALL CHEERING)
MAN 1: Yes!
ALL: Whoa!
MAN 2: Don't let him drive you, Dan.
Don't let him drive you.
MAN 3: Turn him. Come on, turn him.
That's it.
- MAN 4: You gotta turn him. Yes!
- MAN 5: Turn him. Turn him.
Yes!
- MAN 1: John!
- MAN 2: Johnny D!
ALL CHANTING: John!
John! John!
John!
John! John! Yeah!
(GUNFIRE)
(SQUAWKING)
- MAN 1: Yo, Johnny D!
- MAN 2: Yeah, Johnny D!
(ALL CHEERING)
MAN 3: Yeah! Whoo!
(GUNFIRE)
Mark.
After practice, I want you to shower
and come talk to me, all right?
MARK: Yeah. All right.
(GUNSHOT)
JOHN: Three hundred eighty-seven
days to Seoul, gentlemen.
Let's have a good
practice, shall we?
You don't have to do this.
You earned it.
You've given me enough.
This is not necessary.
Mark, Mark, you earned that.
Thank you. You're welcome, Mark.
You're more than Dave
Schultz's little brother, Mark.
Okay.
Dave Schultz
is a wonderful wrestler.
He, I'm sure, has
been an inspiration to you.
A mentor to you.
But he will always be
your older brother.
He will never let you
be everything that you can be.
Mark, you have been living in your brother's shadow
your entire life.
It's time. It's your time now.
I know what you mean.
Do you?
Because everything
that I've done,
I feel like...
has somehow
been credited to Dave.
And, you know, I feel that...
it's time for me to...
distance myself from him.
You know, become my own person.
Without your brother...
you can do anything that you
choose to set your mind to.
Mr. du Pont, I need you
to know that I'm...
I'm so grateful
for what you've done for me.
Well, first of all,
I don't want you to call me "Mr.
Du Pont" or "sir" anymore.
I consider us friends.
And most of my friends will call
me "Eagle" or "Golden Eagle."
So either of those will work.
Okay.
Or "John" or "Coach."
All right. That's not a problem.
Good.
Good afternoon, sir.
M113, sir. APC.
I know what it is.
Where's the gun?
What gun, sir?
Fifty-caliber machine gun. Sir,
there wasn't a machine gun ordered.
It's supposed to be
mounted right there.
There's no gun
on the order, sir.
Sir, I just need a signature
to complete the order.
Get my gun.
Reed, McClaren, let's off-load.
JOHN: It's supposed to come with a.
50-caliber machine gun.
We'll get it.
You hungry? Yeah.
JOHN: Let's get
something to eat.
MARK: You snap him down.
He'll posture up,
that's your window.
Shoot in and pull
him over the top.
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(MUSIC)
Excellent.
One more.
Great.
The oil looks really
good on you, Mark.
Bow your arms a little bit.
Here we go.
Excellent.
Very good, and all right.
Very good, Mark.
Your speeches, your kit.
Do we know if my mother
has already arrived?
She is en route, sir.
The blazer looks good.
Thank you, sir.
I wrote down a few things
for you to say.
Don't be nervous.
You're gonna be great.
Read it. Read it out loud.
MARK: Okay. Right now?
Get some practice. Yes, sir.
"Highly respected
ornithologist,"
author, world explorer,
"phil... Phila..."
JOHN: Philatelist. Philatelist.
Stamps. Sta... Can
we say "stamps"?
No, philatelist. Philatelist.
Don't be intimidated
by these people.
How many people
are gonna be there?
About 400.
(SNIFFING)
(JOHN CLEARS THROAT)
Go ahead.
What is it?
It's cocaine.
Uh... I'm not sure
that's such a good idea.
Mark, it's just cocaine.
It's not going to kill you.
What am I...? You're
supposed to just...?
Take the vial,
tap some on the mirror,
take the straw, just inhale
it through your nose.
"Highly respected ornithologist,
author, world explorer,
philatelist and former
pentathlete."
All of that? All of it.
Straight down.
"Mr. du Pont will be making
his return to competitive sports
in the over-50 category
of the masters..."
Did you hear how I was doing it?
It's just all one thought, Mark.
(COUGHING)
You got it.
Give that to me.
MARK: Okay.
"Highly respected
ornithologist, author,
world explorer, philatelist".
JOHN: Philatelist.
Philanthropist. Philanthrop...
Which one...?
JOHN: Ornithologist. Which
one do you want to come first?
JOHN: Ornithologist,
philatelist, philanthropist.
MARK: Okay, ornilo... Ornithologist,
JOHN: Ornithologist,
philatelist, philanthropist.
Ornilo... Ornithologist, philatelist...
Ornithologist, philatelist, philanthropist.
MARK: Ornilo...
"Ornithogolist"...
Ornithologist, philatelist, philanthropist.
Ornithologist...
Ornithologist, philatelist,
philanthropist. Look at me.
BOTH: Ornithologist,
philatelist, philanthropist.
JOHN: Again.
BOTH: Ornithologist,
philatelist, philanthropist.
JOHN: Again.
BOTH: Ornithologist,
philatelist, philanthropist.
JOHN: Good.
(MUSIC)
JOHN: Do I know you?
- MAN: Yes, John. How are you?
- JOHN: Good to see you again.
This is Mark Schultz. Hi.
JOHN: Have you ever met
an Olympic gold medalist before?
Mark won the Olympic gold
medal for wrestling in 1984.
Ever seen an Olympic
medalist before?
No, I don't think I have.
JOHN: Mark. Mark.
This is Congressman Daniel.
Nice to meet you.
Bob. Congressman Daniel...
Bob or Daniel?
Bob, yes. Bob, nice to meet you.
This is Mark Schultz.
Mark won an Olympic gold
medal in the 1984 Olympics.
Impressive. Isn't
that impressive?
Congratulations. Thank you.
Quite a young man.
Very proud of him.
Nice meeting you.
MARK: I'm so proud
to introduce my mentor.
He has the ability to look at me
and see where I am in life.
I feel his love for me as an athlete
and as a human being.
My mother and father were
divorced when I was 2.
And I spent a lifetime
looking for a father,
and I found one in the Golden
Eagle of America, John du Pont.
Mark Schultz. Thank you, son.
Hello, Mother.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I would like to read something.
"The liberties of our country,"
the freedom of our civil
constitution,
are worth defending
at all hazards.
"And it is our duty to defend
them against all attacks..."
(MUSIC)
(DIALPAD BEEPING)
(BEEPING)
MARK: Oh, hey. Hey, what's up?
I miss you.
Yeah. What you up to?
Huh?
What you up to?
Nothing. Nothing.
Are you working out?
Getting ready?
Yeah... No. I mean, well, I'm taking
a little bit of a break right now.
Just resting up the body. I'm
gonna ramp it up, you know,
when it gets closer to World...
Trials.
All right. How close?
Hey, hold on. Hold on one second.
What?
What's happening?
(PHONE BEEPS)
(CAR HORN HONKING)
Hey!
Mark!
Gear up. Practice
in the gallery.
(MARK PANTING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTING)
(BOB DYLAN'S "THIS LAND
IS YOUR LAND" PLAYING)
♪ As I went walking ♪
♪ That ribbon of highway ♪
(HAIR CLIPPER BUZZING)
♪ I saw above me ♪
♪ That endless skyway ♪
♪ I saw below me ♪
♪ That golden valley ♪
♪ This land was made ♪
♪ for you and me ♪
♪ This land is your land ♪
♪ This land is my land ♪
♪ From California ♪
♪ To the New York island ♪
♪ From the red wood forest ♪
♪ To the Gulf Stream waters ♪
(SNIFFING)
♪ This land was made ♪
(COUGHING)
♪ For you and me ♪
You all right?
Huh?
You are a good friend, Mark.
Thank you, John.
I only had one real
friend growing up.
Hugh Cherry. Hughby.
He was the son
of my mother's chauffeur.
Uh-huh.
When I was 16, I found
out that my mother had been paying him
to be my friend.
Dave was my only friend
growing up.
Yeah.
(CHUCKLING)
(MUSIC)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(MUSIC)
I thought we could put
it in the Rosemont case.
It says John "Eagle" du Pont.
That's right.
First place? Yes.
You funded this.
Presumably.
You can put it
in the trophy room.
Thank you, Mother.
What are we going to do
about your train set?
My train set?
Well, Mr. Beck spoke
to you about this.
No.
Oh, I know he did.
I know he did.
You've never wanted
to give it away, but...
I don't care about my train set, Mother.
I don't care.
Well, I think we'll...
We'll give it to the children's museum,
if they have room.
Do you agree?
I don't care what you
do with the train set.
I don't care about trains.
Mother, I am leading men.
I am training them.
I am teaching them.
I am giving them...
a dream.
And I am giving America...
hope.
Hope?
It doesn't matter.
I'm glad you have your trophy.
It can go in the trophy room.
Not in the Rosemont case.
I don't like the sport
of wrestling, as you know.
It's a low sport.
And I don't like to see
you being low.
(CROWD CHEERING ON TV)
MAN 1 (ON TV): And quickly
Herrera shoots the leg.
MAN 2: And Herrera's a very
good grappler here.
MAN 1: Oh, my. Elbows
in number, by Goodridge,
and that is it.
GARCIA: Albert wrestled
with this guy at Pitt.
I think it's sad.
He was legit.
BEN: He's probably
getting paid a lot.
HANK: Look at his face.
- MAN 1: That was short and sweet.
- HANK: It's destroyed.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
- HANK: It's John.
- BEN: It's John.
- Hey, coach.
- JOHN: Is Mark in?
HANK: Yeah. Right here, coach.
What's up?
Why is there nobody in the gym?
What do you mean? It's noon.
Nobody in there.
Yeah, no, I gave the boys the morning off.
We're gonna do a double tonight.
JOHN: Who's making
these decisions?
I am.
I want your brother Dave here.
What are you talking about?
I want your brother
Dave to come.
Um, that's not gonna happen.
We've talked about that.
Are you okay?
You ungrateful ape.
I made such a mistake
bringing you here.
I'm getting Dave.
I don't care how much it costs.
Shit.
(MUSIC)
(HAIR CLIPPER BUZZING)
Hey. Hi, guys.
Yeah.
MAN: There he is. He's coming.
He's coming.
- John du Pont.
- JOHN: Yeah.
Thanks. Yeah.
(INDISTINCT DIALOGUE)
Hey.
How you doing?
Good. I'm good.
What's up?
I just... Just came in. All
the wrestlers were there to meet me
and you weren't there,
and I just thought I'd come up,
make sure everything's okay.
No, I'm good.
Just concentrating.
We got trials coming up.
You okay, Mark?
Yeah. I'm good.
What's up?
You got my messages?
Mm-hm.
Nancy and the kids are here.
Yeah? How are they?
They're good.
Why don't you come down and say hi.
Okay. I will. I'll see you.
DAVE: Boom, down low.
This hand comes here, this
hand catches the ankle.
Lay your back into the guy, scoop
with this leg, catch both knees,
put your arm through.
There's your cross ankle, all right?
Nice and tight.
Do it again, all right?
So you're here,
you're wrestling.
If you get here and you're
loose like this,
to make it nice and tight, what you
wanna do is drive the knees together
with your hip and your elbow, and drop
your arm down or drop your chest.
That'll make it nice
and snug for you.
You wanna keep your outside leg
away from him.
Keep your leg away from him,
come up to your knee,
turn your toe to the ceiling,
step him up.
Let's say he does reel
over with that outside ankle,
that's pretty much game over.
I have a chance to make
him keep those feet...
So from here, you pull this
up and you drive that.
Outside shoulders
from that, and he pulls...
Use your stomach.
(CLANKING)
JOHN: Good.
Good set.
All right, pair up.
Let's go, guys.
What's going on, Mark?
There's that knee pick he likes
to hit from a fake shot or cross...
Dave, I don't need your help.
I'm doing this on my own, okay?
You don't want my help?
Dave, what did I just say?!
Wanna tell me what's going
on with you and du Pont?
Okay.
DAVE: Handstands.
Tuck and roll forward, boys.
Army crawl on this side.
Good.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
JOHN: Bring it in.
Move.
Right there. Make some room.
All the way over.
In three days,
several of you will be
traveling with me to Pensacola
to participate
in the Olympic trials.
When you leave the hallowed grounds
of this training facility...
you will be in competition.
You will be representing
Foxcatcher.
the United States.
As a coach,
I want you to be
champions in sport...
and winners in life.
And also...
to be good citizens...
for America.
Garcia.
A couple basics.
This is one that generally
works for me quite well.
Arm drag.
Right to left, left to right.
Rip it across.
And as I do that, you
see this portion.
And I can move right in.
Again.
Right to left, left to right.
Rip it across.
And then in.
Got it? Yeah.
- Do we have that?
- GARCIA: Yes.
JOHN: All right, par terre.
Down. Actually, I'll go down.
- You do it.
- GARCIA: Okay.
JOHN: Do it on me.
So get underneath my rib.
All right.
(JOHN GRUNTING)
The basic physics is to keep
yourself wide at the bottom.
All right.
He puts his knee under my hip,
and you see an opening here.
So you shoot...
Let's pair up.
- Basics.
- MAN 1: All right.
DAVE: All right, let's pair
up and work on arm drags.
Arm drags and gut wrenches.
MAN 2: All right,
let's do it, guys.
Three days, three days.
- OFFICIAL 1: Step forward.
- OFFICIAL 2: All right, name, weight.
He's good.
OFFICIAL 1: All right, you got about a...
Looks like about a half a kilo to go.
- Step forward.
- OFFICIAL 2: Name, weight?
- MAN 1: Thirty.
- OFFICIAL 1: He's good.
- OFFICIAL 2: Next.
- OFFICIAL 1: Step forward.
- Name? Weight?
- OFFICIAL 2: Let's see.
That's about a half kilo to go.
- OFFICIAL 1: You're good.
- OFFICIAL 2: Next.
OFFICIAL 1: He's good.
Step forward. Name, weight?
OFFICIAL 2: Good.
Next bastard's good.
Next.
Two kilos over.
- OFFICIAL 1: That looks good.
- OFFICIAL 2: You're good.
- Next. OFFICIAL
1: Step forward.
- ANNOUNCER: Next match: Mark
Schultz versus Rico Chiapparelli.
(APPLAUSE)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(MUSIC)
REFEREE: One, blue.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(GRUNTING)
(MUSIC)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(BUZZER SOUNDS AND WHISTLE BLOWS)
(MUSIC)
(APPLAUSE)
Best of three, Mark.
You'll get it back.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SOBBING)
(PHONE RINGING)
(THUMPING AND BANGING ON DOOR)
Mark.
DAVE: You're not
in this alone, man.
I'm your brother and I love you.
I am not gonna let you
go down like this.
That's it.
(RETCHING AND VOMITING)
There's more in there.
(COUGHING)
That's it, keep going, Mark.
Twelve pounds over.
How much time we got?
OFFICIAL: Ninety minutes.
Ninety minutes, okay.
Come on, there you go.
That's it, drive it.
Harder, Mark.
That's it. Time.
DAVE: Okay. All right.
Five, four, three, two, one.
Time.
Three, two, one.
(MUSIC)
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
DAVE: All right, buddy.
Go.
(BICYCLE PICKING UP SPEED)
(MUSIC)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
DAVE: Circle.
Hold your position, Mark.
Ten seconds.
Hold your position.
(BUZZER SOUNDS AND WHISTLE BLOWS)
All right. All right, Mark.
MAN WHISPERING: Sheets
can't be on the team.
Mark Schultz
is on the Olympic team.
DAVE: Get in there,
Mark, you hear me?
REFEREE: Okay, center
red, center blue.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(GRUNTS)
DAVE: Yeah!
Two-thirty, Mark.
(MUSIC)
(APPLAUSE)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Hey, Henry. Dave. What
can I do for you?
Henry, John and I kind of had
an uncomfortable moment earlier
and, you know, I didn't
see him at the finals.
Was he even there? No.
Mr. du Pont flew
home earlier today.
Okay.
Mr. du Pont's mother died.
Oh, man. That's really bad news.
Excuse me, Dave. All right.
Thank you.
(MUSIC)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
MAN: Would you like us
to mount the weapon?
JOHN: Yes. Gentlemen.
(MUSIC)
DAVE: You and me, buddy.
How you doing?
You sore?
There you go.
Open that stretch for me.
It's John.
Hey, John.
I'm really sorry about your mother.
Oh, no, no, no. It's fine. It's fine.
You okay?
You sure? Yes.
David, we have a lot of work to do
in the next couple of months.
And you're an integral part of that.
You understand?
I understand. I'm
going to need you.
And I will be relying on you.
DAVE: All right. To a great extent.
I want,
More than anything,
to win a gold medal.
And we have someone
who could do that for us.
We're gonna win
a gold medal, John.
How are you feeling about that?
I feel very good about it.
I am a little concerned
that there
are some psychological issues
that we need to take care of.
He's gonna be in real good shape.
You're doing a great job.
- DAVE: Thank you, John.
- JOHN: And I...
I think that with you
and I, working in tandem,
if we can't get him
there, no one can.
All right. Get back.
Okay.
JOHN: Mark?
Mark?
- You okay?
- JOHN: Mark.
He's okay.
Come on, Mark.
JOHN: Good.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
(MUSIC)
BECK: Coach du
Pont has a vision.
He would like Foxcatcher
to be designated and recognized
as the official training site
for U.S.A. Wrestling
and the Olympic team.
Now, this means that the national
team would live here and train here.
On top of funding this program,
Coach du Pont would be willing to make
a donation to U.S.A. Wrestling
of $500,000 per year.
- MAN 1: That's fantastic.
- MAN 2: Yeah, that's really nice.
Mr. du Pont, thank
you very much for...
JOHN: The spirit of Foxcatcher.
It is a philosophy
which began generations ago.
- Thank you.
- JOHN: It is more than just sport.
And coaching these
young athletes,
I am able to instill in them the lessons
that I have learned in life.
Athletes need role models.
Like anyone, they need
people to look up to.
A coach is a father.
A coach is a mentor.
A coach has great power...
great import
on an athlete's life.
We'll put you in a house
with another wrestler.
Gym's a hundred yards from it.
There's plenty of places
for the kids to run around.
(DOOR THUMPS)
Hey, Mark, I'll just be...
All right. I'll tell
her you said hey.
I'm waiting to hear from you.
Bye.
Hey, buddy.
Hey. Warm up. I'll be
out there in a minute.
Yeah, I just... I gotta
make one more call.
Look.
I don't wanna be here.
I called Coach Beacham at BYU.
He said he'd take both of us.
We don't got time to make
a big change like that.
Okay, what about after Seoul?
Mark...
Look, I don't know what's gonna
happen in the future,
but Nancy
and I would like to try
and make it work here.
You and I both know
that I can't stay here.
I know, Mark.
Hey, do you remember
when we were kids?
You remember how we lived?
Moving all over the place?
Never had any idea where or how long
we were gonna be anywhere.
Remember how that was for us?
Was it easy for us?
No.
That's my responsibility
to my family, Mark.
I know you understand that.
Keep your head
in the game, Mark.
Go on down.
Hi, Dave, I'm Doc.
DAVE: Doc, Dave Schultz.
Nice to meet you.
Have a seat in the chair
here, if you would.
We're rolling.
Let's talk a bit
about his philosophy as a coach.
What is his philosophy as the individual
that's gonna lead this team and you?
Well, John's philosophy as a coach
is to let the wrestlers...
Um...
Sorry.
Is to, um, create an environment
where, uh, the athlete
doesn't have many obstacles
to get past to be great.
Let's get pointed here. I... I'm
not doing what you want me to.
Let's get pointed. What
are you looking for?
You know what we're
trying to accomplish.
We're making a documentary that shows
John is gonna be able to lead this team,
lead you to levels of greatness
in wrestling we haven't seen before.
And talk about that, but use
some of those terms that he likes,
like "excellent" and "intensity"
and "domination."
(LAUGHS)
All right.
Well, John du Pont...
Say that again? I'm sorry. Can
you ask me that question again?
John sees you as important to this.
You're the closing chapter to this thing.
You're the end of it,
and you're his assistant coach.
He sees himself as your mentor.
I would like you to just
look at the camera
and speak about John...
as a mentor.
And say what exactly?
That he's your mentor.
Can you do that?
John du Pont...
is kind of a mentor to me.
Just look over here
at the camera and say it again.
(CLEARS THROAT)
John du Pont is a mentor to me.
BECK: I thought maybe it'd be a good idea
if we talked, kind of clear the air.
I wanna make sure you guys
are clear that we expect
that Mr. du Pont is gonna be in Mark's corner
throughout the Olympic Games.
Well, we can ask him
if that's okay, but first,
I'd like to raise a few things
that are important to me.
One, if I'm gonna...
commit to staying
on here at Foxcatcher,
I need to know that Mark's gonna
be taken care of.
Well, taken care of how?
So long as I'm at Foxcatcher,
Mark's gonna get paid.
You want him to be paid
even if he's not here?
Yeah, that's pretty much it.
BECK: Dave, you may be overestimating
your importance to Foxcatcher.
DAVE: Well, that may be so.
We could test that, but I'm
here to say, John,
I wanna continue what we've started
here at Foxcatcher.
And it's important to me
that I know that my brother
is gonna be supported.
(MUSIC)
Thanks, John.
BECK: Okay, you'll get your deal,
you'll get your demands,
but this means that Mr. du Pont
is gonna be seated in Mark's corner
throughout the Olympic Games.
I wanna hear Mark agree
to that himself.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(MUSIC)
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(MUSIC)
Remember what we went
over today, Mark.
You can't do this to yourself, buddy.
You can't do this to yourself.
You can beat this guy, Mark.
You can beat him.
(MUSIC)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(BUZZER SOUNDS AND WHISTLE BLOWS)
(MUSIC)
Can I help you?
- Everything okay?
- MAN: Can I help you?
- Uh, yeah, we live here.
- MAN: Okay.
There's a new security plan in place.
I'm gonna need to see some IDs.
DAVE: Sure.
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(MUSIC)
Hey, John, it's Sunday.
It's family time.
NANCY: Morning, John.
Say hi to John.
XANDER: Hi, John.
It's Sunday.
(MUSIC)
JOHN ON TV: Every athlete, no
matter what sport, needs structure,
needs direction,
and this is something
that a coach can offer.
As a coach, I hope
to develop young athletes,
not only in body, but in mind.
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYS ON TV)
JOHN: I want you to be champions
in sport and winners in life.
And also, good
citizens of America.
You will be representing
Foxcatcher.
the United States.
The coach is there
to help the athlete succeed
in all the ways that that athlete
should be able to succeed.
And in doing so
that coach is able
to create a champion.
(APPLAUSE ON TV)
My athletes look to me
as a brother, a mentor,
a father and a leader.
I spent my lifetime
looking for a father,
and I have found one in the Golden
Eagle of America,
John du Pont.
(APPLAUSE ON TV)
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING ON TV)
(CLICK)
Wayne.
Yes, sir?
Is it snowing?
No, it's not.
Warm up my car.
Yes, sir.
Hey, John. What's happening?
Hey, whoa!
WAYNE: No. Do you have
a problem with me?
WAYNE: John. Don't, John. No,
John, I don't have a problem.
Hey, John... Argh!
WAYNE: John, no!
Stop, John. Stop!
(DAVE GRUNTING)
John, no!
(GUNSHOT)
(DAVE GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT AND DAVE SCREAMS)
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(MUSIC)
- COP 1: Freeze! Drop the gun!
- COP 2: Drop it now!
(GRUNTING)
(CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(MUSIC)
(CROWD CHEERING)
MAN: Mark.
You're up.
ANNOUNCER: He is a jujitsu fighter,
standing 6 feet, 2 inches tall,
weighing 225 pounds.
From Moscow, Russia,
Vladimir "The
Prototype" Milstead.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(MUSIC)
Ladies and gentlemen,
fight number three
on our six-bout card
features a matchup
with this freestyle wrestler
out of Lindon, Utah.
Standing 5 feet, 10 inches tall,
weighing in at 203 pounds,
he is a three-time NCAA
and three-time world champion,
1984 Olympic gold medalist.
Please welcome,
Mark Schultz!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(MUSIC)
CROWD CHANTING: U.S.A.!
U.S.A.! U.S.A.!
U.S.A.!
(MUSIC)
http://subscene.com/u/659433
Improved by: @Ivandrofly