- Here.
- Shit.
Come on. Hurry up.
Got it?
Shh.
Let's go shopping.
I'm a firm believer in karma.
And I think this situation was attracted into
my life as a huge learning lesson for me..
to grow and expand
as a spiritual human being.
I want to lead a huge charity organization.
I want to lead a country
one day, for all I know.
Girls, time to get up!! Let's go!!
Come on, girls.
Oh, my Lord.
You were so out of control last night.
What about you?
You were all over that old manager guy.
Girls!!
Time for your Adderall.
What time did you guys get home last night?
- Uh, late.
- Mmmmm?
- And you know it's a school night.
- We know.
Yeah? Okay.
Well, let's do our morning prayer, okay?
And then, at 8:00, we'll meet
in the living room for today's lesson.
Okay? Does that sound good?
- Mm-hmm.
- Let's go.
Okay.
My chief aim in life
is to continually strive..
to be the best person that I can be
for the greater good of the planet..
and everyone who walks on it.
And so it is.
- And so it is.
- Whoo!!
- Have a good first day, Marc.
- Thanks.
- Hope you like it here.
- Oh, my God.
- Who's that?
- Yeah.
- Really.
I told her.
What did I tell you?
Whatever.
Take a seat.
Soldier boy. No, he's just a soldier.
I don't know what that is.
What?
Watch it. Loser.
Bye.
- Hey, new kid.
- Hey.
- You got Jamis for English?
- Yeah.
He's the worst. He's a real perv.
Oh, okay. I'll watch out. Thanks.
- Where you headed?
- Gym. Where's that at?
It's down here.
- Where you from?
- Agoura Hills.
- But I was away for a year, so did home school.
- Bummer.
How'd you end up in the dropout school?
Well, I got kicked out of my last school
for having too many absences, so-
You know. What about you?
For having substances
you're not supposed to have at school.
See you around.
See ya.
Hey. Want to come to the beach
after school?
MJG, bitch
I got 8 balls
9 piece, straight 8 balls
MJG, bitch
I got 8 balls
Suave house, still independent
Distribution Mexican
He still sending
Shoe box
No shoes in 'em
In the two-seater,
me and two women
I just have to graduate so I can go to FIDM.
Fashion Institute of Design.
It's where all The Hills girls went.
Cool.
And then intern at Teen Vogue?
Totes, and then have my own line
and fragrance, host my own show.
Yeah.
I'd like to have my own lifestyle brand.
Definitely.
- Yo, Chloe, what's up?
- Yo, bitch.
- Going to, uh, Carly's later?
- Uh, maybe.
- Right. I'll see you guys.
- Right.
My morn and her douchey
husband are out of town..
if you guys want to come over later.
Yeah.
- I could be down.
- Cool.
I can't wait to get out of here.
I want to live in New York eventually.
- Yeah, me too.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Cool.
That's so cute.
I love that dress. I love Chanel.
Yeah, and the shoes,
but she needs better hair extensions.
- I know, right?
- Yeah.
- Are those Prada?
- Miu Miu.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Wow.
- So, is your mom away a lot?
- Yeah, she goes on trips a lot for work.
Oh, really? For what?
She has a chain
of student tutoring centers.
And you're at Indian Hills?
I know. Exemplary student, right?
So, what do your parents do?
Well, my mom doesn't work, and my dad
works for a film distribution company.
Hmm.
Yeah, they do a lot of work
overseas and stuff, so-
That's so cool. He's in the biz.
Yeah, it's pretty cool. I mean,
I get to go to screenings and stuff, so-
- Nice.
- Yeah.
- Do you want to check some cars?
- What's that?
Come on.
What are you doing?
- Shh.
- Sweet.
Come on.
- Check that side.
- I heard something.
- It's locked.
- Okay. Come on.
It's locked too.
Shit. it's open.
- No way.
- Let's go.
- That's crazy.
- I know.
People leave 'em open
with credit cards and cash.
Look, Marc. We got, like, 400 bucks.
Oh, yeah.
How did you meet Rebecca ?
I met Rebecca in school after
I'd moved back and went to Indian Hills.
Urn, I went there
'cause I had a lot of absences.
I didn't want to go to school. I had
a lot of self-loathing and anxiety issues.
- I thought that I was ugly.
- You're not ugly.
I know I'm not ugly. I just-
I don't know. I never saw myself
as an A-list-looking guy.
Um, but I went to Indian Hills
to learn and be with my peers.
But I was always self-conscious that I wasn't,
you know, as good-looking as other people.
Want a ride?
Hey, where we going?
Wherever we want.
Okay.
Do you know anybody that's out of town?
Um-
Yeah, this kid Evan.
His family went to Jamaica. Why?
I went into an unlocked house
a few weeks ago..
- found a bunch of cash.
- Oh, shit.
- Where does Evan live?
- Woodland Hills.
How well do you know Evan?
I mean, we met up a few times.
He's pretty hot.
It's a nice place.
Fuck. We need to get out of here.
It's fine. Don't freak out.
It's a Birkin.
Great.
Lindsay has this one.
I think we need to get out of here.
Oh, yeah.
What is it?
No way.
What the fuck?
Get in.
Fuck!!
Where'd you get the keys?
I got them on the way out.
How long's Evan in Jamaica?
This is so cute.
Yeah.
- You need a pair of these.
- Perfect.
Would this be good on me?
This would look so good on you.
What do you think about this?
Oh, my God. That looks so cute.
Oh, no.
- That's disgusting.
- How about this?
That's amazing.
- Right?
- Yeah. Look at 'em.
Perfect.
Picture.
Hurry UP-
Yo, Rob!! What's up?
- Hey, Chloe. Chloe, come on in.
- Is Rick inside?
- Yeah, yeah. He should be around.
- For sure.
When's he coming?
- Yo, sluts!!
- Chloe!!
What's this?
- My homey Marc.
- Hey.
- Hi, I'm Nicki. This is Sam.
- Hi.
- We used to go to school with them.
- Are they sisters?
No, they've known each other
since they were, like, three.
They took Sam in.
I don't know what happened to her mom.
Oh, my God.
Jude Law totally keeps texting me.
I'll probably meet him later.
Yeah, I bet you're really
gonna hesitate on that one.
- Bitch, you're just jealous.
- Suck my dick.
You did text him, like, 50 times.
- I did not!!
- Yeah, you did.
Really?
That's Kirsten Dunst.
Come on, Chloe.
Where's that bottle service?
- Let's get that going.
- Working on it, bro.
Girls.
- Ricky.
- Hey, baby.
- You good?
- Mm-hmm.
- You guys have everything you need?
- Yeah.
Hey, Nicki. There's some photographers
out here for fashion week.
- I think you might want to meet them.
- For sure.
And we got some huge music manager coming,
some executive producer from Entourage.
It's gonna be a real party salad
tonight, right, so..
- let me know if there's anything you need.
- Check with you later.
Okay.
Oh, my God. That's Paris Hilton.
Yeah. She's here a lot.
- Take a picture.
- Sure.
- Hey. Ready?
- Right.
Yeah.
- Come on!!
Look at Sam.
- What is she doing?
- I don't know.
Drinks up.
I literally thought I was gonna die.
- Homey.
- Yo, bitches.
- Dog, what's up?
- Thought you might want one.
Oh, you're the best. I love your shirt.
Thank you.
I'll see you later, okay?
I loved her.
I really did.
She was the first person
I felt like was my best friend.
I loved her almost like a sister.
That's what made this situation so hard.
Okay, this morning's lesson
is on character development.
So in The Secret,
we talk about the law of attraction..
and how we need to be really careful about
who we surround ourselves with..
because we wind up being
the average of those people.
So we are going to make vision boards..
about people who are demonstrating
good character..
like Angelina Jolie.
So, what qualities do you guys
admire about Angelina Jolie?
Her husband.
Mm-hmm. Okay.
- Anything else?
- Her hot bod.
Okay. Okay.
Well, the hot bod is not a characteristic.
- But- Okay?
- How long do we have to do this for?
Well, we're gonna do it until we finish..
and then we're gonna move on
to the ď¬‚uorescence work.
Got it.
Okay.
Water delivery.
Come in.
- Where do you want this?
- Hi. The kitchen.
Okay. Back to work.
Mischa Barton got a DUI.
Really? Wow.
Paris Hilton's hosting
a party in Vegas tonight.
Where does she live?
Can you find her house?
Um-
2342 Briar Summit Circle.
Let's go there.
Do you think we could find a way in?
Uh, looks like you get in
going up this hill by her house.
I bet she'd leave her keys under her mat.
Awesome!!
Oh, my fucking gosh!!
It's her pet monkey. Hi, little guy.
Okay. Come on.
Holy shit.
- Marc.
- Huh?
That's amazing.
Let's go upstairs. Come on.
- Come on.
- Okay.
- Oh, my God.
- I know, right?
No way.
Wow.
- Becca, I don't-
- Oh, my God.
Wow.
- Come on. Let's get the fuck out of here.
- It's fine.
Let's keep going.
Come on.
Look at her sunglasses.
These are Alexander McQueen.
Come on.
Whoa.
Oh, my God.
I know, right?
She has so much stuff.
It's amazing.
- We gotta go.
- Take a picture first.
- Come on.
- Then we're leaving.
Fine. Ready?
That's cute. Let's go.
All right.
- It's her nightclub room.
- Come on. Let's go.
Don't trip out. it's fine.
Oh, my God!! No way.
I totally want to go to Paris's.
Yeah, it was sweet.
We hung out in her nightclub room.
I got this.
- Oh, my God!!
- Isn't that beautiful?
That's so ill!! OG motherfucker!!
- Damn!!
- No way. How did you get in?
Dude, her key was under the mat.
We just walked in. It was so fucking chill.
- Under the fucking mat.
- You just walked in?
- Just walked right in.
- Holy shit!!
- Just right in.
- To Paris Hilton's house?
Yeah.
And the best part is we can all go back.
We just have to check
when she's going out to something.
Lindsay got another DUI.
- Wow.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Surprising.
Try this with it.
Yes!!
What do you think?
Try it with your hair back.
Oh, yeah. That looks classy.
I wouldn't go that far.
- Leopard and zebra?
- What?
Yeah, you can't have leopard and zebra.
You gotta choose one.
Okay, fine. Whateves.
At least I don't look like I'm 35.
- Oh!! Damn.
- Harsh.
Come on. Let's go to Paris's.
I want to rob.
I didn't know what' they were doing.
I thought they were my friends.
It all comes back to, like, bad choices..
who you have as your friends.
And I know the truth will come out.
See? Look.
Okay. So, these are her sunglasses,
and that's her bathroom..
and there's her closet.
Um-
- Check out the bathtub.
- Oh, my-
- Wait, wait, wait. Let's see what's behind here.
- I love bathtubs.
- Oh, my God.
- She likes mirrors.
- She likes mirrors. She likes herself.
- Oh, my God!!
- Holy shit!!
Genius.
- Oh, my God.
- Damn.
This is so sick!!
- It is insane.
- Wow.
Whoa!!
Look at all her Louboutins.
- Oh.
- Her feet are so big.
I know. What size is this? 11?
- These are amazing.
- Seriously?
Oh, my God.
Do you think they'll fit?
Not me. Probably you.
Oh, my God!!
- Yo, dude, she's got her own line.
- So hot though.
- Look.
- That's crazy.
- "Paris Hilton."
- Oh, look. The bags are really cute.
Ooh, leopard. Ah!! Move.
No, no, no, no.
Oh, baby, I'll take these.
I'll take the Loubies.
- Oh. That's right.
- Can't wear 'em though.
Ladies. Excuse me.
Oh, my God!!
- Ooh, hey, baby.
- He looks hot.
Wow. if only the guys
could see you at school now.
- Wait. No. Come back. Come back.
- Guys. Guys. Guys. Come here.
- What?
Guys, look.
Sweet. Guys. Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God.
- Look at this!!
Holy shit!!
- No way. No way.
- Chloe. Chloe.
- Right?
- Oh, damn!! That's perfect.
- Ooh!!
- Look. Check it out.
- It's good.
- Guys, they have real diamonds.
- Hey, guys. She has real diamonds.
- Dinner's on me.
No, no, no, no.
It's on me. it's on me.
- We got it, we got it, we got it.
- Oh, shit!!
Look. Pulling hundreds, hundreds.
Oh, my God. So good.
- Don't drop it!!
- Look at these. Look at these.
- Wait, wait, wait. Let me see.
- We could sell these.
- Shit!!
- Ooh. That one's weird.
Dude, look at these!!
- Ew!!
- Oh, my God.
- Ew. What's all over her?
- A lot of bronzer.
- Oh, my God. This is amazing.
- I like the feel of this.
- It's so good.
- Oh, my God. This is Balmain.
So cute.
Wait.
It's so cute. Oh, my God.
- Check it.
- Meow.
This is Herve Leger!!
- What?
- Oh, my God. I love it.
She's got leopard. Yes. Yes!! Yes!!
- That's really hot.
- Leopard.
- Oh, my God.
- No. That's mine.
- Yes, yes. No, it's mine.
- Mine.
- Green doesn't look good on you.
- You won't fit in here.
You know it doesn't look good on you.
- Oh, my God. There's another one.
- Good. Then take it.
Why does she have two?
- Oh, my God. Ew!! Ew, ew, ew, ew, ew!!
- What? What?
Come on.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
All right. In a second.
Wait. We have to show them
the nightclub room first.
Rebecca, I don't think-
Maybe not this type of pole.
- On!!
- on!!
Wait. Go down, go down, go down.
- Yes!!
- Whoo!!
Oh!!
Party foul!!
That was a mistake.
- Nice. That was hilarious.
- Fill it up, and we're-
Whoo!!
Yeah, sexy bitch!!
Shh, shh.
- Fuck.
- Careful. Careful.
- Everybody. Hey.
- What?
Let's toast this to-
- Paris Hilton.
- To a great fucking night!!
Whoo!!
I'll be right back.
No. I'm just driving.
L- I don't know.
- Dude, just keep going.
- Where are we going?
- Just keep going straight. We'll find it.
- The car is a mess.
- Stop messing with the car.
- It opens and closes.
- Oh, God. Just go straight.
- Shut up.
You're blind to everything.
You got your own little
dance party going back there.
I know. it's awesome.
Live fast, die young
Bad girls do if well
My level was off the charts.
It was crazy.
They didn't know how I was driving,
let alone still alive.
- That's fucked-up.
- Yeah.
I have to pick up trash for fuckin' forever.
- That sucks.
- What are you guys doing later?
I don't know.
There may be a party at Madison's.
- I'll let you know.
- Bye.
Drop it, drop it low, girl
Come on, Peter Pan.
- You can't take her dog.
- But he likes me..
and I could get, like, 500 for him.
Come on, Becca. You can't take her dog.
- It'd be too noticeable anyway.
- Okay. I guess.
Bye, Peter Pan.
- Shit!!
- Security. Shit.
Maybe over by the garbage can.
Damn it.
Keep going. Keep going.
Fuck!!
- Oh, my God.
- I got nothing over here.
No, negative. Come on, man.
Go around the corner.
I'm gonna check the street.
- Are they gone?
- Shh.
Come on. Come on.
What?
Shit.
- Shut the fuck up!!
- What?
Tum up the lights in here, baby
Extra bright, I want y'all to see this
Turn up the-
- Hate me in that order
- Oh!!
Public visitation
We met' at' Borders
Told her she take me back,
I 'll be more-
- Whoo!!
- Wipe your nose.
Baby, please, can't let her grow up
in that ghetto university
All of the lights
Fast life, drug life, thug life, rock life
Every night
- Gonna let these- know
- Yeah
- Ger it right
- Baby
Go and get your-
Get it right, baby
What are your favorite hot spots in LA?
Hot spots. We love Lola's. We go there
all the time. it's a martini bar.
And I like the Dime. I like, um-
We always go to Les Deux,
just 'cause all our friends are there.
Like, the spot to go to.
And that's- We always go to those places.
Those are our favorite.
So have you toned down the partying
now that you have a relationship..
or are you still going out?
Um, I've toned down a little bit.
I used to go out almost every night.
Oh, my God. I literally
love Audrina's style.
Can you see where she lives?
She's going to Demi and Ashton's
Oscar party on Sunday.
Perfect.
- Raise the bag a little.
- Sam. Sam. Sam.
Oh!! Becca!! Becca!! Becca!!
No, I- I got-
Which glasses are good today?
These ones?
I don't need the glasses.
I like it. Oh!!
Oh!!
- How much is this?
- It runs 50.
- Hey.
- Wait. Who are you?
- It's my little sister Emily.
- Oh. How old are you?
- Thirteen.
Come on.
- Can you fit through here?
- I'll see.
- What's up?
- Hi.
Sweet.
Oh. Damn.
Okay.
I'm gonna stay on lookout.
Gross.
Did you guys hear that?
- It's fine.
- No, no. I think I heard someone.
There's no one outside.
Calm the fuck down.
I hear helicopters.
We're in LA.
Of course there are helicopters.
Don't be such a little bitch.
- Well, that's-
- I like this Rick Owens jacket.
Wait. What's alprazolam?
- Xanax.
- Oh. Good.
Can we speed it up?
Oh, my God.
- Sam.
- Yeah?
- Look what I found.
- Oh-ho!! No way.
Let me see that.
- Oh, careful.
- Wow. Where'd you find it?
- Under the bed.
- Really?
- Whoa.
- Don't- Don't-
- Babe.
- You're good. You're fine. You're fine.
- You're fucking crazy.
- No, I'm not.
- Holy shit. Be careful with that.
- What?
Is it loaded?
I don't know.
Maybe.
- Dude, what the fuck? No.
- Maybe. Is it loaded?
I don't know, and I don't want to know.
- So just put it away.
- It's kind of heavy.
- Where'd you get it?
It's a real gun. Of course it's heavy.
Really?
- Does it- Does it make you nervous, Marc?
- Sam.
- Does it make you nervous, Marc?
- Fucking stop. Please.
"Please"ť? Did you just beg me? Dude.
It's all- it's chill. Don't touch me.
Okay?
- Just put the gun down.
- Why? I actually like it a lot.
Oh, yeah.
What are you gonna do with a gun?
I don't know. What?
- You're not gonna shoot me with it.
- Can you not grab me, brother?
That's good.
- Stop it.
- Did you just push a girl?
- Hi, Robbie.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- What's up?
- What's happening?
- I got you a present.
- You got me a present?
- Yeah, I did. You like it?
- Let me see. Let me take a closer look at that.
You want to see it?
Ready? it's right there. Right there.
Shit!! Shh, shh.
If I ever became not your friend
anymore, would you rob me?
I would never do that to you.
Orlando Bloom's shooting
a movie in New York.
He's there with Miranda Kerr.
I want to get some
Victoria's Secret model clothes.
- Look, dude. Check it.
- What? What?
- It's a love letter.
- That's cute.
Aw.
- Cute, right?
- Becca, move.
Fuck.
Holy shit. Guys.
Sweet.
They're all Rolexes. Guys.
Let's go.
Well, it wouldn't work in the first place,
so don't worry. it's fine.
Shit.
Put it.. there.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Got a new room at my dad's in Vegas.
I need some stuff to decorate it with.
Here.
- You fucking serious?
- Come on.
- Marc?
- One second, Mom.
It's time for dinner.
Be right there.
- Hey, Chloe.
- Yo, home skillet. What's going on?
Not much. Hey. Did you ever, uh-
Did you ever talk to Ricky
about the Rolexes?
Yeah, yeah.
He's got connects. Bring 'em by later.
Okay. Thanks.
- How'd your audition go today?
- It was all right.
I think it went really well.
They said they want to do a test shoot.
- Oh, good. That's good.
- Yeah.
- What's it for?
- Uh, Axe body spray.
Oh.
And we have a "go see"ť
for the BCBG runway show.
Oh, that's huge. Good job.
And that's a cute dress.
Did you get a new dress?
Mm-hmm.
Our friend Marc- he's a stylist.
He let us borrow some stuff
for the auditions.
- That's nice.
- Mmm.
His dad has a production company
that he helps style for.
What's it called?
I don't remember. Like-
- Something.. "international."
- Mmm.
Uh, Morn, we actually have to get going..
because we're meeting this manager tonight
who could be really helpful.
Yeah, he knows a lot of
photographers and producers, so-
- A manager?
- Hmm.
I'd totally do that singer guy.
- But did you see how small his hands are?
- No. Ew.
Yeah, that could be gross.
Dude, we have to get in that video.
- I know.
- Does this look good?
Yeah, I mean, do you feel good in that?
I want to be hot but not desperate.
Totally.
- I think it looks cute.
- Yeah?
- Show me a different top.
- All right.
My butt look good in these jeans?
Your butt looks awesome.
Come on.
Hey, Ricky. You remember Marc.
Sure. Sure, I do.
So, Marc, what can I do for you?
Um-
I was wondering if you could, uh-
could sell these for me.
- Where'd you get them?
- Uh, we found them.
I see.
Well, what do you think?
Can you take them?
I don't know.
I could see.
Tell you what.
I'll give you five grand for them.
Aren't they worth a lot more?
Not stolen ones.
Okay. Sweet. Thanks.
Eva, I love those shoes!!
Thank you.
Sure, kid.
Ooh.
Oh!!
When we went out, we got in everywhere,
and everyone loved us.
We had so many
beautiful, gorgeous things.
- Bye, Grandma.
- Bye now.
Thanks.
How many times
have you guys been up here?
- This is, like, our fifth time.
- And she never noticed?
We never take enough for it to be obvious.
I mean, come on. it's Paris Hilton.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, right.
- She's got so much stuff.
- I know, right?
- It's great.
- It's chill.
I don't know.
You'd never wake up though.
- You'd sleep in all day.
- Here we go.
- Whoa.
- Oh, shit!!
- Come on. Let's get the fuck out of here.
- What?
- Let's go. Let's go.
- Hey, Sam.
- What?
- Your coat.
Let's go.
Okay. Let's try it with this.
Now fix your hair.
Oh, yeah.
You could totally pull this off.
You're like an off-duty supermodel.
- Really?
- Yeah.
These Chloe sandals could work with it too.
- For, like, a day look.
- Yeah, definitely.
- Right?
- Here. Try 'em on.
- Hello?
- Turn on KTLA.
- What?
- Now.
- After a break-in earlier this year-
- Oh, my God.
Audrina Patridge posted
this security footage on her Web site.
Shit.
She's asking anyone who has information
about the break-in..
to contact police at the number below.
It's fine. You can't see who it is.
- Shit. Fuck. One second, Rebecca.
- Just chill out.
I can't talk.
- Everything all right in here?
- Yes, Mr. Hall.
We're sorry for making too much noise.
Everything's fine, Dad.
All right.
You're stressing me out.
Carly keeps texting me.
It's so annoying.
Ew. She's so grimy.
I know.
I think I'm gonna go to Sagebrush later.
Cool. Who's playing?
I don't know. A couple local bands.
I want to go to Rachel Bilson's.
She's in Paris for fashion week.
Don't you think you should
chill out a little bit?
Yeah. That news thing
totally freaked me out.
Nothing happened.
There's no way of telling who it is anyway.
Come on.
Can you find her house for me, please?
I want some Chanel.
- I don't know.
- Come on. You're my best friend.
Please? Let's go get some stuff.
We're going to Rachel Bilson's.
Wanna come?
Hells yeah. Text me where-
Is she still dating Hayden Christensen ?
I don't know.
Marc thinks so.
Come on.
I think the biggest problem was
after the Audrina thing, nothing happened.
It gave Rebecca that self-boost that,
"Oh, this is okay. I can get away with this."ť
And I think her projecting that onto me
made me think that it was gonna be okay.
- Yo, Becca.
- Hey. What's up?
I heard you went to Paris Hilton's.
- Yeah.
- And you took some stuff?
- Oh, that's so cool. Paris Hilton.
We're gonna go get a drink. Lates.
I can't believe she went to
Paris Hilton's house.
What up?
Where have you guys been tonight?
- We went to Rachel Bilson's.
- No fucking way!!
- Yeah. It was chill.
- Sick!!
You went to Rachel Bilson's?
- Yeah. She's in Paris at fashion week.
- Shut the fuck up.
We just went in.
Yeah, look at their chill-ass
Chanel purses, dude.
What the fuck are you doing? Come on.
- Come on now.
- Puff, puff, pass.
Puff, puff, puff.
Rebecca's, like, biggest conquest
was Lindsay Lohan.
She was her ultimate fashion icon.
Lindsay Lohan is
fighting back against accusations..
she stole a $2,500 necklace
from a Southern California jewelry store.
Her attorney addressed
the matter for the first time.
This is the dress she wore
to the Cosmopolitan opening.
Oh, my God. Let me see it.
I want to try it on. it's amazing.
These are cute. These are really useful.
Yeah.
When are you coming back from Vegas?
I don't know. Just gonna stay with my dad
until things calm down with my mom.
- I'll call you from there?
- Okay.
Will you hold on to
some of my stuff for me?
- Yeah, sure.
- Okay. Bye.
Bye.
Ciao.
Why do you think Rebecca was so obsessed
with these women and their clothes-
enough to steal?
I just think she wanted to be
a part of, like, the lifestyle.
Like, the lifestyle
that everybody kind of wants.
Lindsay Lohan gave police
the security footage..
from the night of March 23,
when her house was burglarized.
Comparing the clips..
it looks like these are the same burglars..
as in the Audrina Patridge security video..
and police are investigating
the connection..
of the Hollywood Hills burglaries.
If you have any information,
please contact the LAPD.
Marc and Rebecca were
bragging about it at a party.
They said they had been in Rachel Bilson 's
house and Lindsay Lohan's.
They said they went' to Paris Hilton is,
like, eight times.
That's Marc Hall, Rebecca Ahn and Chloe.
I don't know her last name. And Nicki Moore.
LAPD. Open the door!!
- Is this the home of Marc Hall?
- Yes.
- We have a search warrant.
- I'll- I'll get him.
Marc.
Mom.
Okay. Whatever it is,
we'll figure it out. it's gonna be okay.
Ma'am.
You have the right
to remain silent. Understand?
Anything you say can and will be used
against you in a court of law.
What's going on here?
What's this all about?
- Sir, I'm gonna have to ask you to step aside.
- Honey.
You have the right to speak to an attorney
present during any questioning, okay?
And if you cannot afford a lawyer,
one will be provided for you.
All right? Let's go.
- Marc. Over here.
- Marc, right over here!!
- Right here, buddy.
- Hey, Marc. Right here.
Los Angeles Police.
- Yes?
- Ma'am, we're the police.
- Is this the home of Nicolette Moore?
- Yes.
We have a search warrant to search the house.
Ma'am, can you please step out of the way?
- Out of the way.
- For what?
- Is anyone else in the house, ma'am?
- Mom?
- My kids.
- Call them downstairs.
- What's going on?
- Come downstairs, you guys.
Come downstairs right now.
- What's going on?
- Where are they going?
Ma'am, you need to secure
your animal- now.
Pick up your dog.
Ma'am, you have any weapons in the house?
- No.
- Okay.
What is this about?
Wait. What is going on?
I'll explain everything to you
before we're done. Nicolette?
- Yeah.
- Sit down over there.
- Why?
- What did I do?
Just sit down.
- Just sit down.
- Why?
We're conducting an investigation.
Before we're done..
I promise you I'll explain everything.
- Why do I have to sit down?
- Zip it.
- Put your hands behind your back.
- Mom?
- Mom? Mom?
- Excuse me. Sorry.
- Excuse me.
- Get her back.
- Can you stop-
- I need you to stop right here.
- I need to speak to my mom.
- ..what you're doing with my daughter.
I need to speak to my mom. Mom?
- Call the lawyer. Call a lawyer!!
- Mom, why are they taking her?
You're hurting me.
You're really hurting me. Mom.
Can you call the- Ow!!
Ow. I want to talk to my mom.
Ow. Ow.
- Hello? How can I help you?
- Is this the home of Rebecca Ahn?
I'm her mother,
but she's staying with her father in Nevada.
Easy, Tank.
What the fuck, man?
Chloe.
- Carrot-beet?
- No.
Crystal, shh!! Crystal.
Crystal. Chloe.
Then Rebecca wanted
to go to Orlando Bloom's.
We knew he was away, from the Internet.
You know, you Google his name..
and it says Orlando Bloom's shooting a movie
in New York, and he's with Miranda Kerr.
So we just walked in.
The door was unlocked. There was no alarm.
The door was unlocked?
I'm really sorry about what I did.
Did you know Rebecca
was leaving the state?
I- I just knew that she was
going to stay at her dad's..
because she wasn't getting along
with her mom and her stepdad.
You didn't know she was taking
stolen property..
across state lines
and leaving you holding the bag?
I thought she was just
gonna go see her dad.
- Metro Police. Are you Rebecca Ahn?
- Yes.
We have a warrant to search
the premises. Step aside.
Move back.
Bobby. Downstairs.
Jeff, upstairs. See what you find.
Here's your warrant.
Do you know why we're in your home,
serving you a search warrant?
- Yes.
- Why do you think we're here?
My friend Marc was arrested.
He called me from jail..
and said the police had done
a search warrant on his home.
- Do you know why?
- I've been watching TMZ.
They've been saying I'm a person of interest
in these burglaries.
Were you involved in these burglaries
of these celebrities?
No, I wasn't.
Is there going to be any property
from those burglaries in this residence?
- No.
- Have you ever been..
to these celebrity homes
that were burglarized?
No.
Could any of your fingerprints or DNA
be found in any of the victims' homes?
No.
You boys having fun?
Find something interesting? What?
- Yeah, we got a few things on the list.
- Right on.
Anything else?
- Yeah, we also came up with these.
- Nice.
We found a jacket and jeans
that match a description by Lohan..
and some personal photographs
of Paris Hilton.
If I tell you where everything is,
would you let me go?
Hypothetically, let's say I can help you
locate this property..
and tell you who has it,
how would that help me?
Rebecca Ahn, thought
to be the ringleader, was arrested..
and awaits her hearing
with the other members.
Stay tuned for the latest on the Bling Ring.
Did you speak to any of the victims?
I've spoken to all the victims.
Really? What did Lindsay say?
- Nicki. Nicki.
- How was it in there?
- It was not good.
Okay, thank you.
Nicki. Kate from Vanity Fair is here.
Can I get you something to drink?
So how is Sam related?
- We have adopted her.
- I was friends with her mother.
- Mom, this is my interview.
- Okay.
Yeah. So, she has been living with us.
Um, we met when my parents divorced..
and now my mom homeschools all of us.
Based on the philosophy of The Secret..
which is based on the laws of attraction.
- Can I talk, please?
- Sure.
I'm sorry.
The reason that we related so well..
is that my dad is a recovering alcoholic..
- and Sam's mom-
- She's a practicing-
is a practicing drug addict and alcoholic.
And our moms became, like, best friends.
- We were, and she went off the deep end.
- Please!!
- So, basically you took her in.
- Yes.
But let's, uh-
Let's- Let's get back to Nicki, okay?
Uh, so Adam here told me
that you do charity work.
Yes. We do a lot of stuff
through our church.
- Mmmmm.
- It's called the Agape Church.
- Right.
- It's the religious science philosophy..
beneath The Secret.
Um, my other sister, Gabby,
is on a trip with them building homes.
And they do a yearly trip to Africa..
where they build wells and schools for kids.
Which country?
Um, I can't remember exactly
which country..
but we do bake sales and, like, feeding
the homeless and that kind of stuff.
Okay. So there's a little bit
of a disconnect..
between your positive pursuits
and what's happening now.
Nicki, I don't want you
to answer that comment.
Well, I think that I am-
Don't.
I have, like,
a good statement to say about this.
She could speak generally.
I think this situation
was attracted into my life..
as a huge learning lesson for me..
to grow and expand
as a spiritual human being.
I believe that I am an old soul.
You are, honey. She is.
We've gotten to know Nicki and her family..
and we believe that she is an extremely
focused and honest young woman..
who has a lot to offer the community.
And we agree that there
has not been a disconnect-
that there were circumstances
that happened..
but Nicki herself
has continued to stay on her plane..
despite the tumultuous
experiences happening.
What's your goal,
or life plan, if you have one?
I do. I think it's my journey..
to push for peace
and the health of the planet.
Nicki's expressed to me
a lot of her humanitarianism.
It's my main goal.
I.. want to be a leader..
and do things that people really notice.
That's why I'm taking business-
so that I can be a leader..
and- and take a stand for people.
But I went to Indian Hills
to learn and be with my peers..
but I was always self-conscious that I wasn't,
you know, as good-looking as other people.
And now you're a star.
Yeah- On my Facebook page recently..
I had over 800 friend requests.
I accepted them all.
I mean, I didn't even look at them.
And then I noticed someone
had created a fan page for me.
It's just kind of awkward
that so many people are loving me..
for- for something
that's so looked down on in society.
If it had been, you know, something that
were to benefit the community..
or something like that, I'd love it.
But it's kind of showing America has this-
this sick fascination
with a Bonnie and Clyde kind of thing.
Does this look good?
Is this conservative?
If you like a secretary-style hooker.
Bite me.
Maybe with a jacket?
Well, it looks better.
Right?
Ah, you need lower heels.
Yeah.
Where are my kitten heels?
You're so lucky
you weren't on that video.
I know. Sucks.
Yeah. It does.
Maybe I need to wear something longer.
Do you own anything longer?
No.
Mom does.
- Can I have a five-milligram Adderall?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay, just remember what
we went over with Shannon.
They can't prove that you were
in any of those houses, okay?
- I know, Mom.
- All right?
Do you want to just ground ourselves
really quick? Nicki?
I know there is one mind,
one presence and one power.
- Mom, shouldn't we go?
- Emily.
What?
- Stop talking.
- She's praying.
I know I'm always protected,
and karma cleanses my journey.
Thank you, Lord, so much for this truth.
- And so it is.
So it is. And you rock, girl. Okay?
Right here. Right here. Nicki. Nicki.
- Okay, Nicki.
- Hey, Nicki. Can we get a comment? Nicki.
Nicki.
- Nicki.
This has been a very difficult time
for myself and my family.
Thank you for respecting my privacy.
I look forward to my day in court.
Chloe!!
- Marc.
Right here. Right here.
Hey, Marc.
How does it feel to be a rat?
Okay.
Remain seated. Come to order.
Division 31 is now in session. The Honorable
Judge Patricia Henley presiding.
- Good morning.
Are all parties ready?
Rebecca Ahn, you are found guilty..
on four counts of first-degree
residential burglary
You are sentenced to four years
in state prison and $800,000 in restitution.
Marc Hall, you are found guilty on four
counts of first-degree residental burglary.
You are sentenced to four years-
Nicolette Moore, you are found guilty..
on one count of first-degree
residential burglary
You are sentenced to one year
In county jail and $300,000-
Robert Hernandez, you are found guilty
on one count of first-degree-
Chloe Tayner, you are found guilty..
on one count of first-degree
residential burglary
You are sentenced to one year
In county jail and $300,000 in restitution.
Members of the Bling Ring
were sentenced today..
for their role in a rash of break-ins..
that netted more than
three million in high-end goods-
We're here with Nicki Moore..
who just served 30 days for her
involvement in the Bling Ring..
and shared a cellblock
with one of its victims, Lindsay Lohan.
There were reports that Lindsay was crying.
With you being next to her,
did you actually hear any of this?
Yeah. I could hear her
crying the first day..
which is really hard
when you're just trying to be strong.
But I just really kept to myself..
and just tried to get through the day.
It's hard when you're
woken up at, like, 5:30.
And how'd she look?
She got to keep her extensions in.
A lot of the girls were talking-
"Oh, I had to take my weave out," or whatever.
But, um, she was in orange like all of us.
Now, were you nervous being next to her?
Because you actually were accused
of being a part of the group..
that allegedly robbed her house.
Yeah. I mean, it was scary for me.
They were showing the surveillance video.
They were showing the story on TVs inside..
and, you know, little do people know..
that when that first video came out..
I was actually in contact
with her manager..
to tell her who I believed
the people were who robbed her house.
I mean, when I get to tell
my side of this story..
people are gonna know the truth.
So, that's nerve-racking.
She could think you robbed her house.
Yeah. She could have.
But, you know, anyway..
you can follow everything about me
and my journey..
a  SELVAHEMA  presentation